<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Rogue Film School</title>
    <link>https://community.source.institute/t/rogue-film-school/288</link>
    <description>This is what I call education that transforms.

&gt; [The Rogue Film School](http://www.roguefilmschool.com/about.asp) will be in the form of weekend seminars held by Werner Herzog in person at varying locations and at infrequent intervals.

&gt; The number of participants will be limited to a maximum of 65.

&gt; Locations and dates will be announced on this website and Werner Herzog&#39;s website: www.wernerherzog.com approximately 12 weeks in advance.

&gt; The Rogue Film School will not teach anything technical related to film-making. For this purpose, please enroll at your local film school.

&gt; The Rogue Film School is about a way of life. It is about a climate, the excitement that makes film possible. It will be about poetry, films, music, images, literature.

&gt; The focus of the seminars will be a dialogue with Werner Herzog, in which the participants will have their voice with their projects, their questions, their aspirations.

&gt; Excerpts of films will be discussed, which could include your submitted films; they may be shown and discussed as well. Depending on the materials, the attention will revolve around essential questions: how does music function in film? How do you narrate a story? (This will certainly depart from the brainless teachings of three-act-screenplays). How do you sensitize an audience? How is space created and understood by an audience? How do you produce and edit a film? How do you create illumination and an ecstasy of truth?

&gt; Related, but more practical subjects, will be the art of lockpicking. Traveling on foot. The exhilaration of being shot at unsuccessfully. The athletic side of filmmaking. The creation of your own shooting permits. The neutralization of bureaucracy. Guerrilla tactics. Self reliance.

&gt; Censorship will be enforced. There will be no talk of shamans, of yoga classes, nutritional values, herbal teas, discovering your Boundaries, and Inner Growth.

&gt; Follow your vision. Form secretive Rogue Cells everywhere. At the same time, be not afraid of solitude.

More than the personality of this, it&#39;s about teaching a way of being.  Herzog expects you to walk the walk,  literally on foot.  This gives me a sense of elitism and inclusiveness.   You&#39;re welcome to join us but you have to walk through the same gates as everyone else.

I&#39;ve signed up to his [online class](https://www.masterclass.com/classes/werner-herzog-teaches-filmmaking) starting this summer.  God knows what my browser history will look like after that.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2016 07:31:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Community</category>
    <atom:link href="https://community.source.institute/t/rogue-film-school/288.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Rogue Film School</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@salim Salim Virani]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/u/salim">@salim</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>This is what I call education that transforms.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><a href="http://www.roguefilmschool.com/about.asp">The Rogue Film School</a> will be in the form of weekend seminars held by Werner Herzog in person at varying locations and at infrequent intervals.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>The number of participants will be limited to a maximum of 65.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Locations and dates will be announced on this website and Werner Herzog’s website: <a href="http://www.wernerherzog.com">www.wernerherzog.com</a> approximately 12 weeks in advance.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>The Rogue Film School will not teach anything technical related to film-making. For this purpose, please enroll at your local film school.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>The Rogue Film School is about a way of life. It is about a climate, the excitement that makes film possible. It will be about poetry, films, music, images, literature.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>The focus of the seminars will be a dialogue with Werner Herzog, in which the participants will have their voice with their projects, their questions, their aspirations.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Excerpts of films will be discussed, which could include your submitted films; they may be shown and discussed as well. Depending on the materials, the attention will revolve around essential questions: how does music function in film? How do you narrate a story? (This will certainly depart from the brainless teachings of three-act-screenplays). How do you sensitize an audience? How is space created and understood by an audience? How do you produce and edit a film? How do you create illumination and an ecstasy of truth?</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Related, but more practical subjects, will be the art of lockpicking. Traveling on foot. The exhilaration of being shot at unsuccessfully. The athletic side of filmmaking. The creation of your own shooting permits. The neutralization of bureaucracy. Guerrilla tactics. Self reliance.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Censorship will be enforced. There will be no talk of shamans, of yoga classes, nutritional values, herbal teas, discovering your Boundaries, and Inner Growth.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Follow your vision. Form secretive Rogue Cells everywhere. At the same time, be not afraid of solitude.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>More than the personality of this, it’s about teaching a way of being.  Herzog expects you to walk the walk,  literally on foot.  This gives me a sense of elitism and inclusiveness.   You’re welcome to join us but you have to walk through the same gates as everyone else.</p>
<p>I’ve signed up to his <a href="https://www.masterclass.com/classes/werner-herzog-teaches-filmmaking">online class</a> starting this summer.  God knows what my browser history will look like after that.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/t/rogue-film-school/288/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://community.source.institute/t/rogue-film-school/288/1</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2016 16:30:29 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.source.institute-post-288-1</guid>
        <source url="https://community.source.institute/t/rogue-film-school/288.rss">Rogue Film School</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
