<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:discourse="http://www.discourse.org/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>AIESEC International - Source Institute</title>
    <link>https://community.source.institute/c/archive/aiesec-international</link>
    <description>Topics in the &#39;AIESEC International&#39; category A category for our discussions with AIESEC International.  Mainly for broader topics around agile and entrepreneurship.</description>
    
      <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 12:14:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      <atom:link href="https://community.source.institute/c/archive/aiesec-international.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
          <title>Some thoughts after March 2017&#39;s SG</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@salim Salim Virani]]></dc:creator>
          <category>AIESEC International</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/u/salim">@salim</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <h2>Overall impression</h2>
<p>When I mentor startups, I always try to assess the situation so I can calibrate any advice I give.  Advice that is truly useful takes into account the startup stage, resources, past experience and founders’ <a href="http://motives.My">motives.My</a></p>
<p>Sometimes, the founders are doing too much, and they need help focusing and applying some kind of strategy. Sometimes, they are missing something big that I can help them see.  Sometimes, they’re fucking around need a kick in the ass.</p>
<p>And sometimes, my face lights up because they’re doing everything just fine, and all I can say is, “so how can I help?”</p>
<p>That’s what this SG felt like to me.</p>
<p>I’ve learned from investors how to assess if a team is investable, and the quality of the team is more important than their business idea or their results.</p>
<p>One of the favourite things I heard at this SG was that there was so much demand for Pipe to do database queries that you had to create a dedicated Slack channel.  (And I’ve heard before how much you hate creating Slack channels, so that says a lot.)</p>
<p>You guys are using data to make decisions! Shit yeah.</p>
<p>There were so many other signs that you’re on the right track: the collaboration between PD and finance; the efficiency levers you were finding in social media, sales funnel management, platform support; the level-headedness regarding GTs numbers (a sign you are learning to be capital-D Disruptive, as in true Disruptive Innovation, like Apple, Uber, Grameen, M-Kopa); being on top of network management like a machine!; MoS deployment being rock-steady; the increased speed in measurement of network finance (down to 5 months and dropping) and you’re measuring process time too; IM deploying platforms and APIs like bosses.</p>
<p>I could keep going.</p>
<p>The point I’m trying to make is all of this is hard, and you’re all going, “I got this.”</p>
<p>The point I’m trying to make is that when you set hard goals you get farther than when you set easy goals, but it doesn’t feel like as much of a success since you wanted more.</p>
<p>The point I’m trying to make is that if you were a startup, you’d be an investable team.  You don’t need saving or managing, you don’t need anything really.  Rather than <em>need</em>, you <em>deserve</em> backing and help to open doors to bigger opportunities.</p>
<p>You deserve to give SG homework rather than the other way around.</p>
<p>So how can I help? <img src="//community.source.institute/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=5" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
<h3>What’s next for AIESEC International</h3>
<p>So, for quite a few of you, you’re feeling like you didn’t get to do that thing you wanted to do this term.  I get it.  Immersion (Deep Dive) was my baby and we had to park it.  We worked haaaaard on that.</p>
<p>But please don’t lose sight of the bigger picture.</p>
<p>We didn’t all get our “hows” but we got a lot of our “whats” and “whys” in some way. AIESEC has far more entrepreneurial thinking ingrained now. It’s a more distributed and empowering network organisation.</p>
<h2>Fixers and other p2p facilitation formats</h2>
<p>I’m pretty stoked that you liked Fixers.  There’s a lot more where that came from. We have a ton of peer to peer formats which can help.</p>
<p>First of all, I’ll share the Delegation Canvas with you if you find it useful, and we have some notes on fixers in our facilitation guide.</p>
<p>We have a lot more formats like that, and I think they’d be useful at future SGs, ICs, XPROs, and also ad-hoc.  If anyone’s interested in poking through our faciliator guide (always under construction), I’d love to share and help you make use of that stuff.</p>
<h2>Use The Source, Luke</h2>
<p>On that note, if anyone wants to come learn our ways, you’re welcome to our internal Source Camps in Bulgaria. They’re roughly every 3 months.</p>
<p>And as I mentioned, we’ve now isolated a business model that grows, and puts us delivering p2p education to network organisations all over the world. We help all kinds of engineers and social enterprises learn the state-of-the-art techniques they need to succeed in fast-changing environments.  If you want to be a facilitator with us, you’d be in the middle of a stream of hundreds of cool tech companies doing everything from fintech to clean water.  And a more ambitious opportunity is to step up as a Source Partner, where you pick up your own clients within Source (with plenty of our support), so the profits are yours.  So if either being a faciitator (on salary, supporting entrepreneurs all over the globe) or partner (earning profits) is interesting to you, let’s talk.</p>
<p>When I mentioned this at the end of SG, I mentioned the money.  Yes, the money is pretty good, but I mentioned that just so you’d have a tangible idea of what your options are – and what’s the value of your experience.</p>
<p>Don’t undervalue yourself, and don’t be afraid to go for something you want to do and carve your own path.  You are ready and you have a support network to help you succeed on your own terms.</p>
<p>If I can be of any kind of support, add me on Linked In (<a href="http://linkedin.com/in/salimvirani">linkedin.com/in/salimvirani</a>) and on Telegram (+359 889331544) and we can chat.</p>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 1</p>
            <p>Participants: 1</p>
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/t/some-thoughts-after-march-2017s-sg/1793">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://community.source.institute/t/some-thoughts-after-march-2017s-sg/1793</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 12:14:45 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">community.source.institute-topic-1793</guid>
          <source url="https://community.source.institute/t/some-thoughts-after-march-2017s-sg/1793.rss">Some thoughts after March 2017&#39;s SG</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Throwing more time at it doesn&#39;t make you a hero</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@salim Salim Virani]]></dc:creator>
          <category>AIESEC International</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/u/salim">@salim</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p>Throwing more time at it doesn’t make you a hero.</p>
<p>It doesn’t even make you a burn out martyr.</p>
<p>But it does make you an ineffective leader.</p>
<p>Take it from me, an old guy who discovered his limits the hard way. The reason old people hire young people is that they get a lot of energy without a lot of questions.</p>
<p>And eventually, every young person realises they can’t keep it up.</p>
<p>They hit a wall. Once. Twice, a few more times. And then they’re <em>forced</em> to make some decisions.</p>
<p>First, you’ll notice you start getting these mythical things called <em>hangovers.</em>  You tell yourself it’s just a headache at first. No, it’s age catching up.</p>
<p>Then, you’ll notice hair where there isn’t supposed to be hair.</p>
<p>You might hit a birthday and think, <em>holy shit, I’m twenty-blah already!</em> and then you’ll forget about it by doing shots.</p>
<p>Another birthday will come again – too quickly – and you’ll say, <em>holy shit, I just wasted the last year at a deadend job/awful band/idiot boyfriend that really didn’t do what it promised.</em></p>
<p>Then you have the better part of a decade of adult life behind you, and you can’t find the right <em>wtf</em> sticker in Snapchat to describe that feeling.</p>
<p>It’s about this time, usually approaching your Thirties, that you stop and look up for a second.</p>
<p>It’s like that weekend when you got sucked into that video game and all of a sudden it was Sunday night, you’re surrounded in dirty plates and smell like the kid in school that nobody talked to. Where did that time go?</p>
<p>You look at your life, and look back.</p>
<p>When I did this, I was 28, and realised I’d been chasing false dreams. I readjusted my goals, but with less energy now, I looked back wishing I hadn’t wasted my high-energy years by not sticking to what deeply mattered. And  <a href="http://www.salimvirani.com/constraints/"> 7 years later I had to learn that lesson again </a>.</p>
<p>So you learn this amazing new skill – <em>saying no</em>.  Though fancy people call it <em>prioritisation.</em></p>
<h1>So why is this important for you now? At AI?</h1>
<p>Agile has a very specific way to prioritise.  You prioritise based on value for the customer, and difficulty or <a href="http://decisionhacks.co/remove-variables">variability in delivery</a>.  And you prioritise weekly, as a team.</p>
<p>Now, the stupid hero in you, the one who likes to stay up until 4am every day because you wanted to say yes to every project that promised to tickle your ego, that hero will want to twist Agile priorities to include everything. You should say to that voice, <em>“sit the fuck down and learn something.”</em> Try to sound like Samuel L. Jackson. The L stands for Learn Something Mutherfucker.</p>
<p>The key skill to learn here is called <em>de-scoping</em>.  Pretend it’s the night before the deadline, and you have to cut out all the nice-to-haves. You’re limiting the scope of the deliverable to the minimum that will work. Do that first, and ship it to the customer, then you can add more on later.</p>
<p>Eventually you get the hang of it, and when you plan each sprint, you get pretty good at choosing things that are realistic <em>and</em> worthwhile.  You start to realise that all that extra stuff wasn’t so important, and that doing less stuff better goes a lot further.</p>
<p>Throwing more time at it isn’t heroic, it’s dangerous.  Especially when everyone does that and creates a ton of expecatations and a web of interdependencies. If you fail, your team fails.</p>
<p><strong>When you choose not to prioritise, you choose roll the dice with which important thing will fall apart.</strong></p>
<p>Use your stand ups to learn to prioritise, to learn to say <em>no</em> or at least say <em>later</em>.  Then you’ll find the time you invest has way bigger impact.</p>
<p>Or at least you’ll have the time to deal with that new hair. Eww.</p>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 1</p>
            <p>Participants: 1</p>
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/t/throwing-more-time-at-it-doesnt-make-you-a-hero/534">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://community.source.institute/t/throwing-more-time-at-it-doesnt-make-you-a-hero/534</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2016 14:41:37 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">community.source.institute-topic-534</guid>
          <source url="https://community.source.institute/t/throwing-more-time-at-it-doesnt-make-you-a-hero/534.rss">Throwing more time at it doesn&#39;t make you a hero</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>From projects to products</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@salim Salim Virani]]></dc:creator>
          <category>AIESEC International</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/u/salim">@salim</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p>From SG, I felt one of the main gaps in Agile understanding at AI was the ways agile methodologies focus on the customer.  (I though I’d share quick guidance here on our forum - feel free to invite others from the AI team to sign up to see these.)</p>
<p>There are few key things to understand about Agile to make it work for you, rather than against you.</p>
<p>Let’s start with some of the key issues <em>that I’ve heard from you</em>:</p>
<ol>
<li>AI has too many meetings.  Not enough time to work.</li>
<li>AI team members often don’t take action they feel is useful, because they feel they are stepping outside of their role.</li>
<li>AI tends to have to nanny the network, checking they’re doing their job and that they’re implementing the new processes.  Not a good use of time.</li>
<li>AI projects tend to fall back to top-down directives and running processes, rather than customer focus.</li>
</ol>
<p>Doing Agile without the parts that give you customer focus are likely to make these problems worse, not better.</p>
<h2>Agile Squads are multi-disciplinary teams that work on products which give value to customer at the end of every sprint</h2>
<p>So to do this at AI, we need to be aware of the differences in how AI has organised in the past, and how AI needs to organise to make Agile work.</p>
<h2>Products, not projects</h2>
<p>Projects have goals that serve the host organisation.  Products have goals that serve the customer.  When you organise into product teams, you break work down, not by function, but by value to the customer.</p>
<p>A specific Agile technique called User Stories is the unit of progress.  Shipping something that acheives the user stories allows the squad to self-organise and do what needs doing to deliver value.</p>
<div class="lazyYT" data-youtube-id="LGeDZmrWwsw" data-youtube-title="Agile In Practice: StoryCards/User Stories" data-width="480" data-height="270" data-parameters="feature=oembed&amp;wmode=opaque"></div>
<h2>Product teams have every function they need on their squad</h2>
<p>When you break up your teams by function, then you create interdependency.  This slows you down because not only are you going to end up waiting on others, which will lead to more need for planning and less time for doing, you’re also going to end up feeling like you <em>shouldn’t do what makes sense for you</em> because it might mess with another project.</p>
<p>That makes it difficult for the team to just do what it needs to do to deliver value into customer hands every week, which slows down everyone’s speed and learning.</p>
<p>Product teams have everyone they need in the squad and can act.  The squad doesn’t need to check in with anyone but themselves.  There’s less time needed for meetings and talking, and more of a culture of “let’s just try this.”  Fearlessness!</p>
<h2>Are you serving the needs of @ network, or serving your ideas?</h2>
<p>If the squads work affects MCs or LCs, those people should be represented in the squad.  At best, they are included in the squads (and then the squad is a <em>remote</em> squad) - at the very least, they are represented by the product owner who treats them as a stakeholder.</p>
<p>The key point is that their needs are front-and-center every week and every deliverable.  Their voice is literally heard every time there’s an AI brainstorm about what to do.</p>
<p><span class="mention">@Ext_AIESECIntl</span></p>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 4</p>
            <p>Participants: 2</p>
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/t/from-projects-to-products/530">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://community.source.institute/t/from-projects-to-products/530</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2016 18:47:12 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">community.source.institute-topic-530</guid>
          <source url="https://community.source.institute/t/from-projects-to-products/530.rss">From projects to products</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>About the AIESEC International category</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@salim Salim Virani]]></dc:creator>
          <category>AIESEC International</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/u/salim">@salim</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p>A category for our discussions with AIESEC International.  Mainly for broader topics around agile and entrepreneurship.</p>
<p>This category is only visibile to AI (who sign up with an <span class="mention">@ai.aiesec.org</span> address) and to the Source team.</p>
<p>Please use the Track feature to track this group, if you want to receive notifications and a weekly email digest.</p>
<p><span class="mention">@Ext_AIESECIntl</span></p>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 1</p>
            <p>Participants: 1</p>
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/t/about-the-aiesec-international-category/529">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://community.source.institute/t/about-the-aiesec-international-category/529</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2016 18:25:32 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>Yes</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">community.source.institute-topic-529</guid>
          <source url="https://community.source.institute/t/about-the-aiesec-international-category/529.rss">About the AIESEC International category</source>
        </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
