<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Some thoughts after March 2017&#39;s SG</title>
    <link>https://community.source.institute/t/some-thoughts-after-march-2017s-sg/1793</link>
    <description>## Overall impression

When I mentor startups, I always try to assess the situation so I can calibrate any advice I give.  Advice that is truly useful takes into account the startup stage, resources, past experience and founders&#39; motives.My

Sometimes, the founders are doing too much, and they need help focusing and applying some kind of strategy. Sometimes, they are missing something big that I can help them see.  Sometimes, they&#39;re fucking around need a kick in the ass. 

And sometimes, my face lights up because they&#39;re doing everything just fine, and all I can say is, &quot;so how can I help?&quot;

That&#39;s what this SG felt like to me.

I&#39;ve learned from investors how to assess if a team is investable, and the quality of the team is more important than their business idea or their results.  

One of the favourite things I heard at this SG was that there was so much demand for Pipe to do database queries that you had to create a dedicated Slack channel.  (And I&#39;ve heard before how much you hate creating Slack channels, so that says a lot.) 

You guys are using data to make decisions! Shit yeah. 

There were so many other signs that you&#39;re on the right track: the collaboration between PD and finance; the efficiency levers you were finding in social media, sales funnel management, platform support; the level-headedness regarding GTs numbers (a sign you are learning to be capital-D Disruptive, as in true Disruptive Innovation, like Apple, Uber, Grameen, M-Kopa); being on top of network management like a machine!; MoS deployment being rock-steady; the increased speed in measurement of network finance (down to 5 months and dropping) and you&#39;re measuring process time too; IM deploying platforms and APIs like bosses. 

I could keep going.

The point I&#39;m trying to make is all of this is hard, and you&#39;re all going, &quot;I got this.&quot; 

The point I&#39;m trying to make is that when you set hard goals you get farther than when you set easy goals, but it doesn&#39;t feel like as much of a success since you wanted more.

The point I&#39;m trying to make is that if you were a startup, you&#39;d be an investable team.  You don&#39;t need saving or managing, you don&#39;t need anything really.  Rather than *need*, you *deserve* backing and help to open doors to bigger opportunities.  

You deserve to give SG homework rather than the other way around.

So how can I help? :)

### What&#39;s next for AIESEC International

So, for quite a few of you, you&#39;re feeling like you didn&#39;t get to do that thing you wanted to do this term.  I get it.  Immersion (Deep Dive) was my baby and we had to park it.  We worked haaaaard on that. 

But please don&#39;t lose sight of the bigger picture.  

We didn&#39;t all get our &quot;hows&quot; but we got a lot of our &quot;whats&quot; and &quot;whys&quot; in some way. AIESEC has far more entrepreneurial thinking ingrained now. It&#39;s a more distributed and empowering network organisation. 

## Fixers and other p2p facilitation formats
I&#39;m pretty stoked that you liked Fixers.  There&#39;s a lot more where that came from. We have a ton of peer to peer formats which can help.

First of all, I&#39;ll share the Delegation Canvas with you if you find it useful, and we have some notes on fixers in our facilitation guide.

We have a lot more formats like that, and I think they&#39;d be useful at future SGs, ICs, XPROs, and also ad-hoc.  If anyone&#39;s interested in poking through our faciliator guide (always under construction), I&#39;d love to share and help you make use of that stuff.

## Use The Source, Luke
On that note, if anyone wants to come learn our ways, you&#39;re welcome to our internal Source Camps in Bulgaria. They&#39;re roughly every 3 months.

And as I mentioned, we&#39;ve now isolated a business model that grows, and puts us delivering p2p education to network organisations all over the world. We help all kinds of engineers and social enterprises learn the state-of-the-art techniques they need to succeed in fast-changing environments.  If you want to be a facilitator with us, you&#39;d be in the middle of a stream of hundreds of cool tech companies doing everything from fintech to clean water.  And a more ambitious opportunity is to step up as a Source Partner, where you pick up your own clients within Source (with plenty of our support), so the profits are yours.  So if either being a faciitator (on salary, supporting entrepreneurs all over the globe) or partner (earning profits) is interesting to you, let&#39;s talk.

When I mentioned this at the end of SG, I mentioned the money.  Yes, the money is pretty good, but I mentioned that just so you&#39;d have a tangible idea of what your options are -- and what&#39;s the value of your experience.  

Don&#39;t undervalue yourself, and don&#39;t be afraid to go for something you want to do and carve your own path.  You are ready and you have a support network to help you succeed on your own terms.

If I can be of any kind of support, add me on Linked In (linkedin.com/in/salimvirani) and on Telegram (+359 889331544) and we can chat.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 12:14:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>AIESEC International</category>
    <atom:link href="https://community.source.institute/t/some-thoughts-after-march-2017s-sg/1793.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Some thoughts after March 2017&#39;s SG</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@salim Salim Virani]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/u/salim">@salim</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <h2>Overall impression</h2>
<p>When I mentor startups, I always try to assess the situation so I can calibrate any advice I give.  Advice that is truly useful takes into account the startup stage, resources, past experience and founders’ <a href="http://motives.My">motives.My</a></p>
<p>Sometimes, the founders are doing too much, and they need help focusing and applying some kind of strategy. Sometimes, they are missing something big that I can help them see.  Sometimes, they’re fucking around need a kick in the ass.</p>
<p>And sometimes, my face lights up because they’re doing everything just fine, and all I can say is, “so how can I help?”</p>
<p>That’s what this SG felt like to me.</p>
<p>I’ve learned from investors how to assess if a team is investable, and the quality of the team is more important than their business idea or their results.</p>
<p>One of the favourite things I heard at this SG was that there was so much demand for Pipe to do database queries that you had to create a dedicated Slack channel.  (And I’ve heard before how much you hate creating Slack channels, so that says a lot.)</p>
<p>You guys are using data to make decisions! Shit yeah.</p>
<p>There were so many other signs that you’re on the right track: the collaboration between PD and finance; the efficiency levers you were finding in social media, sales funnel management, platform support; the level-headedness regarding GTs numbers (a sign you are learning to be capital-D Disruptive, as in true Disruptive Innovation, like Apple, Uber, Grameen, M-Kopa); being on top of network management like a machine!; MoS deployment being rock-steady; the increased speed in measurement of network finance (down to 5 months and dropping) and you’re measuring process time too; IM deploying platforms and APIs like bosses.</p>
<p>I could keep going.</p>
<p>The point I’m trying to make is all of this is hard, and you’re all going, “I got this.”</p>
<p>The point I’m trying to make is that when you set hard goals you get farther than when you set easy goals, but it doesn’t feel like as much of a success since you wanted more.</p>
<p>The point I’m trying to make is that if you were a startup, you’d be an investable team.  You don’t need saving or managing, you don’t need anything really.  Rather than <em>need</em>, you <em>deserve</em> backing and help to open doors to bigger opportunities.</p>
<p>You deserve to give SG homework rather than the other way around.</p>
<p>So how can I help? <img src="//community.source.institute/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=5" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
<h3>What’s next for AIESEC International</h3>
<p>So, for quite a few of you, you’re feeling like you didn’t get to do that thing you wanted to do this term.  I get it.  Immersion (Deep Dive) was my baby and we had to park it.  We worked haaaaard on that.</p>
<p>But please don’t lose sight of the bigger picture.</p>
<p>We didn’t all get our “hows” but we got a lot of our “whats” and “whys” in some way. AIESEC has far more entrepreneurial thinking ingrained now. It’s a more distributed and empowering network organisation.</p>
<h2>Fixers and other p2p facilitation formats</h2>
<p>I’m pretty stoked that you liked Fixers.  There’s a lot more where that came from. We have a ton of peer to peer formats which can help.</p>
<p>First of all, I’ll share the Delegation Canvas with you if you find it useful, and we have some notes on fixers in our facilitation guide.</p>
<p>We have a lot more formats like that, and I think they’d be useful at future SGs, ICs, XPROs, and also ad-hoc.  If anyone’s interested in poking through our faciliator guide (always under construction), I’d love to share and help you make use of that stuff.</p>
<h2>Use The Source, Luke</h2>
<p>On that note, if anyone wants to come learn our ways, you’re welcome to our internal Source Camps in Bulgaria. They’re roughly every 3 months.</p>
<p>And as I mentioned, we’ve now isolated a business model that grows, and puts us delivering p2p education to network organisations all over the world. We help all kinds of engineers and social enterprises learn the state-of-the-art techniques they need to succeed in fast-changing environments.  If you want to be a facilitator with us, you’d be in the middle of a stream of hundreds of cool tech companies doing everything from fintech to clean water.  And a more ambitious opportunity is to step up as a Source Partner, where you pick up your own clients within Source (with plenty of our support), so the profits are yours.  So if either being a faciitator (on salary, supporting entrepreneurs all over the globe) or partner (earning profits) is interesting to you, let’s talk.</p>
<p>When I mentioned this at the end of SG, I mentioned the money.  Yes, the money is pretty good, but I mentioned that just so you’d have a tangible idea of what your options are – and what’s the value of your experience.</p>
<p>Don’t undervalue yourself, and don’t be afraid to go for something you want to do and carve your own path.  You are ready and you have a support network to help you succeed on your own terms.</p>
<p>If I can be of any kind of support, add me on Linked In (<a href="http://linkedin.com/in/salimvirani">linkedin.com/in/salimvirani</a>) and on Telegram (+359 889331544) and we can chat.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/t/some-thoughts-after-march-2017s-sg/1793/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://community.source.institute/t/some-thoughts-after-march-2017s-sg/1793/1</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 12:14:46 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.source.institute-post-1793-1</guid>
        <source url="https://community.source.institute/t/some-thoughts-after-march-2017s-sg/1793.rss">Some thoughts after March 2017&#39;s SG</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
