<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:discourse="http://www.discourse.org/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects - Source Institute</title>
    <link>https://community.source.institute/c/activities/projects</link>
    <description>Topics in the &#39;Projects&#39; category This section briefly outlines our main projects and has a few case studies from our service delivery arm, Source Partners.</description>
    
      <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 21:29:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      <atom:link href="https://community.source.institute/c/activities/projects.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
          <title>Leaders of Innovation Fellowship Year 4</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@lino Lino Velev]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Projects</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/u/lino">@lino</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p><div class="lightbox-wrapper"><a class="lightbox" href="//community.source.institute/uploads/default/original/1X/37a6e20557a7b8f4ba0786c0c2c2a0d21fc166f6.jpg" data-download-href="//community.source.institute/uploads/default/37a6e20557a7b8f4ba0786c0c2c2a0d21fc166f6" title="oxford-innovation-leaders-in-innovation-fellowships-3-1024.jpg"><img src="//community.source.institute/uploads/default/optimized/1X/37a6e20557a7b8f4ba0786c0c2c2a0d21fc166f6_2_690x388.jpg" alt="source-institute-leaders-in-innovation-fellowships-4-1024" width="690" height="388" srcset="//community.source.institute/uploads/default/optimized/1X/37a6e20557a7b8f4ba0786c0c2c2a0d21fc166f6_2_690x388.jpg, //community.source.institute/uploads/default/original/1X/37a6e20557a7b8f4ba0786c0c2c2a0d21fc166f6.jpg 1.5x, //community.source.institute/uploads/default/original/1X/37a6e20557a7b8f4ba0786c0c2c2a0d21fc166f6.jpg 2x" data-small-upload="//community.source.institute/uploads/default/optimized/1X/37a6e20557a7b8f4ba0786c0c2c2a0d21fc166f6_2_10x10.png"><div class="meta">
<svg class="fa d-icon d-icon-far-image svg-icon" aria-hidden="true"><use xlink:href="#far-image"></use></svg><span class="filename">oxford-innovation-leaders-in-innovation-fellowships-3-1024.jpg</span><span class="informations">1024×577 83.6 KB</span><svg class="fa d-icon d-icon-discourse-expand svg-icon" aria-hidden="true"><use xlink:href="#discourse-expand"></use></svg>
</div></a></div></p>
<p><strong>The Royal Academy of Engineering</strong> is the UK’s national academy for engineering and a registered charity, bringing together the most successful and talented engineers from across industries to advance and promote excellence in global engineering. Fellows of The Royal Academy of Engineering include design leaders James Dyson and Sir Ove Arup, radar pioneer Sir George MacFarlane, and Sir Maurice Wilkes, father of the UK computer industry.</p>
<p>The Academy is a formal partner of the UK Government’s Newton Fund, part of the UK’s official overseas development assistance (ODA), aiming to build international science and innovation partnerships that promote the economic development and welfare of developing countries.</p>
<p><strong>The <a href="http://www.raeng.org.uk/grants-and-prizes/international-research-and-collaborations/newton-fund-programmes/leaders-in-innovation-fellowships" rel="nofollow noopener">Leaders in Innovation Fellowships (LIF) programme</a>:</strong><br>
LIF builds partnerships with fellows and business leaders to develop their capacity for entrepreneurship and commercialisation of their research. The programme is aimed at engineers and researchers who are ready to commercialise their innovation, and will benefit from developing partnerships, mentoring, and networking in the UK. This year’s first cohort attending the programme in the UK welcomes participants from Colombia, Brazil and Chile for a focussed period of training in innovation and entrepreneurship.</p>
<p><strong>About the fellows:</strong><br>
Meet, network, and mentor with leading engineering and research fellows, who developing sustainable and innovative solutions to some of the worlds most challenging problems!</p>
<p>•	Previous participants of the LIF programme have worked on commercializing a wide variety of technologies, such as using lasers to etch nano-patterns into wind turbines to improve their performance.<br>
Other LIF participants are focusing on ways to improve the livelihoods of people across emerging countries. For example,  making rice more nutritious andmaking it more economical to raise goats.<br>
•	Yet more are tackling some of the greatest issues facing society today, such as antibiotic-resistant bacteria and developing genomic technologies to boost agricultural yields – technologies and approaches aiming to save millions of lives in the future</p>
<p>These technologies are aimed at everyone from rural farmers to businesses, from surgeons to city governments. Some fellows have raised hundred of thousands of dollars in funding while others are still proving concepts and conducting early tests.</p>
<p><strong>How to Participate:</strong><br>
Meet, network, and develop business relationships through a series of training sessions and open events which Source Institute is running for LIF, including the <a href="http://www.sourcesummit.com/" rel="nofollow noopener">Source Summit Unconfenrence</a>), where we’re inviting interested members of the London tech community to learn, support and build relationships with the fellows.</p>
<h2>If you’d like to participate please <strong>register <a href="https://goo.gl/forms/SbdCGalDVeDYs2qF2" rel="nofollow noopener">HERE</a></strong>
</h2>
<p><strong>Location: <a href="http://tobaccodocklondon.com/contact-us/" rel="nofollow noopener">Tobacco Dock</a></strong><br>
<strong>Time: 19.10.2017 9:00 to 18:00</strong><br>
Additionally sessions on:<br>
20.10 and 25.10 afternoons</p>
<p><div class="lightbox-wrapper"><a class="lightbox" href="//community.source.institute/uploads/default/original/1X/175e3185089e5e21a185b9e121bb12e237a78004.jpg" data-download-href="//community.source.institute/uploads/default/175e3185089e5e21a185b9e121bb12e237a78004" title="Screenshot 2017-09-25 22.32.24.jpg"><img src="//community.source.institute/uploads/default/optimized/1X/175e3185089e5e21a185b9e121bb12e237a78004_2_690x436.jpg" alt="24" width="690" height="436" srcset="//community.source.institute/uploads/default/optimized/1X/175e3185089e5e21a185b9e121bb12e237a78004_2_690x436.jpg, //community.source.institute/uploads/default/optimized/1X/175e3185089e5e21a185b9e121bb12e237a78004_2_1035x654.jpg 1.5x, //community.source.institute/uploads/default/optimized/1X/175e3185089e5e21a185b9e121bb12e237a78004_2_1380x872.jpg 2x" data-small-upload="//community.source.institute/uploads/default/optimized/1X/175e3185089e5e21a185b9e121bb12e237a78004_2_10x10.png"><div class="meta">
<svg class="fa d-icon d-icon-far-image svg-icon" aria-hidden="true"><use xlink:href="#far-image"></use></svg><span class="filename">Screenshot 2017-09-25 22.32.24.jpg</span><span class="informations">2244×1420 264 KB</span><svg class="fa d-icon d-icon-discourse-expand svg-icon" aria-hidden="true"><use xlink:href="#discourse-expand"></use></svg>
</div></a></div></p>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 1</p>
            <p>Participants: 1</p>
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/t/leaders-of-innovation-fellowship-year-4/2110">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://community.source.institute/t/leaders-of-innovation-fellowship-year-4/2110</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 21:29:53 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">community.source.institute-topic-2110</guid>
          <source url="https://community.source.institute/t/leaders-of-innovation-fellowship-year-4/2110.rss">Leaders of Innovation Fellowship Year 4</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Leaders in Innovation Fellowship - Year 3</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@boyana boyana]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Projects</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/u/boyana">@boyana</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p>The Royal Academy of Engineering’s Leaders in Innovation Fellowships (LIF) programme brings together dozens of researchers from around the world every year to train in capacity building and entrepreneurship. The idea is to equip them with the skills and networks to become technology entrepreneurs. This year’s final LIF cohort contains fellows from China, India, Colombia, and the Philippines.</p>
<p>These fellows are working on commercializing a wide variety of technologies. For example, efficiency boosting turbines for everything from aircraft engines to wind farms. Several LIF fellows are examining ways to use technologies like lasers to etch nano-patterns into turbines to improve their performance.</p>
<p>Other emergent technologies being developed by LIF fellows focus on ways to improve the lives of millions of everyday people by, for example, making rice more nutritious, or making it more economical to raise goats. Yet more are targeting some of the greatest threats humans face today as a species, antibiotic-resistant bacteria, by developing a unique drug cocktail with the potential to save millions of lives in the future.</p>
<p>These technologies are aimed at everyone from rural farmers to defense contractors, surgeons to city governments. Some have raised hundred of thousands of dollars in funding while others are still proving concepts and conducting early tests.</p>
<p>Find more on the <a href="http://www.raeng.org.uk/grants-and-prizes/international-research-and-collaborations/newton-fund-programmes/leaders-in-innovation-fellowships">RAENG website.</a></p>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 1</p>
            <p>Participants: 1</p>
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/t/leaders-in-innovation-fellowship-year-3/1731">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://community.source.institute/t/leaders-in-innovation-fellowship-year-3/1731</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2017 10:52:27 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">community.source.institute-topic-1731</guid>
          <source url="https://community.source.institute/t/leaders-in-innovation-fellowship-year-3/1731.rss">Leaders in Innovation Fellowship - Year 3</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>The Sources - online story-telling between Africa&#39;s successful tech founders</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@salim Salim Virani]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Projects</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/u/salim">@salim</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p>The Sources is an online course for African technology entrepreneurs.</p>
<p>It exists to empower entrepreneurs by exposing them to African founders who’ve walked the same path, and does so by sharing typically African challenges and appraoches, right from the source.  It started from an obvious gap in educational material for African markets,<br>
and has been encouraged by well-regarded communities like Techcabal and the<br>
Meltwater Entrepreneurial School Of Technology (MEST).</p>
<p>It develops and demonstrates well-known but underrated type of peer-education – storytelling – by bringing it online.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>It creates higher-impact education by covering more relevant topics, and by delivering the education as it’s needed.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>It filters out the most active and ambitious applicants from a high volume of students.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Sign up to see it for yourself at <a href="http://www.thesources.co">www.thesources.co</a>.</p>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 1</p>
            <p>Participants: 1</p>
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/t/the-sources-online-story-telling-between-africas-successful-tech-founders/552">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://community.source.institute/t/the-sources-online-story-telling-between-africas-successful-tech-founders/552</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2016 14:46:23 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">community.source.institute-topic-552</guid>
          <source url="https://community.source.institute/t/the-sources-online-story-telling-between-africas-successful-tech-founders/552.rss">The Sources - online story-telling between Africa&#39;s successful tech founders</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Source Camp - June 7 &amp; 8</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@salim Salim Virani]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Projects</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/u/salim">@salim</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <h1>Source Camp</h1>
<h2>Want to learn about what it takes to create a startup communities and culture ?</h2>
<h3>Want to learn from the guys who brought Lean Startup to Europe? Want to hear how the groundwork was laid for startup communities in London? Want to know how local heroes became global thought-leaders?</h3>
<h2>Source Camp</h2>
<p>Source Camp is a 3-day internal knowledge-sharing event at which members of Source Institute teach each other their latest educational and community-building techniques, and share the latest trends.</p>
<h2>History</h2>
<p>Eight months ago, Source Institute formed out of a pre-existing group of Community Builders,  Growth Hackers, Hardware Investors, Creative Entrepreneurs, Educators , Institutional Investors and Internet Entrepreneurs.</p>
<p>Our prior work has been at the heart of building Europe’s startup communities. We brought Lean Startup to Europe in 2009, and spent years connected it to Europe’s strengths, like business model design and user experience design. (These disciplines became part of startup vocabulary around the world because of our community in London.) We designed and delivered startup education programmes for most of the accelerator industry in its first few years, and went on do the same for universities like Oxford, UCL and Imperial.</p>
<p>Since then, things have moved fast.  We’ve designed and developed 2 state-fo-the-art startup education programmes, the Africa Prize, and Leaders In Innovation Fellowship, started a university research consortium on the effectiveness of different forms of entrepreneurship education, released a researched book on effective startup mentoring, and have partnered with a world-wide student organisation to deploy a one-day practicum in starting up which will be deployed to 35,000 new entrepreneurs in 100 countries.  Source Institute is emerging as leaders in peer to peer education.</p>
<h2>The Opportunity</h2>
<p>Source Camp is coming to the sunny meadows of Netherlands. But this time we hold a special opportunity for selected people to join us.</p>
<h2>Learn About:</h2>
<p><strong>Intrapreneurship</strong> - How to foster innovation and change from within a company to an extent which a consultant can’t.<br>
<strong>Community Building</strong> - How to rally a community at a city or organisational level, and leverage its strengths to position that community as a global leader<br>
<strong>Mentor Impact</strong> - A study on what innovation mentoring techniques lead to success<br>
<strong>Decision Hacks</strong> -  A study in how successful founders make good decisions fast.<br>
<strong>Peer Education</strong> - How to create relevant and immediate education in fast-changing environments<br>
<strong>Your Topic</strong> - Have a problem or an idea you want feedback on ? This is your chance.</p>
<h2>Apply to Source Camp</h2>
<p>This is a 2-day event, with a maximum of 15 people.</p>
<p>Day 1 (June 7) - <em>Unconference</em>.   Participants choose the topics, and we run up to 15 one-hour sessions in 3 parallel tracks.  You’ll learn a range of new techniques from the source.</p>
<p>Day 2 (June 8)- <em>Fixers</em> - Participants bring their challenges to each other, and we roll up our sleeves to solve them. You’ll learn how those with complimentary strengths to you think through your challenges and find actionable advice.</p>
<p>There is also time for nature walks and fireside chats.</p>
<h2>To apply</h2>
<p>This is an invitation-only event, so please contact us at hello@source.institute</p>
<p>External rate: 1000 EUR<br>
Source Institute Fellows: 200 EUR</p>
<h2>About Source:</h2>
<p>We build startup communities and design education for fast-changing environments.Having built some of the most innovative names in startup education, we’ve reached over 70,000 entrepreneurs in the most challenging markets on earth. Learn more at <a href="http://source.institute">http://source.institute</a></p>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 1</p>
            <p>Participants: 1</p>
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/t/source-camp-june-7-8/284">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://community.source.institute/t/source-camp-june-7-8/284</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2016 16:10:29 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">community.source.institute-topic-284</guid>
          <source url="https://community.source.institute/t/source-camp-june-7-8/284.rss">Source Camp - June 7 &amp; 8</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Startup Deep Dive - a structured first step in becoming a founder</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@salim Salim Virani]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Projects</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/u/salim">@salim</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p>What do you do when you’re considering being an entrepreneur?</p>
<p>There are a few events that can help.  Startup Weekend, Lean Startup Machine. Those events are designed around launching a startup more than skills building, and the quality of each event really depends on the local organiser and mentors.</p>
<p>In 2016, we think that a new approach is needed.  Something community run, and designed around the growth of founders, rather than the progress of startup ideas.  Deep Dive is a one-day event where you learn to launch, focusing on the skills you need and creating an experience that empowers <em>every</em> participant, helping them decide if being a founder is right for them and if it is, giving them the skills, support and momentum to take the next steps.</p>
<h1>The opportunity</h1>
<p>We’re working with AIESEC, a global student organisation, spanning 120 countries and covering 60,000 students per year.  Their goal is develop world citizens with leadership skills.   This means Deep Dive will be run globally, including strong presences in countries where startups aren’t common.</p>
<h1>The challenge</h1>
<p>To design a programme that enables everyone to be a founder, but is facilitated by non-entrepreneurs.  We’ve seen horribly failed attempts at taking workshop material designed to be taught by entrepreneurs and handing it over to inexperienced students to teach.  So many accelerators and innovation consultancies fail because they’ve taken this approach. A ground-up redesign is in order.</p>
<p>Plus, the global footprint of this programme also means that what’s taught must be relevant to that region, even though local business mentors may not available.</p>
<h1>What we’re doing with AIESEC</h1>
<p>#<span class="hashtag">#Design</span><br>
We’re investing heavily in a new programme design and new forms of interactive education.</p>
<p>Deep Dive is being designed based on learnable facilitation skills, and modules that can regionalise easily. Entrepreneurial expertise is injected using relevance-and-recall techniques we’ve developed for our online video course, The Sources.</p>
<h1>Train The Trainer</h1>
<p>The programme is designed to be self-propagating - so the students can quickly become the teacher.  We’re deploying this programme worldwide, training students to be entrepreneurs with Deep Dive, then supporting them to launch their own businesses within days.  This gives them the experience necessary to turn around and teach the next batch coming in behind them.</p>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 1</p>
            <p>Participants: 1</p>
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/t/startup-deep-dive-a-structured-first-step-in-becoming-a-founder/278">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://community.source.institute/t/startup-deep-dive-a-structured-first-step-in-becoming-a-founder/278</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2016 19:27:12 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">community.source.institute-topic-278</guid>
          <source url="https://community.source.institute/t/startup-deep-dive-a-structured-first-step-in-becoming-a-founder/278.rss">Startup Deep Dive - a structured first step in becoming a founder</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Oxford Career Services</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@salim Salim Virani]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Projects</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/u/salim">@salim</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p>Oxford is one of the world’s most revered universities, with world-leading schools in economics and social enterprise.</p>
<h1>The challenge</h1>
<p>Oxford Career Services wanted students to make informed career decisions, especially given that large companies invest heavily in recruiting Oxford grads.  We were invited to design a weekend programme that:</p>
<ol>
<li>Gave students a realistic sense of being an entrepreneurs</li>
<li>Gave students skills that were both useful as entrepreneurs, and on the job market</li>
</ol>
<p>#<span class="hashtag">#Design</span> &amp; Delivery<br>
We designed a programme to be delivered by Source-selected entrepreneurs.  It emulated much of the strife of being an entrepreneur while layering on key skills in early-stage technology entrepreneurship. The workshops oscillated from story-telling to application, with teams of students progressing with their business idea.  We’ve run this programme every semester for over 2 years.</p>
<h1>Results</h1>
<p>Immersion achieved 3 important outcomes:</p>
<ol>
<li>It’s exciting and engaging to students, and with little promotion is well-attending, even during busy times of year.</li>
<li>Roughly 10% of attendees actually launch the business they started in Immersion. Others go on to found new companies and still more use their skills to get jobs in startups.</li>
<li>Most importantly, students leave the weekend feeling they’re now in a position to decide for themselves with an important choice: do I go down the startup path?</li>
</ol>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 1</p>
            <p>Participants: 1</p>
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/t/oxford-career-services/203">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://community.source.institute/t/oxford-career-services/203</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 15:27:28 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">community.source.institute-topic-203</guid>
          <source url="https://community.source.institute/t/oxford-career-services/203.rss">Oxford Career Services</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>About the Projects category</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@salim Salim Virani]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Projects</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/u/salim">@salim</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p>This section briefly outlines our main projects and has a few case studies from our service delivery arm, Source Partners.</p>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 1</p>
            <p>Participants: 1</p>
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/t/about-the-projects-category/201">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://community.source.institute/t/about-the-projects-category/201</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 13:30:19 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>Yes</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">community.source.institute-topic-201</guid>
          <source url="https://community.source.institute/t/about-the-projects-category/201.rss">About the Projects category</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Leaders In Innovation Fellowship</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@salim Salim Virani]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Projects</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/u/salim">@salim</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p>The Royal Academy of Engineering is a professional fellowship, which represents the United Kingdom’s best practising engineers, innovators and entrepreneurs.</p>
<p>Its fellows include design leaders James Dyson and Sir Ove Arup, radar pioneer Sir George MacFarlane, and Sir Maurice Wilkes, father of the UK computer industry.</p>
<p>The Leaders In Innovation Fellowship is a pinnacle programme under The Newton Fund, bringing over 200 leading engineers from 15 countries to the UK to support them in commercialising their innovations.</p>
<h1>The challenge</h1>
<p>To design and deliver an education programme that’s relevant to hundreds of engineers from all corners of the world, and operating at a range of stages.</p>
<h1>What we did with The Royal Academy Of Engineering</h1>
<p>#<span class="hashtag">#Design</span><br>
Taking a lead on programme design, we shifted the programme from pre-determined workshops run for each country in isolation, to one where the engineers dictated their learning goals and could learn from each other.</p>
<p>The programme overlapped various country visits, the workshops were redesigned to allow for greater peer-learning, and we added peer-to-peer conferences to allow for these highly-accomplished engineers and entrepreneurs to teach each other.</p>
<p><span class="hashtag">#Peer-Support</span> And Training<br>
To ensure a high bar for participants, we developed a set of experiential workshops which could quickly bring less experienced engineers to an innate understanding of topics like customer interviews, fund-raising and team formation.</p>
<p>We curated and facilitated a number of multi-track peer-conferences, which became the highlight of the entire programme for many of the participants, particularly those who were active entrepreneurs.</p>
<p>Our peer-conferences are now being used as the primary way for alumni in each region to support each other.</p>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 1</p>
            <p>Participants: 1</p>
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/t/leaders-in-innovation-fellowship/200">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://community.source.institute/t/leaders-in-innovation-fellowship/200</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 13:29:25 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">community.source.institute-topic-200</guid>
          <source url="https://community.source.institute/t/leaders-in-innovation-fellowship/200.rss">Leaders In Innovation Fellowship</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>The Africa Prize For Engineering Innovation</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@salim Salim Virani]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Projects</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/u/salim">@salim</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p>The Royal Academy of Engineering is a professional fellowship, which represents the United Kingdom’s best practising engineers, innovators and entrepreneurs. Its fellows include design leaders James Dyson and Sir Ove Arup, radar pioneer Sir George MacFarlane, and Sir Maurice Wilkes, father of the UK computer industry.</p>
<p>The Africa Prize marked a shift from UK-centered support to on-the-ground support across Sub-Saharan Africa.  Source Institiute worked with the Royal Academy, delivering the entire program.</p>
<p>By the second year, we were supporting our innovators to acheive 2-3X growth, addressing multiple national markets and getting international recognition from the likes of the BBC World Service.</p>
<div class="lazyYT" data-youtube-id="ga-sH9bUeWw" data-youtube-title="Africa Prize 2016 on BBC World News, 26/5/16" data-width="480" data-height="270" data-parameters="feature=oembed&amp;wmode=opaque"></div>
<h1>The challenge</h1>
<p>Design and deliver a full 6-month training programme, to address the needs of 15 early-stage engineering startups in a range of markets, stages and technologies.</p>
<p>How can we design and deliver a programme that helps African engineers launch in African markets, founder mindset, marketing channels, funding options and research methods all needed to <strong>be addressed on local terms</strong>?</p>
<div class="lazyYT" data-youtube-id="Q4SwfFDxiz4" data-youtube-title="The Africa Prize for Engineering Innovation" data-width="480" data-height="270" data-parameters="feature=oembed&amp;wmode=opaque"></div>
<h1>What we do with The Royal Academy Of Engineering</h1>
<p>For 3 years, since the start, we’ve delivered all entrepreneur-support aspects of the Africa Prize. Only selection, judging and PR fall outside of our responsibility. Each year, we support 15 African entrepreneurs, aiming to create an inflection point in their growth.</p>
<p>#<span class="hashtag">#Design</span><br>
We blend principles from internet startups and African tech companies, creating new workshops with Africa-specific perspectives on product design and business models.  The program covers business fundamentals from an African tech perspective, and highly-targeted peer-support and peer-education components, which are augmented by including mentors and role models with relevant go-to-market experience.</p>
<p><span class="hashtag">#Peer-Support</span> And Training<br>
Our best trainers and facilitators from Europe and Africa deliver two intensive weeks of training in Ghana, South Africa and Kenya, connected by ongoing remote support.  This training included experiential workshops but emphasised facilitated peer-support, allowing the strengths of each entrepreneur on the shortlist to help others.</p>
<h1>Community-Building</h1>
<p>These were combined with community events, and Source-run uhttp://www.raeng.org.uk/grants-and-prizes/international-research-and-collaborations/africa-prizenconferences, to draw in support and build relationships. The programme connects our startups to the heart of African startup ecosystems through regional leaders like MEST and iHub.</p>
<h1>Learn more</h1>
<p>Source Institute has delivered the full Africa Prize support and education programme since it’s launch in 2014, and continues to deliver and improve upon it.</p>
<p>To keep up to date on the progress - follow us on Medium:</p>
<aside class="onebox whitelistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <img src="https://cdn-static-1.medium.com/_/fp/icons/favicon-rebrand-medium.3Y6xpZ-0FSdWDnPM3hSBIA.ico" class="site-icon" width="32" height="32">
      <a href="https://medium.com/source-institute" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Medium</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <div class="aspect-image" style="--aspect-ratio:324/337;"><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*VYOcB4UFj8FkJS1rr9dmPA.png" class="thumbnail"></div>

<h3><a href="https://medium.com/source-institute" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Source Institute – Medium</a></h3>

<p>Relevant education to the world’s tech founders.</p>


  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

<p>Some glimpes into the story so far:</p>
<aside class="onebox whitelistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <img src="https://cdn-static-1.medium.com/_/fp/icons/favicon-rebrand-medium.3Y6xpZ-0FSdWDnPM3hSBIA.ico" class="site-icon" width="32" height="32">
      <a href="https://medium.com/source-institute/its-hard-for-an-african-engineer-to-explain-to-his-family-why-he-s-working-with-the-labourers-in-d3bde5beda1b#.1cmq0cyv8" target="_blank" title="06:15AM - 21 August 2016" rel="nofollow noopener">Medium – 21 Aug 16</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <div class="aspect-image" style="--aspect-ratio:497/500;"><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*UKBEg8C7em7M1CDiGpjaJg.jpeg" class="thumbnail"></div>

<h3><a href="https://medium.com/source-institute/its-hard-for-an-african-engineer-to-explain-to-his-family-why-he-s-working-with-the-labourers-in-d3bde5beda1b#.1cmq0cyv8" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">It’s hard for an African engineer to explain why he’s joining the labourers in...</a></h3>

<p>If you’ve been lucky enough to be the one chosen among your siblings to go to school, and smart enough to win a university scholarship…</p>

  <p><span class="label1">Reading time: 3 min read</span>
    </p>

  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

<aside class="onebox whitelistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <img src="https://cdn-static-1.medium.com/_/fp/icons/favicon-rebrand-medium.3Y6xpZ-0FSdWDnPM3hSBIA.ico" class="site-icon" width="32" height="32">
      <a href="https://medium.com/source-institute/where-cardiologists-are-in-short-supply-2366405182cd#.jhvj8jy7k" target="_blank" title="08:22AM - 08 November 2016" rel="nofollow noopener">Medium – 8 Nov 16</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <div class="aspect-image" style="--aspect-ratio:690/386;"><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*cvUxUo6LF_ldQanMLh23yg.png" class="thumbnail"></div>

<h3><a href="https://medium.com/source-institute/where-cardiologists-are-in-short-supply-2366405182cd#.jhvj8jy7k" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Where doctors are in short supply, a kid who watched action movies started...</a></h3>

<p>Arthur was one of the top kids in his class, lucky enough to be in school, and yet American movies taught him to skip out.</p>

  <p><span class="label1">Reading time: 3 min read</span>
    </p>

  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

<aside class="onebox whitelistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <img src="https://cdn-static-1.medium.com/_/fp/icons/favicon-rebrand-medium.3Y6xpZ-0FSdWDnPM3hSBIA.ico" class="site-icon" width="32" height="32">
      <a href="https://medium.com/source-institute/the-three-bridge-builders-809d71e4bb30#.3ojzjkc4z" target="_blank" title="09:56AM - 08 October 2016" rel="nofollow noopener">Medium – 8 Oct 16</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <div class="aspect-image" style="--aspect-ratio:690/345;"><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*ghX5qe78X9S38upfO21Z3g.png" class="thumbnail"></div>

<h3><a href="https://medium.com/source-institute/the-three-bridge-builders-809d71e4bb30#.3ojzjkc4z" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">The Fable Of The Three Bridge-Builders – Source Institute – Medium</a></h3>

<p>A story about ambition and high-growth investment</p>

  <p><span class="label1">Reading time: 2 min read</span>
    </p>

  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

<aside class="onebox whitelistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <img src="//community.source.institute/uploads/default/original/1X/bbff99dcc5c2a37b51d819e1d278d280aae8eaa6.png" class="site-icon" width="51" height="52">
      <a href="https://medium.com/@SaintSal/cross-ecosystem-grinding-a4f22e846d8d#.hdrbs3gah" target="_blank" title="06:54AM - 24 August 2016" rel="nofollow noopener">Source Institute Community – 24 Aug 16</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <div class="aspect-image" style="--aspect-ratio:640/400;"><img src="//community.source.institute/uploads/default/original/1X/1e5e577240709b0c43f2dacb3a93ff48e406ff16.png" class="thumbnail"></div>

<h3><a href="https://medium.com/@SaintSal/cross-ecosystem-grinding-a4f22e846d8d#.hdrbs3gah" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Cross-Ecosystem Grinding</a></h3>

<p>Why do African startups get dropped by EU/US investors?  Sean Obedih from New Gen Angels asked me to share this internal note I shared with The Africa Prize alumni in advance of their visit to London.   He pointed out this is a typical conversation...</p>


  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

<aside class="onebox whitelistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <img src="https://cdn-static-1.medium.com/_/fp/icons/favicon-rebrand-medium.3Y6xpZ-0FSdWDnPM3hSBIA.ico" class="site-icon" width="32" height="32">
      <a href="https://medium.com/source-institute/mentoring-tip-calibrate-your-advice-before-you-give-it-b17202c52377#.sv884izfb" target="_blank" title="05:30PM - 24 August 2016" rel="nofollow noopener">Medium – 24 Aug 16</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <div class="aspect-image" style="--aspect-ratio:690/459;"><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*IOKdTU6fvHI6ltZUJaUylA.jpeg" class="thumbnail"></div>

<h3><a href="https://medium.com/source-institute/mentoring-tip-calibrate-your-advice-before-you-give-it-b17202c52377#.sv884izfb" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Do you calibrate your advice before you give it? – Source Institute – Medium</a></h3>

<p>An excerpt from my book Mentor Impact — we found the mentors that truly changed startups, and we asked them how they do it.</p>

  <p><span class="label1">Reading time: 4 min read</span>
    </p>

  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

<aside class="onebox whitelistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <img src="https://cdn-static-1.medium.com/_/fp/icons/favicon-rebrand-medium.3Y6xpZ-0FSdWDnPM3hSBIA.ico" class="site-icon" width="32" height="32">
      <a href="https://medium.com/source-institute/the-africa-prize-for-engineering-is-coming-to-london-42f4a458ae1c#.q88t9lytw" target="_blank" title="08:43AM - 16 August 2016" rel="nofollow noopener">Medium – 16 Aug 16</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <div class="aspect-image" style="--aspect-ratio:640/480;"><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*n_455pisuHL9tHrHKBkUdw.jpeg" class="thumbnail"></div>

<h3><a href="https://medium.com/source-institute/the-africa-prize-for-engineering-is-coming-to-london-42f4a458ae1c#.q88t9lytw" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Meet The Africa Prize For Engineering – Source Institute – Medium</a></h3>

<p>In the last two years, I’ve looked dead-serious in the eyes of a more than a few founders, saying “you have a billion-dollar business in…</p>

  <p><span class="label1">Reading time: 8 min read</span>
    </p>

  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 1</p>
            <p>Participants: 1</p>
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/t/the-africa-prize-for-engineering-innovation/150">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://community.source.institute/t/the-africa-prize-for-engineering-innovation/150</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2016 14:19:27 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">community.source.institute-topic-150</guid>
          <source url="https://community.source.institute/t/the-africa-prize-for-engineering-innovation/150.rss">The Africa Prize For Engineering Innovation</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Network to bring academic integrity to entrepreneurship education</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@bart Bart Doorneweert]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Projects</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/u/bart">@bart</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p><strong>The Opportunity</strong><br>
To build a continuous network for exchange of learnings, peer reviewed research, and the latest about entrepreneurship education, including P2P methods.</p>
<p><strong>Common Goal - how will it make a difference?</strong><br>
The current Erasmus network exists of educators, who all see that we need to step our game on entrepreneurship education. The questions we’ll be addressing through this current starting phase of the network, is how to effectively design P2P learning mechanisms into entrepreneurship education.</p>
<p><strong>Organisation Goals:</strong><br>
<strong>Wageningen University</strong> is known for cross disciplinary research in food and agriculture. It already addresses entrepreneurship in some of its course, but the idea is to further the topic through all of the university courses. Entrepreneurship is not yet part of the culture in food and agriculture. This has to built in through education.</p>
<p><strong>University of Copenhagen</strong> has been ramping up university teachers’ skills to become better at entrepreneurship education. The university is also actively picking up its role in entrepreneurship ecosystem development.</p>
<p><strong>University of Tartu</strong> is actively pursuing entrepreneurship education, and making courses in their curricula. They want to build on this dynamic with new insights on education.</p>
<p><strong>University of Lisbo</strong>n has very little experience with entrepreneurship education. But the faculty of Human Kinetics is actively looking for ways of involving its students entrepreneurship, to figure out how it can be integrated into the field of sports, and rehabilitation.</p>
<p><strong>Enterprise Educators UK</strong> aims to promote enterprise education within every university in the UK, regardless of the business orientation of the course or not. They have a stack of approaches available that they want to bring into this network for experimentation.</p>
<p><strong>Source Institute</strong> is developing the forefront of P2P education, and has leeway to try and test the latest in techniques before it is a thing. We are here to feed the network with new insights, and learn about how to look out for efficacy of P2P education techniques.</p>
<p><strong>Strategic relevance:</strong><br>
This is an opportunity to build a P2P network around P2P EntEd. We have the opportunity to build a body of authority in the education community through this network, we help define what’s important to measure as outcomes. Our competitors can either choose to join it, or build their own.</p>
<p><strong>Budget:</strong><br>
Euro 90k</p>
<p><strong>Timeline:</strong><br>
36 months, starting from July 2016.</p>
<p><strong>People needed:</strong><br>
Sal and Bart for helping feed the network with tools and edcuation experiences on P2P<br>
Other Source Fellows can be included for either of the 5 Source Summits that will be held during the course of this project.</p>
<p><strong>Resources needed:</strong><br>
For Source, this is an investment project. We’re only getting some compensation for our time and effort. We’ll ask for Source Fellow’s support on a voluntary basis, and arrange for compensation if that is possible. The return will lie in meeting the entrepreneurship network in 5 european cities, and in being part of network that sets the tone for entrepreneurship education to come.</p>
<p><strong>Outcomes:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>proven-effective P2P methods</li>
<li>spread of the Source brand in the right way, through the 5 Summits that will be held in this project</li>
<li>recognition from our new, and existing client/partners of our involvement in this network</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Description:</strong></p>
<p>To keep the consortium focused on key challenge areas in the broader EntEd industry, we’ll run several research cycles per year, each of which will start by convening key actors in EntEd to share their challenges and approaches. This will help us choose both success measures, educational methods to test, and expose context to help define experiements.  Experiments will be designed, run and analysed by participating universities, and the impact of our efforts will be shared at the beginning of the following cycle. This iterative approach will help keep us relevant, and keep the scope of our efforts as a consortium manageable, improving our approach as we go.</p>
<p>Source’s core contribution to this project consists of 2 points:</p>
<ol>
<li>Participating in the consortium meeting, where the relevant new experiments on P2P learning approaches are discussed, and decided.</li>
<li>Organise Source Summits around this meeting, to pull in the voices from the local entrepreneurial community, where the meeting will be held. The project results will be promoted through the Source Summit website.</li>
</ol>
<p>The universities involved will take the lead in implementing the experiments, analysing results, and learning from them. Also universities will support us to organise the Summits, and identify &amp; attract the various voices from the local ecosystem.</p>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 2</p>
            <p>Participants: 2</p>
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/t/network-to-bring-academic-integrity-to-entrepreneurship-education/87">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://community.source.institute/t/network-to-bring-academic-integrity-to-entrepreneurship-education/87</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2016 14:38:51 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">community.source.institute-topic-87</guid>
          <source url="https://community.source.institute/t/network-to-bring-academic-integrity-to-entrepreneurship-education/87.rss">Network to bring academic integrity to entrepreneurship education</source>
        </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
