<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Network to bring academic integrity to entrepreneurship education</title>
    <link>https://community.source.institute/t/network-to-bring-academic-integrity-to-entrepreneurship-education/87</link>
    <description>**The Opportunity**
To build a continuous network for exchange of learnings, peer reviewed research, and the latest about entrepreneurship education, including P2P methods.

**Common Goal - how will it make a difference?**
The current Erasmus network exists of educators, who all see that we need to step our game on entrepreneurship education. The questions we&#39;ll be addressing through this current starting phase of the network, is how to effectively design P2P learning mechanisms into entrepreneurship education. 

**Organisation Goals:**
**Wageningen University** is known for cross disciplinary research in food and agriculture. It already addresses entrepreneurship in some of its course, but the idea is to further the topic through all of the university courses. Entrepreneurship is not yet part of the culture in food and agriculture. This has to built in through education.

**University of Copenhagen** has been ramping up university teachers&#39; skills to become better at entrepreneurship education. The university is also actively picking up its role in entrepreneurship ecosystem development.

**University of Tartu** is actively pursuing entrepreneurship education, and making courses in their curricula. They want to build on this dynamic with new insights on education.

**University of Lisbo**n has very little experience with entrepreneurship education. But the faculty of Human Kinetics is actively looking for ways of involving its students entrepreneurship, to figure out how it can be integrated into the field of sports, and rehabilitation.

**Enterprise Educators UK** aims to promote enterprise education within every university in the UK, regardless of the business orientation of the course or not. They have a stack of approaches available that they want to bring into this network for experimentation.

**Source Institute** is developing the forefront of P2P education, and has leeway to try and test the latest in techniques before it is a thing. We are here to feed the network with new insights, and learn about how to look out for efficacy of P2P education techniques. 

**Strategic relevance:** 
This is an opportunity to build a P2P network around P2P EntEd. We have the opportunity to build a body of authority in the education community through this network, we help define what&#39;s important to measure as outcomes. Our competitors can either choose to join it, or build their own. 

**Budget:**
Euro 90k

**Timeline:**
36 months, starting from July 2016.

**People needed:**
Sal and Bart for helping feed the network with tools and edcuation experiences on P2P
Other Source Fellows can be included for either of the 5 Source Summits that will be held during the course of this project. 

**Resources needed:**
For Source, this is an investment project. We&#39;re only getting some compensation for our time and effort. We&#39;ll ask for Source Fellow&#39;s support on a voluntary basis, and arrange for compensation if that is possible. The return will lie in meeting the entrepreneurship network in 5 european cities, and in being part of network that sets the tone for entrepreneurship education to come.

**Outcomes:**
* proven-effective P2P methods
* spread of the Source brand in the right way, through the 5 Summits that will be held in this project
* recognition from our new, and existing client/partners of our involvement in this network

**Description:**

To keep the consortium focused on key challenge areas in the broader EntEd industry, we&#39;ll run several research cycles per year, each of which will start by convening key actors in EntEd to share their challenges and approaches. This will help us choose both success measures, educational methods to test, and expose context to help define experiements.  Experiments will be designed, run and analysed by participating universities, and the impact of our efforts will be shared at the beginning of the following cycle. This iterative approach will help keep us relevant, and keep the scope of our efforts as a consortium manageable, improving our approach as we go.

Source&#39;s core contribution to this project consists of 2 points:

1. Participating in the consortium meeting, where the relevant new experiments on P2P learning approaches are discussed, and decided.
2. Organise Source Summits around this meeting, to pull in the voices from the local entrepreneurial community, where the meeting will be held. The project results will be promoted through the Source Summit website.

The universities involved will take the lead in implementing the experiments, analysing results, and learning from them. Also universities will support us to organise the Summits, and identify &amp; attract the various voices from the local ecosystem.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2016 14:39:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Projects</category>
    <atom:link href="https://community.source.institute/t/network-to-bring-academic-integrity-to-entrepreneurship-education/87.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Network to bring academic integrity to entrepreneurship education</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@salim Salim Virani]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/u/salim">@salim</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Seeing each partner’s goals was really useful for me.  I like combining our respective super-powers. I picture us all combining into a Japanese super-robot.</p>
<p><div class="lightbox-wrapper"><a class="lightbox" href="//community.source.institute/uploads/default/original/1X/c1d3359a5e0fad654984cad750f1a2357caad2d5.JPG" data-download-href="//community.source.institute/uploads/default/c1d3359a5e0fad654984cad750f1a2357caad2d5" title="Daizyujin+1.JPG"><img src="//community.source.institute/uploads/default/optimized/1X/c1d3359a5e0fad654984cad750f1a2357caad2d5_2_373x500.JPG" width="373" height="500" srcset="//community.source.institute/uploads/default/optimized/1X/c1d3359a5e0fad654984cad750f1a2357caad2d5_2_373x500.JPG, //community.source.institute/uploads/default/optimized/1X/c1d3359a5e0fad654984cad750f1a2357caad2d5_2_559x750.JPG 1.5x, //community.source.institute/uploads/default/original/1X/c1d3359a5e0fad654984cad750f1a2357caad2d5.JPG 2x" data-small-upload="//community.source.institute/uploads/default/optimized/1X/c1d3359a5e0fad654984cad750f1a2357caad2d5_2_10x10.png"><div class="meta">
<svg class="fa d-icon d-icon-far-image svg-icon" aria-hidden="true"><use xlink:href="#far-image"></use></svg><span class="filename">Daizyujin+1.JPG</span><span class="informations">581×778 143 KB</span><svg class="fa d-icon d-icon-discourse-expand svg-icon" aria-hidden="true"><use xlink:href="#discourse-expand"></use></svg>
</div></a></div></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/t/network-to-bring-academic-integrity-to-entrepreneurship-education/87/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://community.source.institute/t/network-to-bring-academic-integrity-to-entrepreneurship-education/87/2</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2016 14:39:59 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.source.institute-post-87-2</guid>
        <source url="https://community.source.institute/t/network-to-bring-academic-integrity-to-entrepreneurship-education/87.rss">Network to bring academic integrity to entrepreneurship education</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Network to bring academic integrity to entrepreneurship education</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@bart Bart Doorneweert]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/u/bart">@bart</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p><strong>The Opportunity</strong><br>
To build a continuous network for exchange of learnings, peer reviewed research, and the latest about entrepreneurship education, including P2P methods.</p>
<p><strong>Common Goal - how will it make a difference?</strong><br>
The current Erasmus network exists of educators, who all see that we need to step our game on entrepreneurship education. The questions we’ll be addressing through this current starting phase of the network, is how to effectively design P2P learning mechanisms into entrepreneurship education.</p>
<p><strong>Organisation Goals:</strong><br>
<strong>Wageningen University</strong> is known for cross disciplinary research in food and agriculture. It already addresses entrepreneurship in some of its course, but the idea is to further the topic through all of the university courses. Entrepreneurship is not yet part of the culture in food and agriculture. This has to built in through education.</p>
<p><strong>University of Copenhagen</strong> has been ramping up university teachers’ skills to become better at entrepreneurship education. The university is also actively picking up its role in entrepreneurship ecosystem development.</p>
<p><strong>University of Tartu</strong> is actively pursuing entrepreneurship education, and making courses in their curricula. They want to build on this dynamic with new insights on education.</p>
<p><strong>University of Lisbo</strong>n has very little experience with entrepreneurship education. But the faculty of Human Kinetics is actively looking for ways of involving its students entrepreneurship, to figure out how it can be integrated into the field of sports, and rehabilitation.</p>
<p><strong>Enterprise Educators UK</strong> aims to promote enterprise education within every university in the UK, regardless of the business orientation of the course or not. They have a stack of approaches available that they want to bring into this network for experimentation.</p>
<p><strong>Source Institute</strong> is developing the forefront of P2P education, and has leeway to try and test the latest in techniques before it is a thing. We are here to feed the network with new insights, and learn about how to look out for efficacy of P2P education techniques.</p>
<p><strong>Strategic relevance:</strong><br>
This is an opportunity to build a P2P network around P2P EntEd. We have the opportunity to build a body of authority in the education community through this network, we help define what’s important to measure as outcomes. Our competitors can either choose to join it, or build their own.</p>
<p><strong>Budget:</strong><br>
Euro 90k</p>
<p><strong>Timeline:</strong><br>
36 months, starting from July 2016.</p>
<p><strong>People needed:</strong><br>
Sal and Bart for helping feed the network with tools and edcuation experiences on P2P<br>
Other Source Fellows can be included for either of the 5 Source Summits that will be held during the course of this project.</p>
<p><strong>Resources needed:</strong><br>
For Source, this is an investment project. We’re only getting some compensation for our time and effort. We’ll ask for Source Fellow’s support on a voluntary basis, and arrange for compensation if that is possible. The return will lie in meeting the entrepreneurship network in 5 european cities, and in being part of network that sets the tone for entrepreneurship education to come.</p>
<p><strong>Outcomes:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>proven-effective P2P methods</li>
<li>spread of the Source brand in the right way, through the 5 Summits that will be held in this project</li>
<li>recognition from our new, and existing client/partners of our involvement in this network</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Description:</strong></p>
<p>To keep the consortium focused on key challenge areas in the broader EntEd industry, we’ll run several research cycles per year, each of which will start by convening key actors in EntEd to share their challenges and approaches. This will help us choose both success measures, educational methods to test, and expose context to help define experiements.  Experiments will be designed, run and analysed by participating universities, and the impact of our efforts will be shared at the beginning of the following cycle. This iterative approach will help keep us relevant, and keep the scope of our efforts as a consortium manageable, improving our approach as we go.</p>
<p>Source’s core contribution to this project consists of 2 points:</p>
<ol>
<li>Participating in the consortium meeting, where the relevant new experiments on P2P learning approaches are discussed, and decided.</li>
<li>Organise Source Summits around this meeting, to pull in the voices from the local entrepreneurial community, where the meeting will be held. The project results will be promoted through the Source Summit website.</li>
</ol>
<p>The universities involved will take the lead in implementing the experiments, analysing results, and learning from them. Also universities will support us to organise the Summits, and identify &amp; attract the various voices from the local ecosystem.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/t/network-to-bring-academic-integrity-to-entrepreneurship-education/87/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://community.source.institute/t/network-to-bring-academic-integrity-to-entrepreneurship-education/87/1</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2016 14:38:51 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.source.institute-post-87-1</guid>
        <source url="https://community.source.institute/t/network-to-bring-academic-integrity-to-entrepreneurship-education/87.rss">Network to bring academic integrity to entrepreneurship education</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
