<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Source Camp - June 7 &amp; 8</title>
    <link>https://community.source.institute/t/source-camp-june-7-8/284</link>
    <description># Source Camp

## Want to learn about what it takes to create a startup communities and culture ?

### Want to learn from the guys who brought Lean Startup to Europe? Want to hear how the groundwork was laid for startup communities in London? Want to know how local heroes became global thought-leaders?

## Source Camp

Source Camp is a 3-day internal knowledge-sharing event at which members of Source Institute teach each other their latest educational and community-building techniques, and share the latest trends.

## History 

Eight months ago, Source Institute formed out of a pre-existing group of Community Builders,  Growth Hackers, Hardware Investors, Creative Entrepreneurs, Educators , Institutional Investors and Internet Entrepreneurs. 

Our prior work has been at the heart of building Europe&#39;s startup communities. We brought Lean Startup to Europe in 2009, and spent years connected it to Europe&#39;s strengths, like business model design and user experience design. (These disciplines became part of startup vocabulary around the world because of our community in London.) We designed and delivered startup education programmes for most of the accelerator industry in its first few years, and went on do the same for universities like Oxford, UCL and Imperial.  

Since then, things have moved fast.  We&#39;ve designed and developed 2 state-fo-the-art startup education programmes, the Africa Prize, and Leaders In Innovation Fellowship, started a university research consortium on the effectiveness of different forms of entrepreneurship education, released a researched book on effective startup mentoring, and have partnered with a world-wide student organisation to deploy a one-day practicum in starting up which will be deployed to 35,000 new entrepreneurs in 100 countries.  Source Institute is emerging as leaders in peer to peer education. 


## The Opportunity

Source Camp is coming to the sunny meadows of Netherlands. But this time we hold a special opportunity for selected people to join us.

## Learn About:

**Intrapreneurship** - How to foster innovation and change from within a company to an extent which a consultant can’t.
**Community Building** - How to rally a community at a city or organisational level, and leverage its strengths to position that community as a global leader
**Mentor Impact** - A study on what innovation mentoring techniques lead to success
**Decision Hacks** -  A study in how successful founders make good decisions fast.
**Peer Education** - How to create relevant and immediate education in fast-changing environments
**Your Topic** - Have a problem or an idea you want feedback on ? This is your chance.


## Apply to Source Camp

This is a 2-day event, with a maximum of 15 people. 

Day 1 (June 7) - _Unconference_.   Participants choose the topics, and we run up to 15 one-hour sessions in 3 parallel tracks.  You&#39;ll learn a range of new techniques from the source.

Day 2 (June 8)- _Fixers_ - Participants bring their challenges to each other, and we roll up our sleeves to solve them. You&#39;ll learn how those with complimentary strengths to you think through your challenges and find actionable advice.

There is also time for nature walks and fireside chats.

## To apply

This is an invitation-only event, so please contact us at hello@source.institute

External rate: 1000 EUR
Source Institute Fellows: 200 EUR

## About Source:

We build startup communities and design education for fast-changing environments.Having built some of the most innovative names in startup education, we&#39;ve reached over 70,000 entrepreneurs in the most challenging markets on earth. Learn more at http://source.institute</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 May 2016 13:02:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Projects</category>
    <atom:link href="https://community.source.institute/t/source-camp-june-7-8/284.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Source Camp - June 7 &amp; 8</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@salim Salim Virani]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/u/salim">@salim</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <h1>Source Camp</h1>
<h2>Want to learn about what it takes to create a startup communities and culture ?</h2>
<h3>Want to learn from the guys who brought Lean Startup to Europe? Want to hear how the groundwork was laid for startup communities in London? Want to know how local heroes became global thought-leaders?</h3>
<h2>Source Camp</h2>
<p>Source Camp is a 3-day internal knowledge-sharing event at which members of Source Institute teach each other their latest educational and community-building techniques, and share the latest trends.</p>
<h2>History</h2>
<p>Eight months ago, Source Institute formed out of a pre-existing group of Community Builders,  Growth Hackers, Hardware Investors, Creative Entrepreneurs, Educators , Institutional Investors and Internet Entrepreneurs.</p>
<p>Our prior work has been at the heart of building Europe’s startup communities. We brought Lean Startup to Europe in 2009, and spent years connected it to Europe’s strengths, like business model design and user experience design. (These disciplines became part of startup vocabulary around the world because of our community in London.) We designed and delivered startup education programmes for most of the accelerator industry in its first few years, and went on do the same for universities like Oxford, UCL and Imperial.</p>
<p>Since then, things have moved fast.  We’ve designed and developed 2 state-fo-the-art startup education programmes, the Africa Prize, and Leaders In Innovation Fellowship, started a university research consortium on the effectiveness of different forms of entrepreneurship education, released a researched book on effective startup mentoring, and have partnered with a world-wide student organisation to deploy a one-day practicum in starting up which will be deployed to 35,000 new entrepreneurs in 100 countries.  Source Institute is emerging as leaders in peer to peer education.</p>
<h2>The Opportunity</h2>
<p>Source Camp is coming to the sunny meadows of Netherlands. But this time we hold a special opportunity for selected people to join us.</p>
<h2>Learn About:</h2>
<p><strong>Intrapreneurship</strong> - How to foster innovation and change from within a company to an extent which a consultant can’t.<br>
<strong>Community Building</strong> - How to rally a community at a city or organisational level, and leverage its strengths to position that community as a global leader<br>
<strong>Mentor Impact</strong> - A study on what innovation mentoring techniques lead to success<br>
<strong>Decision Hacks</strong> -  A study in how successful founders make good decisions fast.<br>
<strong>Peer Education</strong> - How to create relevant and immediate education in fast-changing environments<br>
<strong>Your Topic</strong> - Have a problem or an idea you want feedback on ? This is your chance.</p>
<h2>Apply to Source Camp</h2>
<p>This is a 2-day event, with a maximum of 15 people.</p>
<p>Day 1 (June 7) - <em>Unconference</em>.   Participants choose the topics, and we run up to 15 one-hour sessions in 3 parallel tracks.  You’ll learn a range of new techniques from the source.</p>
<p>Day 2 (June 8)- <em>Fixers</em> - Participants bring their challenges to each other, and we roll up our sleeves to solve them. You’ll learn how those with complimentary strengths to you think through your challenges and find actionable advice.</p>
<p>There is also time for nature walks and fireside chats.</p>
<h2>To apply</h2>
<p>This is an invitation-only event, so please contact us at hello@source.institute</p>
<p>External rate: 1000 EUR<br>
Source Institute Fellows: 200 EUR</p>
<h2>About Source:</h2>
<p>We build startup communities and design education for fast-changing environments.Having built some of the most innovative names in startup education, we’ve reached over 70,000 entrepreneurs in the most challenging markets on earth. Learn more at <a href="http://source.institute">http://source.institute</a></p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/t/source-camp-june-7-8/284/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://community.source.institute/t/source-camp-june-7-8/284/1</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2016 16:10:29 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.source.institute-post-284-1</guid>
        <source url="https://community.source.institute/t/source-camp-june-7-8/284.rss">Source Camp - June 7 &amp; 8</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
