<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:discourse="http://www.discourse.org/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>The Sources - Source Institute</title>
    <link>https://community.source.institute/c/the-sources</link>
    <description>Topics in the &#39;The Sources&#39; category The Sources is an online course for tech founders that gives you locally-relevant knowledge, starting with Sub-Saharan Africa.  We interview successful founders, and share their diverse experiences and advice in short lessons.</description>
    
      <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 12:35:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      <atom:link href="https://community.source.institute/c/the-sources.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
          <title>Starting a Company is like a Rambo Movie</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@ehalsey1 Eric Halsey]]></dc:creator>
          <category>The Sources</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/u/ehalsey1">@ehalsey1</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p>Louis-Antoine Muhire, is a Rwandan who made a new life in Canada as a Police Intelligence Officer. However, in spite of his success there, he decided to return to Rwanda to build a better remittance system, inspired by his own frustration sending money back home.</p>
<p>After three years of work, his company, <a href="https://www.mergims.com">Mergims</a>, has now raised 4 rounds of funding and is valued at 5 million US dollars. He sees his experience as being something like a Rambo movie from the 90s:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>I have this philosophy, actually it’s because I watched too many movies of Rambo, you know those movies from the 90s, and I realized something. This guy always has a plan, okay, you gotta go, do this, attack, the Vietnamese, and there’s like 10 or 20 American GIs, well equipped, but once they landed they always shoot the first one and then it’s always the guy with the plans and nothing works anymore the way they thought of.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>And in the end, maybe two come back totally destroyed. That’s how the business thing is, you have to have a business plan, financial projections, but the moment you start executing your idea, things go where they want to go. Now the only one who survives, the one who’s really able to adapt yourself to the condition.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>So, at the center of the whole mess is being honest with people. I really love those movies where the other GIs are so beaten and there’s always one guy who’s confident and they ask him “so, what do you think, how are we gonna survive?” He’s like “man, I don’t know, but let’s just finish them.” And in the end, they make it.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>But, I was constantly honest with everyone I worked with. I tell them when we run out of money, or tell them what’s not pleasant to say but I have to say it, but when you’re honest with people they help you and it keeps your business moving around. That was my Rambo story.</p>
</blockquote>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 2</p>
            <p>Participants: 2</p>
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/t/starting-a-company-is-like-a-rambo-movie/1863">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://community.source.institute/t/starting-a-company-is-like-a-rambo-movie/1863</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 12:35:23 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">community.source.institute-topic-1863</guid>
          <source url="https://community.source.institute/t/starting-a-company-is-like-a-rambo-movie/1863.rss">Starting a Company is like a Rambo Movie</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Partnership Gone Wrong</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@ehalsey1 Eric Halsey]]></dc:creator>
          <category>The Sources</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/u/ehalsey1">@ehalsey1</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p>Louis-Antoine Muhire, is a Rwandan who made a new life in Canada as a Police Intelligence Officer. However, in spite of his success there, he decided to return to Rwanda to build a better remittance system, inspired by his own frustration sending money back home.</p>
<p>After three years of work, his company, <a href="https://www.mergims.com">Mergims</a>, has now raised 4 rounds of funding and is valued at 5 million US dollars. Along the way, however, he experienced what can happen when you bring the wrong partner into your company.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Sometimes you bring in some partners and now you’re stuck with them. You don’t know how to get rid of them. Because legally, they’re in, but they’re not delivering. So you expect one day to buy them out. Because if you force them out it becomes a legal battle and nobody will invest in a company with a legal battle.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>The guy, he promised to invest money so we can merge our technology. And we met in a very cushy, a little bit political conference where everybody’s trying to show. So I pitched, he loved the idea, he said “I’m gonna put money” So I said sure.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Then for 6 months, once we had signed a few papers of shared agreement, we included him on our registration and things because that was his requirement. Then, he disappeared, for 6 months we couldn’t get in touch with him. We wrote emails, we got him on whatsapp and he blocked us, he has a very significant share of the equity of the company and his technology is not available. And we learned even after that, his technology company we wanted to bring on our system failed. It went bankrupt</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>So now we’re stuck with him because he owns some equity in our company but he’s not providing what he’s promised. So probably it’s going to be a legal battle and we’re going to get rid of him easily because he didn’t bring his share on the plate. But still, it was a very stressful moment. How do you explain to other investors who come in “woah, this guys not really here, it’s just an empty chair but you can take it. It’s taken by someone who’s not there”</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>So we managed to, for example, to have him explaining the situation clearly so whenever anyone else comes in we take him off, show what’s happened exactly, and show that he has no decision making in our system. He’s just a matter of time once we’ve sorted all the papers, he’s out.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>We had agreed to push and it wasn’t a pleasant thing. So now whenever you bring a partner, find a way of, if things are not going the way you agreed, automatically you separate It’s called a prenup, something like that. Otherwise you’re stuck with someone comes, has nothing, he gets back, he has half of your house, it’s not fair right? So that’s the case of the partner.</p>
</blockquote>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 1</p>
            <p>Participants: 1</p>
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/t/partnership-gone-wrong/1862">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://community.source.institute/t/partnership-gone-wrong/1862</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 12:30:44 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">community.source.institute-topic-1862</guid>
          <source url="https://community.source.institute/t/partnership-gone-wrong/1862.rss">Partnership Gone Wrong</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Building a Beta</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@ehalsey1 Eric Halsey]]></dc:creator>
          <category>The Sources</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/u/ehalsey1">@ehalsey1</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p>Louis-Antoine Muhire, is a Rwandan who made a new life in Canada as a Police Intelligence Officer. However, in spite of his success there, he decided to return to Rwanda to build a better remittance system, inspired by his own frustration sending money back home.</p>
<p>After three years of work, his company, <a href="https://www.mergims.com">Mergims</a>, has now raised 4 rounds of funding and is valued at 5 million US dollars. But it all began with building a beta version. Here’s how Muhire did that:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>You have to get as soon as possible to a version of whatever you’re doing. Then if you see nobody’s really paying attention to that you can say “okay maybe I shouldn’t quit my job. Or I should go back to Canada, or whatever.” You have time to pivot again.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>I had a clear vision of what I wanted, but it took me three years. I said "you know what, the beta version is just to prove that someone from Canada can pay an essential service like electricity in Rwanda. And it has to take less than 1 minute, from the moment the person starts paying to the moment it gets in Rwanda.”</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>If you have people paying, using your services, someone who in a way has no connection with you is paying and using your services. That’s the sign you’re onto something. You don’t need to have 10,000 people. Of course your friends, your brother, your sister will use it. But someone randomly, you start looking at the IP, where it comes from, and all of the sudden it’s from South Korea and you’re like “What?” Then this person comes back, comes back, comes back again. I was like “hey, I’m onto something.”</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>The first 9 months was just chaotic, nothing worked, it was 50% working. And however, every time it wasn’t working I would take, because we monitor our transactions, it doesn’t matter it could be the morning it could be AM in the evening, I would wake up because I had programmed my phone to always notify me whenever there’s a transaction. I was honest, I had these pre-written emails that I would send to them to apologize, like "I’m sorry, this is not working, we have reimbursed your money, please try us again tomorrow.”</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>So I think you have to be honest with people, discuss all the time with your partners, you be very close to your business. I told yesterday to them that you have to love your business if not more, but at least at the same level as your family. If you have a girlfriend, love your business as if it was your second girlfriend. But don’t tell your girlfriend, because she will leave you.</p>
</blockquote>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 1</p>
            <p>Participants: 1</p>
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/t/building-a-beta/1861">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://community.source.institute/t/building-a-beta/1861</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 12:24:59 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">community.source.institute-topic-1861</guid>
          <source url="https://community.source.institute/t/building-a-beta/1861.rss">Building a Beta</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>API Integration with Partners</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@ehalsey1 Eric Halsey]]></dc:creator>
          <category>The Sources</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/u/ehalsey1">@ehalsey1</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p>Louis-Antoine Muhire, is a Rwandan who made a new life in Canada as a Police Intelligence Officer. However, in spite of his success there, he decided to return to Rwanda to build a better remittance system, inspired by his own frustration sending money back home.</p>
<p>After three years of work, his company, <a href="https://www.mergims.com">Mergims</a>, has now raised 4 rounds of funding and is valued at 5 million US dollars. But his business requires integrating with telecoms, electricity companies, and schools. Here’s how he chose those partners and developed the relationships:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>We said, let’s take three essential services that we have identified in my numbers as where the money from the African migrants was going to when it arrives in Africa. So they pay electricity fees, they pay medicine, you know, things that you pay every day. So we took airtime, which is the telecommunication bill, we took electricity, and then we added schools. So those are the three different areas with three different technologies that we wanted to see if we can integrate on our beta version and have them work.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>We focused on that on our beta version. Then, when we launched it, we started with one telecom company, MTN, then for the electricity, there’s one public company in Rwanda, then for the school we started with one school. Not ten, not twenty, just one school. People said “well nobody will pay for that”. But at least you see it working, we’re lucky to have people who go to that school pay and it’s working.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Meanwhile we have some few money we run on and we have to have a great relationship with some service providers and partners to which you can ask for a line of credit, can you advance me your laptops because I have a commitment and if people cannot pay…</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>So we launched out beta version and we connected our partners, electricity, telecoms, we tested, it works, but we didn’t know it couldn’t take two transactions a minute. It could just take one. Because you know when you’re coding you give what’s called timing out frame time. That means the time when the window of request is open, when, for example, request is this service available, when someone is buying a service, the system requests from the partner: do you have this service available to their service.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>So we had quoted that can take one minute window open. So then we got two transactions at the same time, in the same minute, it crashed. We’re like “what’s going on again?” Then after that we realized that and then after that we realized our partners, sometimes they have a slow connection on their servers. We’re like, okay can you fix that?</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>You have to go and discuss with them like "listen guys, you have a 3G internet connection that’s really not reliable, so whenever you’re sending a request it’s crashing because ours is 4G and you’re expecting at least the same speed. And once it’s crash, it crashes the whole system.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Ultimately, Muhire built relationships that allowed him to collaborate to overcome such technical problems as well as negotiate flexible financing terms. These relationships are key for his business’ success.</p>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 1</p>
            <p>Participants: 1</p>
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/t/api-integration-with-partners/1860">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://community.source.institute/t/api-integration-with-partners/1860</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 12:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">community.source.institute-topic-1860</guid>
          <source url="https://community.source.institute/t/api-integration-with-partners/1860.rss">API Integration with Partners</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Finding the Right Market</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@ehalsey1 Eric Halsey]]></dc:creator>
          <category>The Sources</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/u/ehalsey1">@ehalsey1</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p>Louis-Antoine Muhire, is a Rwandan who made a new life in Canada as a Police Intelligence Officer. However, in spite of his success there, he decided to return to Rwanda to build a better remittance system, inspired by his own frustration sending money back home.</p>
<p>After three years of work, his company, <a href="https://www.mergims.com">Mergims</a>, has now raised 4 rounds of funding and is valued at 5 million US dollars. This is how he came up with the initial idea and decided which available markets he could target:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>I was living in Canada and starting to send money back to my relatives to pay essential services, but every time I used a traditional remittance system like Western Union or Moneygram, I had to pay a lot of service fees and it was very expensive, not convenient, you had to line up and file the paper. At the same time, here, my cousins had to pay the transfer costs.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>I got tired of that stress, I said, you know what, I need to do something that will connect me to the institutions that I want to pay for my cousins. So it came out of my frustrations. I realized I wasn’t the only one, most migrants in North America have the same issues as me. I went to see my friends in Canada from the Philippines, they have the same problem, from Latin America, they have the same problem.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>The first move was to evaluate the market. Because yes, I had my problem, but to finance such a technology takes a lot of money. So right away I realized I would have to have a large number of users to make it possible. It’s a 500 Billion USD industry worldwide when migrants send money back to relatives</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>And as far as Africa, it’s 60 Billion, and then, for the East African regions where we started, it’s 3 Billion Dollars coming from outside to Rwanda. So right away I said, you know what? There’s a way to make a viable business if there’s such a huge amount of money going there and nobody seems to have taken care of my problem. Those were the easiest numbers to find because the World Bank has all those reports about how much money is coming in remittances. So you read a lot of reports and that’s how I got all those numbers.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>I was convinced that someone really has to do something about this problem. My first question was, to make it viable, how many people in Rwanda send money to their relatives? That was the small market that I can really start with. It doesn’t mean it’s profitable. It’s called SME, so the servicable available market, that the market where you can start with whatever you have. That was Rwanda.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>And I look if my technology is to serve more people in East Africa, how big will the market be? That’s what they can call the segmented obtainable market, SOM. So then, it’s 3 billion of dollars coming outside to East Africa. You have to start somewhere small, the SOM, the serviceable obtainable market, what you can obtain with whatever you have, the little chaotic beta version you have. Where can you work? It was Rwanda, 200 million, this year we are starting to go in Kenya and Uganda, so 3 billion we’re targeting.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>The first one is TMA, Total Available Market, so the 500 billion, then there’s segmentable obtainable market, that’s East Africa, and the serviceable available market, so that’s Rwanda. It’s SAM, East Africa is SOM, segmented obtainable market, the total available market worldwide is 500 billion.</p>
</blockquote>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 1</p>
            <p>Participants: 1</p>
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/t/finding-the-right-market/1859">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://community.source.institute/t/finding-the-right-market/1859</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 11:31:59 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">community.source.institute-topic-1859</guid>
          <source url="https://community.source.institute/t/finding-the-right-market/1859.rss">Finding the Right Market</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Why You Only Need 3 Shirts</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@ehalsey1 Eric Halsey]]></dc:creator>
          <category>The Sources</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/u/ehalsey1">@ehalsey1</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p>Louis-Antoine Muhire, is a Rwandan who made a new life in Canada as a Police Intelligence Officer. However, in spite of his success there, he decided to return to Rwanda to build a better remittance system, inspired by his own frustration sending money back home.</p>
<p>After three years of work, his company, <a href="https://www.mergims.com">Mergims</a>, has now raised 4 rounds of funding and is valued at 5 million US dollars. Along the way he learned a major lesson about where to spend money which totally changed his perspective on his business. Here’s that story:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>I had only about $10k dollars when I arrived in Rwanda. But when I came, I lived a lifestyle of someone who was from the West. Big house, big cars, everything was big.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>When I left Canada it was winter so I had all the clothes, so in Rwanda I start buying things for a hot country. So I realized I have spent a lot of money on things that really have no value for my company. I have bought nice shoes, nice clothes for the beach and stuff like that. And in three months I was out of money. So quickly I realized, I started looking to other successful people like Zuckerburg, Steve Jobs</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>I see that Steve Jobs has one jeans and one black t-shirt because it was, I don’t know, busy too much. It was a waste of money. And as the fact I ran out of money totally, totally have zero money in my account for one month and went through a very stressful moment, it gave me a sense of value for the money I’m getting.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>And from that I commit myself to really buy 3 shirts, that’s my 3 shirt story. Like three white shirts and three black or blue, dark ones, and three pair of shoes and I know those are international standards, wherever you go you don’t look badly dressed or extremely well dressed.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>To me that question of waking up, trying to see how much you can pay for clothes was over. It saves me money because now every money I get I invest in my company. And that’s what I was saying, because if someone has family, relatives that are depending heavily from his income, he has to obtain their support before, otherwise it will be very difficult.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Today, whenever I’m spending money I have to think three or four times, do we really need this actually, do we really need to, because I remember the first 9 months was extremely painful for me. But, yeah. That was the relationship, I was lucky to have him come a little bit late but helping me. Because he could have said, “you know what, I lost that 20k, you’re part of the 90% I’m have to lose, next!”</p>
</blockquote>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 1</p>
            <p>Participants: 1</p>
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/t/why-you-only-need-3-shirts/1858">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://community.source.institute/t/why-you-only-need-3-shirts/1858</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 11:10:07 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">community.source.institute-topic-1858</guid>
          <source url="https://community.source.institute/t/why-you-only-need-3-shirts/1858.rss">Why You Only Need 3 Shirts</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Hiring 7 People</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@ehalsey1 Eric Halsey]]></dc:creator>
          <category>The Sources</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/u/ehalsey1">@ehalsey1</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p>Louis-Antoine Muhire, is a Rwandan who made a new life in Canada as a Police Intelligence Officer. However, in spite of his success there, he decided to return to Rwanda to build a better remittance system, inspired by his own frustration sending money back home.</p>
<p>After three years of work, his company, <a href="https://www.mergims.com">Mergims</a>, has now raised 4 rounds of funding and is valued at 5 million US dollars. But his greatest mistake he made along the way, according to him, was starting by hiring 7 people. Here’s that story:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>I quit my job and arrived in Rwanda in September 2014. we launched our beta version in February 2015, so it’s almost a 6 month period, the time when I found a house and hired a team of seven people, which was my biggest mistake. I’ll never do that again.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>I got 10k first and I misused that money. I had a great villa, employees, and in three months it’s gone. I had a team of 7 people, for a Canadian startup starting with 7 people, that’s a very huge payroll. Secretary of this, driver of that, cook for us, it was a mini Google thing. And again, the 20k didn’t last too much time. It was gone in 3 months.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Then the investor I met was a South African guy, I met him through a website called VC for Africa, which is a platform where you put your idea there and explain what your working on or what you’ve tried to work on. He gave me money, hoping to not misspend the money that quick.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>I came back to him and said I ran out of the money and he said “woah, what happened?” The money that was supposed to take me to 6 months, I spent it again in 3 months. He said “what’s going on?” So he looked at my numbers and gave me the worst homework to do, to fire everyone. Not two or three, he said "I want you to fire everyone.”</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>“Otherwise there’s no way I’m going to support you to raise more money.” And he didn’t give me a reason. Simply, you have a huge payroll, do whatever you have to do and start over. So I called my team, said guys, we’re out of the money, no money left in the bank. So, who wants to leave. And guess what, nobody wanted to leave. They said "oh no, we’re gonna stay, we’re gonna support you.”</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>I was like “oh shit, actually I want you to leave.” “Oh don’t worry, we can work for free until you get…” I’m like "no, you don’t understand it, this is the email, it says fire everyone and start over. So I did fire everyone and it was a very not beautiful moment because some took it very personal. They thought I was lying, that i dissapointed them because when I recruited them I said "this is gonna be the next big thing. With my passion to speak and stuff.”</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>So there were a lot of tears, and painful moment. I think I stayed three days in bed just to digest that. Then I started over again with three people including me, so that’s two, me, a CTO, and an accountant.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Now when we have a lot of work, what do we do? We go into tech hub, we have one in Kigali called Klab, I hire three or four kids to maybe update our website. We do that but no more huge payroll until I become the next Google. You know, I’ve learned that you hire only when you can’t really take it anymore. Otherwise you do everything, you cook for yourself, you drive yourself, you wash your clothes yourself, you do everything yourself. When I came I had people to do that for me, so yeah.</p>
</blockquote>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 1</p>
            <p>Participants: 1</p>
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/t/hiring-7-people/1857">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://community.source.institute/t/hiring-7-people/1857</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 11:07:35 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">community.source.institute-topic-1857</guid>
          <source url="https://community.source.institute/t/hiring-7-people/1857.rss">Hiring 7 People</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Hybrid Investment Strategies</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@ehalsey1 Eric Halsey]]></dc:creator>
          <category>The Sources</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/u/ehalsey1">@ehalsey1</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p>Louis-Antoine Muhire, is a Rwandan who made a new life in Canada as a Police Intelligence Officer. However, in spite of his success there, he decided to return to Rwanda to build a better remittance system, inspired by his own frustration sending money back home.</p>
<p>After three years of work, his company, <a href="https://www.mergims.com">Mergims</a>, has now raised 4 rounds of funding and is valued at 5 million US dollars. To do that, he combined loans, grants, and investment to maximize his share of the company and his valuation. Here, he explains his strategy for doing that.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Up until now we’ve raised 130 thousand USD, in a period of almost 2 years, and we’ve given only 20% of the company. So those are the shares. In the beginning, most angel investors don’t take more than 10%, if you’re lucky they take 5%, if you’re really really lucky they take like 1%. And they tend to give like 20k. For us, it was less than 5%, which was good.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>But, after that, I quickly realized some grants were available for me, where grants is the money NGOs give you so you can misspend. No, don’t do that. But it can add value in the company, move from the first floor to the second floor without taking equity.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>So now once I realized there are some grants, I said I’m gonna focus on that money until I have something that can really raise more interesting money. And after that we’ve got a little bit before that the South African Investor helped us to raise a little more money with other angel investors, so we gave them some equity.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>And after that we started to go to grants again, I think we’ve done three or four rounds of grants, 80 thousand, was also 20k, 20k, 20k from various organizations. Then we went to a competition, we won up to 35 thousand recently from Switzerland, after that there were some shares that had been given to other partners as a strategic shareholder where, for example, you give 5% to resellers of such services, it comes in with less complication in the long-term commitment.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>So up until now, 20% is gone. Now we are raising our first seed round of 500 thousand dollars and we’re going to give 20% for that. Then 40% will be gone. Then we will need at least 3 rounds again. The next round after that, probably will be 5 million and I will give like 15%, and the last one hopefully will be a crazy one, like 100 million.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>You have to follow with the traction you’re getting, and the more traction you have, the more users the more numbers you have, the more value is added in your company. But definitely don’t do the mistake of giving 50% of your company from day one. You’re dead. Already if you give 20% from day 1 you’re dead.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Because, you will need a lot of rounds, you will need 5 or 6 rounds to raise money before you start going public and now issuing another type of options that are not really direct shares from the company.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>We’re open to what they call hybrid investment, this is when someone can come get equity and the other half can in loan. And then with an option that is we’re raising the other round, where we will be evaluating ourselves at 5 million, why we just give the valuation is we’re not sure of the exact amount we want to raise after this.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>But we’re pretty sure, give the trend we’ve taken, we’ll be at least valuated at double of what we are valued at today. So that’s another thing people have to understand If I start saying, after this 500 we’re gonna raise 2 million, someone says “how do you know that?” But I’m sure we’ll definitely have a valuation that’s at least double.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Questioner: How are you sure?</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Well, the trend, the traffic, the valuation, according to our financial projections. Once you know how much money exactly you need in working capital, because I’m taking us a little bit back, once you know how much traffic you’re gonna get, that’s the traction.</p>
</blockquote>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 1</p>
            <p>Participants: 1</p>
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/t/hybrid-investment-strategies/1856">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://community.source.institute/t/hybrid-investment-strategies/1856</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 08:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">community.source.institute-topic-1856</guid>
          <source url="https://community.source.institute/t/hybrid-investment-strategies/1856.rss">Hybrid Investment Strategies</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Pre and Post-Money Valuations</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@ehalsey1 Eric Halsey]]></dc:creator>
          <category>The Sources</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/u/ehalsey1">@ehalsey1</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p>Louis-Antoine Muhire, is a Rwandan who made a new life in Canada as a Police Intelligence Officer. However, in spite of his success there, he decided to return to Rwanda to build a better remittance system, inspired by his own frustration sending money back home.</p>
<p>After three years of work, his company, <a href="https://www.mergims.com">Mergims</a>, has now raised 4 rounds of funding and is valued at 5 million US dollars. Here, he’s discussing the difference between pre-money valuations and post-money valuations as well as why you have to understand these terms if you’re going to raise investment:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>So [they’re] kind of financing terms that founders have to definitely understand. Otherwise when you go to pitch, they will challenge you, try to mess with that “oh, what’s the pre-money, post?”</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>It’s nothing really sophisticated, it’s just the money before and the money after that. So especially when I was starting to raise half a million, then investors become greedy, they want to take more of your company for less investment.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>The pre-money valuation is the value you have before you get the funding. Like today, how do you value a company with such projections, 2.5 million. But once someone has invested in your company, say you put 200k only, then our post-money the money after it has been invested will be 2.7. So it’s simple, it’s a very simple calculation.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>The letter, the post-money valuation, if the amount you’re raising is not changing then you may give him more for his money. More shares for his money. But before, he may make the money, get the money you want necessary to make the company what you want.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>So now with the projections you’re seeing with the market you’re covering, the traction, then we can say “ah, this year we will valuate up 2.5 million” that’s our pre-money valuation. So now we’re raising 500 then post-money will be 3 million for us.</p>
</blockquote>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 1</p>
            <p>Participants: 1</p>
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/t/pre-and-post-money-valuations/1855">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://community.source.institute/t/pre-and-post-money-valuations/1855</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 08:18:44 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">community.source.institute-topic-1855</guid>
          <source url="https://community.source.institute/t/pre-and-post-money-valuations/1855.rss">Pre and Post-Money Valuations</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>The Raintree Farm Story</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@ehalsey1 Eric Halsey]]></dc:creator>
          <category>The Sources</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/u/ehalsey1">@ehalsey1</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p>The past few lessons have all focused on lessons from our conversation with Teddy Ruge centered around individual topics. This last one follows the story of one of his businesses: Raintree Farms. It covers topics we’ve gone into more detail on in other lessons, but seeing how they all tie together is useful.</p>
<p>#<span class="hashtag">#Early</span> Struggles</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“we struggled for quite a while, from inception up to last year when we deployed a new model. We struggled with access to raw materials. We know the farmers have plenty of land, but it took us a while to realize the meain problem is capital to cultivate the land. So we had to pivot.”<br>
-Teddy Rouge, Founder of Raintree Farms, Co-founder of <a href="http://Remit.ug">Remit.ug</a> and Hive Colab</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Raintree Farms had its fair share of difficulties in the early days. What’s important is how Teddy and his team responded to them. Each time, they would pivot, switch to a different model and test it to see if it would work. Instead of leading them to failure when the first model didn’t work, this strategy has allowed them to adapt until the found the right model.</p>
<p>Through those pivots, the most important conclusion was working capital.</p>
<p>#<span class="hashtag">#Handling</span> Working Capital</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Working capital becomes a barrier. We’ll buy everything you plant, they have 5 acres but they can only afford to cultivate a small portion. So we flipped that model completely, every farmer had to dedicate equal actrage to the crops we need. That meant hiring the farmers from the start and giving them a monthly salary. We calculated how much one hectare can produce and divided it into monthly payments, so we front-endeded their working capital and distributed it throughout the year.”<br>
-Teddy Rouge, Founder of Raintree Farms, Co-founder of <a href="http://Remit.ug">Remit.ug</a> and Hive Colab</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Solving Raintree Farms’ working capital problem required a new model. As Teddy explains above, it meant hiring farmers and telling what to plant and how much. While this may sound dictatorial, what it did was give farmers a more reliable income distributed throughout the year, adding to their quality of life and spreading risk.</p>
<p>But getting farmers to work within this system meant hiring and training them.</p>
<p>#<span class="hashtag">#Hiring</span> and Training</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“We start with a 3 month training period, we have a company owned plantation where they can learn the methods, and it’s paid. We have extension workers who take care of any questions they have. We check in every 2 weeks and give performance check ups.”<br>
-Teddy Rouge, Founder of Raintree Farms, Co-founder of <a href="http://Remit.ug">Remit.ug</a> and Hive Colab</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Obviously, working within this new Raintree Farms system was different than how farmers were used to working, so some training was necessary. Teddy aimed to make this transition easier by ensuring the training was paid and included performance check up to make sure things were being done correctly.</p>
<p>#<span class="hashtag">#Handling</span> Price Fluctuations</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“The prices for what we grow are currently going up, making our access to raw materials more expensive, which is why we went to this model. We took the average and paid the farmers for that. We can predict our raw materials cost because they’re separated from the open market. The more expensive the end product gets, the more profitable we are because we own the entire value chain. We control costs from garden to shelf.”<br>
-Teddy Rouge, Founder of Raintree Farms, Co-founder of <a href="http://Remit.ug">Remit.ug</a> and Hive Colab</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Another main challenge Teddy faces with Raintree farms is the same any farming business faces: price fluctuations. That’s where the integrated Raintree Farms system came into play. By making costs more predictable, Raintree is able to focus on improving processes regardless of the ultimate sell price. The system keeps the company focused on making practical advancements.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Because we have a company owned farm, we know the metrics in terms of farming that product, we know we’re going to have good controls in terms of farmers working with us. It’s not like we begin paying them and don’t show up We have extension workers go out every two weeks to make sure the product is taken care of.”<br>
-Teddy Rouge, Founder of Raintree Farms, Co-founder of <a href="http://Remit.ug">Remit.ug</a> and Hive Colab</p>
</blockquote>
<p>#<span class="hashtag">#Market</span> Demand</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“The market was already there for us, our biggest problem was that we couldn’t access enough raw materials to meet market demand. It’s been 5 years of pivoting to figure out the model and what would work, that required funding.”<br>
-Teddy Rouge, Founder of Raintree Farms, Co-founder of <a href="http://Remit.ug">Remit.ug</a> and Hive Colab</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Another core problem for Raintree Farms is adapting to meet market demand. As Teddy explains above, it took outside funding to give him the flexibility to try many different models and figure out which one addressed this problem the best.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Customers are coming to me with requests for many tons, but i don’t have the raw materials to make even half a ton. So it becomes about relationships, we say it will take X time to produce it, will you pay 50% down so we can continue operations? If you have enough of a relationship with that customer then you win them over and self fund to get those materials.”<br>
-Teddy Rouge, Founder of Raintree Farms, Co-founder of <a href="http://Remit.ug">Remit.ug</a> and Hive Colab</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Ultimately, Teddy found that pre-payments solved this problem. For more information on how he built the trust necessary to make that model work, check out our <a href="//community.source.institute/t/getting-paid-upfront/107">lesson on prepayments</a>.</p>
<p>#<span class="hashtag">#Looking</span> Toward the Future of the Business</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“We see potential in that changing their lives and making the company more profitable. We’re not beholden to falling or rising market prices because we get the crops at the same price so it’s up to us to input efficiencies into the system to stay profitable.”<br>
-Teddy Rouge, Founder of Raintree Farms, Co-founder of <a href="http://Remit.ug">Remit.ug</a> and Hive Colab</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Ultimately, Teddy is optimistic about the future of Raintree Farms because he sees the company’s incentives pointing it in the right direction. Beyond that, he’s scaling and expanding his business with care to make sure it has what it needs to succeed. So far, that’s worked very well for them.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“You have to be willing to watch your business model evolve, you have to pivot your business model towards that. If you have too many farmers coming, it can crush your business. There may be 1000 farmers who want to come work with you, but you might not be equipped ot handle them.”<br>
-Teddy Rouge, Founder of Raintree Farms, Co-founder of <a href="http://Remit.ug">Remit.ug</a> and Hive Colab</p>
</blockquote>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 1</p>
            <p>Participants: 1</p>
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/t/the-raintree-farm-story/1639">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://community.source.institute/t/the-raintree-farm-story/1639</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 14:36:07 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">community.source.institute-topic-1639</guid>
          <source url="https://community.source.institute/t/the-raintree-farm-story/1639.rss">The Raintree Farm Story</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>How You Can Lobby Governments</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@ehalsey1 Eric Halsey]]></dc:creator>
          <category>The Sources</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/u/ehalsey1">@ehalsey1</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p>In the last lesson, we looked at how Teddy Ruge deals with regulations in Uganda and the wider East African region. Key to his long-term goals in dealing with regulation better is developing effective lobbying strategies.</p>
<p>#<span class="hashtag">#What</span> Is Lobbying?</p>
<p>Lobbying, put simply, is when private companies or individuals try to influence governments. That could mean working with regulation agencies to help them understand how to best enforce their regulations or it could mean building a relationship with a politician to influence their votes.</p>
<p>#<span class="hashtag">#How</span> Can You Lobby?</p>
<p>If you think you or your company are too small to be able to do this, remember that lobbying is often done by organizations which represent large groups of people or companies. So participating in lobbying for your own interests can also happen by finding the right organization to represent you.</p>
<p>For Teddy, that organization is the <a href="http://afrilabs.com">Afrilabs Network</a>.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Hive colab is a part of the Afrilabs Network, something like this would be a great chance for us to take this on and influence regultory decision making across the continent.”<br>
-Teddy Rouge, Founder of Raintree Farms, Co-founder of <a href="http://Remit.ug">Remit.ug</a> and Hive Colab</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Understanding that technology labs and co-working spaces want many of the same things from their governments, Hive Colab uses this organization to press for smarter regulations on its industry.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“The immediete body is the EAC (East African Community), as you’re building this economic region can you bring down those barriers. It’s starting to happen, Safaricom and MTM have cross border agreements for remittances.”<br>
-Teddy Rouge, Founder of Raintree Farms, Co-founder of <a href="http://Remit.ug">Remit.ug</a> and Hive Colab</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The question then is who to lobby? You can lobby a local government, a national government, or a supranational organization. For Teddy, the most efficient method is to go straight to the top and lobby the EAC. But ask yourself and any organization you want to lobby through where you think your efforts can have the greatest impact.</p>
<p>#<span class="hashtag">#The</span> Importance of Lobbying</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“In order for our economies to scale I need to do business with a Nigerian, to Côte d’Ivoire. Right now, I can’t acquire those customers because Orange Uganda is a different company than Orange Kenya. Those digital roadblocks need to come down. As hub founders, we need to come together and build a collective voice influencing and saying these are the numbers which say we need to move in this direction.”<br>
-Teddy Rouge, Founder of Raintree Farms, Co-founder of <a href="http://Remit.ug">Remit.ug</a> and Hive Colab</p>
</blockquote>
<p>But why lobby at all? Teddy explains it clearly here. Good regulations are essential for his businesses to grow. He can’t simply sit around and hope that governments around Africa will make the right decisions for his businesses. For Teddy, getting involved in lobbying is the right business move, as well as a way for him to make Africa better.</p>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 1</p>
            <p>Participants: 1</p>
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/t/how-you-can-lobby-governments/1637">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://community.source.institute/t/how-you-can-lobby-governments/1637</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 11:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">community.source.institute-topic-1637</guid>
          <source url="https://community.source.institute/t/how-you-can-lobby-governments/1637.rss">How You Can Lobby Governments</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Handling Regulation</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@ehalsey1 Eric Halsey]]></dc:creator>
          <category>The Sources</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/u/ehalsey1">@ehalsey1</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p>It doesn’t get talked about enough, but every African startup has to deal with regulations just as much, if not more, than their foreign counterparts. Teddy Ruge has developed a set of perspectives, tactics, and goals for how to deal with African regulations. Here’s what he told us.</p>
<p>#<span class="hashtag">#The</span> Right Mindset</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“You build that into your business plan, it’s simply a cost of doing business on the continent. Anyone having to do business here shouldn’t balk at regulation compliance being a line item.”<br>
-Teddy Rouge, Founder of Raintree Farms, Co-founder of <a href="http://Remit.ug">Remit.ug</a> and Hive Colab</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The first bit of advice here from Teddy is to anticipate regulation. You’re not going to get around it and it’s always going to cost money to comply. So make sure you’re ready for that reality from day 1. If someone isn’t ready to take the time to deal with regulation, they’re probably not ready to do business.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“If you’re planning on growth you have to plan to deal with 53-54 different regulatory entities.”<br>
-Teddy Rouge, Founder of Raintree Farms, Co-founder of <a href="http://Remit.ug">Remit.ug</a> and Hive Colab</p>
</blockquote>
<p>That advice gets multiplied when it comes to growth. So just as you have to be prepared for regulation in the country where you get started, you’ve got to build it into your business plan when you expand. Still, Teddy also reminds us that in the most cutting edge industries, you might still be waiting for regulations to catch up.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“We’re stitting on 100 year old western regulations. It took that to leapfrog all that old reguation for them to say oh this is something new. Sometimes it’s one of those things where you do the business and wait until the regulation catches up.”<br>
-Teddy Rouge, Founder of Raintree Farms, Co-founder of <a href="http://Remit.ug">Remit.ug</a> and Hive Colab</p>
</blockquote>
<p>But whatever the case, once you’ve accepted the reality of regulations, you’ve got to develop the right tactics to deal with them.</p>
<p>#<span class="hashtag">#The</span> Right Tactics</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“It’s very much operate until someone says no. Just go in there and plead ignorance at the end. You have to be scrappy as an Africa startup.”<br>
-Teddy Rouge, Founder of Raintree Farms, Co-founder of <a href="http://Remit.ug">Remit.ug</a> and Hive Colab</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Teddy’s tactic of pleading ignorance may not work in all cases, but the most important bit of advice there is to be scrappy. If you’re a small startup, you may be able to get away with some things a larger company can’t. But be creative.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“[Those regulations] limit growth a bit if you’re not well funded. Our way of doing that is fighting one small battle at a time and thinking of ways the EAC (East African Community) unifies faster before we have to deal with 5 entities with our growth potential. Then we have to open 5 offices in each country, which is costly and prohibitive.”<br>
-Teddy Rouge, Founder of Raintree Farms, Co-founder of <a href="http://Remit.ug">Remit.ug</a> and Hive Colab</p>
</blockquote>
<p>For Teddy, based in Uganda, working with the EAC directly is a great tactic to avoid the hurdles of dealing with countries individually. So, you can also ask yourself whether your startup can potentially work with a larger regulator to skip the process of dealing with every single bureaucrat in the organization individually.</p>
<p>#<span class="hashtag">#The</span> Right Goals<br>
Besides simply dealing with regulations as they are, Teddy also looks forward to how he can influence them. Doing that requires lobbying, which will be the topic of the next lesson.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“You have a business model you want to expand, all other companies have to do the same thing, you can’t kill a business idea because you’re afraid of regulatory cost. You can also out some of that cost into lobbying for a better regulatory environment. We at hive colab want to get to a point where we influence regulation in the region.”<br>
-Teddy Rouge, Founder of Raintree Farms, Co-founder of <a href="http://Remit.ug">Remit.ug</a> and Hive Colab</p>
</blockquote>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 1</p>
            <p>Participants: 1</p>
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/t/handling-regulation/1636">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://community.source.institute/t/handling-regulation/1636</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 11:11:06 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">community.source.institute-topic-1636</guid>
          <source url="https://community.source.institute/t/handling-regulation/1636.rss">Handling Regulation</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Should You Complain More?</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@ehalsey1 Eric Halsey]]></dc:creator>
          <category>The Sources</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/u/ehalsey1">@ehalsey1</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <blockquote>
<p>“In Africa, w’re used to a ‘it’s good enough’ culture, we accept bullshit more than anyone else. We don’t complain enough.”<br>
-Teddy Rouge, Founder of Raintree Farms, Co-founder of <a href="http://Remit.ug">Remit.ug</a> and Hive Colab</p>
</blockquote>
<p>In talking with so many African entrepreneurs, this statement by Ugandan Teddy Ruge really stood out. It’s not a problem we heard about from anyone else, but Teddy’s thoughts on it are persuasive. So, it’s time you asked yourself “Should I complain more?”</p>
<p>##“It’s Good Enough” Culture</p>
<p>In this criticism, Teddy points out that the culture of accepting things as they are really hurts the ability of African businesses to adapt and compete with foreign businesses. Though, it has to be pointed out, this is different from insisting everything be perfect. Modern startup ideas like minimum viable products are still important. The difference is insisting that quality always improve instead of accepting it where it is.</p>
<p>#<span class="hashtag">#Asking</span> for Permission</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“People are not self starters, they always want permission. You have to create spaces where discussions can be had to break that mentality and not ask for permission. Go from ‘may I do this?’ to ‘I’m going to do this’”<br>
-Teddy Rouge, Founder of Raintree Farms, Co-founder of <a href="http://Remit.ug">Remit.ug</a> and Hive Colab</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Ironically, while Teddy is talking about Ugandans in this example, it applies to many workers around the world. Creating spaces where employees feel they can take the initiative is an element of success in many of the businesses we’ve talked to. It’s also one of the ideas of the Hive co-working space in Kampala which Teddy helped to create. Spaces like this allow workers to develop their own culture.</p>
<p>#<span class="hashtag">#Sharing</span> Success</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Share your successes with others, share what you’ve done and inspire people. That is done through storytelling of our successes and failures. We don’t talk enough about our failures because we’re afraid of being laughed at. If you’re truly tenacious about your vision, you’ll pivot out of that failure and make something better.”<br>
-Teddy Rouge, Founder of Raintree Farms, Co-founder of <a href="http://Remit.ug">Remit.ug</a> and Hive Colab</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Tied in with all of the cultural elements mentioned above is the idea of not being ashamed of your failures. In fact, you’ll notice that many of the lessons we’ve produced mention where African entrepreneurs have failed. Because those failures can teach something to you and those around you. For Teddy it comes down to seeing those failures in context and making sure you draw the right lessons from them to do things better next time.</p>
<p>Combined, Teddy’s advice for his fellow African entrepreneurs is to complain more, don’t ask for permission, and proudly share both your success and failure.</p>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 1</p>
            <p>Participants: 1</p>
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/t/should-you-complain-more/1626">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://community.source.institute/t/should-you-complain-more/1626</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2017 14:09:35 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">community.source.institute-topic-1626</guid>
          <source url="https://community.source.institute/t/should-you-complain-more/1626.rss">Should You Complain More?</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Solving Local Problems or Going Big?</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@ehalsey1 Eric Halsey]]></dc:creator>
          <category>The Sources</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/u/ehalsey1">@ehalsey1</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <blockquote>
<p>“Most of the developers in Uganda and solving Ugandan problems, not realizing there’s something bigger.”<br>
-Teddy Rouge, Founder of Raintree Farms, Co-founder of <a href="http://Remit.ug">Remit.ug</a> and Hive Colab</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Ugandan entrepreneur Teddy Ruge has faced some central questions in building his three main businesses. Among them is whether he should narrow down, focus on solving local problems and delivering his product in a smaller but impactful market, or whether he should go big and aim at delivering something to a wider customer base.</p>
<p>#<span class="hashtag">#The</span> Advantages of Going Local</p>
<p>We’ve heard many African entrepreneurs talk about the importance of understanding your customers and building trust among them. This is one advantage of going local. In a smaller market, it’s easier to get to know your customers and build trust. For Teddy, this applied to both Raintree Farms and <a href="http://Remit.ug">Remit.ug</a>.</p>
<p>With both businesses, Teddy needed to build trust with local farmers in the case of Raintree, and with the diaspora and local Ugandans receiving money in the case of <a href="http://Remit.ug">Remit.ug</a>. Focusing on Uganda helped him establish both of these businesses. There’s a possibility of expansion, but that would never have been possible if the businesses had failed to build trust amongst their initial customer base.</p>
<p>#<span class="hashtag">#The</span> Advantages of Going Big</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Where are you deploying it, what’s you addressable market, when can you get it out, are you thinking about 37 million in Uganda or 150 million in East Africa?”<br>
-Teddy Rouge, Founder of Raintree Farms, Co-founder of <a href="http://Remit.ug">Remit.ug</a> and Hive Colab</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Just because Teddy initially focused on local markets for his three businesses doesn’t mean he thinks that’s always the right choice. Instead, he focuses on the importance of asking the right questions.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Are you thinking about the regulatory hurdles required for expansion, when can you handle them? Then before that, how are you going to grow and sell to a funder who wants to know about scaling. He’s looking for 100 million for scaling and sees that you can’t because the market is too small.”<br>
-Teddy Rouge, Founder of Raintree Farms, Co-founder of <a href="http://Remit.ug">Remit.ug</a> and Hive Colab</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The questions Teddy asks above point to the other side of going local: you can limit yourself. The difference here is between your market and your addressable market. <a href="http://Remit.ug">Remit.ug</a>, for example, started by establishing itself in Uganda. However, its addressable market includes millions in the African diaspora (as well as others potentially).</p>
<p>So for Teddy, it made sense to start local and establish himself while keeping an eye on the potential for scaling and going big in the future.</p>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 1</p>
            <p>Participants: 1</p>
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/t/solving-local-problems-or-going-big/1624">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://community.source.institute/t/solving-local-problems-or-going-big/1624</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2017 12:54:40 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">community.source.institute-topic-1624</guid>
          <source url="https://community.source.institute/t/solving-local-problems-or-going-big/1624.rss">Solving Local Problems or Going Big?</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Using Co-Working Spaces to Build Community</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@ehalsey1 Eric Halsey]]></dc:creator>
          <category>The Sources</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/u/ehalsey1">@ehalsey1</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p>In the last lesson, we looked at how Teddy Ruge used blogging to build his own reputation and a community of followers he later used to develop his businesses. Now, let’s look at one of those businesses more closely. Because Ruge and his partners have built Hive into an example of the power of a co-working space to build a community.</p>
<p>#<span class="hashtag">#Creating</span> Community</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Hive is the Ugandan ihub basically. It’s on a smaller scale because the tech sector in Uganda is less evolved. Back in 2008-2009 and when we launched in 2010, most technologists were working in University labs, cafes, or bedrooms. So there wasn’t a community. I saw we needed that, we would have tech happy hours but we didn’t really have a community place. We started with a small office but all we could provide was slow internet. But we could have events, have people begin to meet each other, put faces to online identities, etc. Then, slowly it evolved as we got money for partnerships, around 2011 we really found our footing and had a space in Kampala.”<br>
-Teddy Rouge, Founder of Raintree Farms, Co-founder of <a href="http://Remit.ug">Remit.ug</a> and Hive Colab</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Teddy could clearly see that Kampala’s tech sector had a greater potential than most people believed. His work with the diaspora community and blogging had got him thinking about the potential of a co-working space. After all, he had already seen how many Africans were skeptical of African businesses and of their own potential. What better way to get more businesses started and more knowledge shared than to create a central meeting and working point for the community?</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“You start with the three Fs. Once your money runs out, start with fools, family, and friends. In small doses you get that done. Eventually we applied of grant funding. We got better at writing grants. Eventually you end up with enough funding to keep the lights and internet on. We have a partnership to provide high speed internet there.”<br>
-Teddy Rouge, Founder of Raintree Farms, Co-founder of <a href="http://Remit.ug">Remit.ug</a> and Hive Colab</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Once Hive was started, the benefits for the community weren’t hard to see. What was difficult was finding a way to fund the space. That solution came gradually with grant funding and partnerships. But it wasn’t just luck or perseverance, Hive was started because Teddy could see that there was enough demand for it to exist.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"As other tech hubs are springing up throughout the continent, there’s the question of how we’re keeping the lights on. Each location needs to figure out how to keep the lights on. What do you pay attention to for that customization. What’s the tech adoption in your locale? Are you creating tools beyond your user base?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>So, he warns here that any co-working space has to be tailored to its own environment. Success is not guaranteed. But Hive, like ihub in Nairobi, has shown that co-working spaces in Africa have the potential to become hubs for learning, community building, and the broader creation of a successful tech sector in African cities.</p>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 1</p>
            <p>Participants: 1</p>
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/t/using-co-working-spaces-to-build-community/1621">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://community.source.institute/t/using-co-working-spaces-to-build-community/1621</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2017 15:43:58 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">community.source.institute-topic-1621</guid>
          <source url="https://community.source.institute/t/using-co-working-spaces-to-build-community/1621.rss">Using Co-Working Spaces to Build Community</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Building a Community Through Blogging</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@ehalsey1 Eric Halsey]]></dc:creator>
          <category>The Sources</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/u/ehalsey1">@ehalsey1</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p>The last lesson discussed how Teddy Ruge harnessed the power of the African diaspora to help build several businesses. A critical part of that successful strategy involved using blogging to build his own reputation and to develop that diaspora community. Here’s how he did it.</p>
<p>#<span class="hashtag">#The</span> Process</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“I blogged for about 5 years and around 2009 I started to put my boots on the ground and look into what I could get into and where I needed to be. Part of that was that I saw we were very quick to criticize but I didn’t see enough Africans getting in there. So I thought, I can’t keep criticizing that, I have to be the change I want. I wanted to be the chance I was criticizing in the industry. I wanted to convene spaces where young entrepreneurs could show the world what we could do.”<br>
-Teddy Rouge, Founder of Raintree Farms, Co-founder of <a href="http://Remit.ug">Remit.ug</a> and Hive Colab</p>
</blockquote>
<p>There’s no denying that Teddy’s success through blogging didn’t happen overnight. But the lesson he learned in those years is one you don’t necessarily need 5 years to learn: that blogging may have taught him a lot and opened many doors, but he wanted to use that experience to do more. But what got him there. The story that really convinced Teddy that he needed to be more involved involved the Million T-Shirt Contest and its creator Jason Sandler.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Apart from talking about the topics around the diaspora I also blogged a lot about development and our role in it. At the time most of the discourse around that didn’t involve Africans. The emergence of Social Media allowed us to have a role i that discussion. One of the first times I saw the emergence of African agency online was around the million t-shirt contest. Jason Sandler made a name for himself with t-shirts, so he decided to solicit used t-shirts. I saw for the first time Africans descending on him and saying “you’re exactly what’s wrong with development” That was the first time my bullshit detector kicked in. I thought it was important to insert myself into the conversation.”<br>
-Teddy Rouge, Founder of Raintree Farms, Co-founder of <a href="http://Remit.ug">Remit.ug</a> and Hive Colab</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Those frustrations gradually channeled themselves into writing more about technology and its potential in Africa. As time passed, Teddy got closer and closer to knowing where he wanted to focus his energies.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“I was basically a wandering African. I didn’t know what I wanted to contribute. That required learning about the field, meeting people. talking to people. One of the first people I followed and blogged about was Eric Hersman, way before ihub launched we were talking about the state of technology in Africa and East Africa in general. I got particularly enamored with the undersea cable. I could see how transformational that could be and it pulled me into the technology sector. As bloggers we started seeing a community build around tech, entrepreneurship, coding, and building a community and those conversations.”<br>
-Teddy Rouge, Founder of Raintree Farms, Co-founder of <a href="http://Remit.ug">Remit.ug</a> and Hive Colab</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Years of blogging, making connections, helping to start discussions around everything from international aid to building tech communities in East Africa, Teddy had created a reputation and a community of followers he could harness for his next projects. Doing this require persistence, but there’s no denying it paid off for Teddy.</p>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 1</p>
            <p>Participants: 1</p>
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/t/building-a-community-through-blogging/1620">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://community.source.institute/t/building-a-community-through-blogging/1620</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2017 14:19:48 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">community.source.institute-topic-1620</guid>
          <source url="https://community.source.institute/t/building-a-community-through-blogging/1620.rss">Building a Community Through Blogging</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Harnessing the African Diaspora</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@ehalsey1 Eric Halsey]]></dc:creator>
          <category>The Sources</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/u/ehalsey1">@ehalsey1</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <blockquote>
<p>“What I found is that even though the continent is diverse, the diaspora is just as diverse. We’re unified in the spirit of doing something for the continent.”<br>
-Teddy Rouge, Founder of Raintree Farms, Co-founder of <a href="http://Remit.ug">Remit.ug</a> and Hive Colab</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Teddy Ruge has in part built his success on harnessing the power of the African Diaspora while building businesses in Uganda. Being a member of the Ugandan diaspora himself was an advantage, but not the whole story. Here’s how he came to understand just what the diaspora could do to help him build successful businesses in Uganda.</p>
<p>#<span class="hashtag">#Understanding</span> the Diaspora</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“One of the first things I did was I figured that in order to figure out what I wanted to do I had to read about it, understand it, engage it. So I started Project diaspora. I wanted to understand the role of the diaspora in the development of the continent. I would blog about what’s interesting, remittances, government policies towards the diaspora. I wanted to know what other members of the diaspora were doing and whether it was the same around the continent.”<br>
-Teddy Rouge, Founder of Raintree Farms, Co-founder of <a href="http://Remit.ug">Remit.ug</a> and Hive Colab</p>
</blockquote>
<p>For Teddy, the way to understand the diaspora began with blogging. This allowed him to begin writing, making a name for himself within this community, and getting input from other diaspora members about their communities. This technique took several years, but ultimately it gave Ruge both deep knowledge of diaspora communities and some credibility amongst those communities. The next step for him was to do something wth this knowledge and reputation.</p>
<p>#<span class="hashtag">#Using</span> the Diaspora</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“The advantage of the diaspora is the global perspective. We know what is possible from a global perspective as opposed to the narrow perspective within the education system. Uganda is all about wrote memorization and killing creativity.”<br>
-Teddy Rouge, Founder of Raintree Farms, Co-founder of <a href="http://Remit.ug">Remit.ug</a> and Hive Colab</p>
</blockquote>
<p>One of Teddy’s first businesses in Uganda was <a href="http://Remit.ug">Remit.ug</a>. This remittance service offers better prices and service for members of the diaspora to send money back home. Starting this business required understanding that both diaspora members and their families back in Africa were his customers. As such, the knowledge he developed about both groups helped immensely.</p>
<p>Another project for Ruge was Hive Colab. This Ugandan co-working space aims at fostering a real community of entrepreneurs in Kampala. But doing this also required bringing the different perspective and skills of the diaspora to bear.</p>
<p>In both cases, understanding that both native Africans and members of the diaspora have a unique set of skills helped bring Ruge success in his projects.</p>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 1</p>
            <p>Participants: 1</p>
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/t/harnessing-the-african-diaspora/1619">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://community.source.institute/t/harnessing-the-african-diaspora/1619</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2017 13:03:18 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">community.source.institute-topic-1619</guid>
          <source url="https://community.source.institute/t/harnessing-the-african-diaspora/1619.rss">Harnessing the African Diaspora</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Ways to Fund Yourself</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@ehalsey1 Eric Halsey]]></dc:creator>
          <category>The Sources</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/u/ehalsey1">@ehalsey1</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p>Without a doubt, the number one challenge we’ve heard about from African entrepreneurs is the difficulty of getting funding. Besides techniques like getting grants, lowering your startup costs, and using free tools, there are a variety of ways to fund yourself while you get your business started.</p>
<p>Here’s how three African companies did just that.</p>
<p>#<span class="hashtag">#Getting</span> a Job</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“I had no money. I had to pay rent, eat, it was really hard. My team at that point, none of them had a job, we would always convince ourselves, slowly we began getting job, we agreed that one of us can get a job and support the rest. Since the idea was initially mine and the technology and expertise was mine we decided I stay behind and they work to support me by giving me some of their salary.”<br>
-Edward Amartey-Tagoe, Founder of Nandimobile, MEST Incubator</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Edward’s technique was to start with a team and everyone else work and use their salaries to support him while he built their product. This carried risks, it was possible that team members could argue over who was supporting the team more by either working a regular job or working on their product. But that risk was necessary to get the company started.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“I wanted to grow the company with revenue. We’re getting people to pay us for subscriptions. Our technology runs on a business model where businesses pay us monthly or annual fees to be on the platform, and for tech companies that are doing so, it’s a recurring fee that companies pay you that makes you financially successful. The most important question was whether or not we could convince enterprises to pay us recurring fees. Now we have 540 of them actually paying us that much money. As I used to say sometimes we are lucky, sometimes we work hard. We’ve built the company to a point now where we want to scale into different markets one, and we want to focus on our new platform which I could talk about.”<br>
-Edward Amartey-Tagoe, Founder of Nandimobile, MEST Incubator</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Ultimately, this team structure worked well enough for Edward to get the company earning enough revenue to bring other members of the team on full time. It was a temporary solution, but it worked for him.</p>
<p>#<span class="hashtag">#Paying</span> the Bills with a Service Model</p>
<p>Philip Walton used a hybrid model to get his business going in the early days. Edward’s model wasn’t possible for his company, so they had to get creative.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“It’s always better to use your own money and bootstrap if possible. I like doing hybrids - service business generating cashflow, helping the R&amp;D, getting a little money from mom and dad, and leveraging a service model to grow the business. Nairobi is a very difficult place to get capital, local investors don’t understand tech, they go to real estate. A lot of entrepreneurs in and around ihub can’t get access to capital so they burrow from mom and dad, bootstrap the rest. Sometimes you should ask yourself if you can do this without outside capital.”<br>
-Philip Walton, Co-founder of BRCK</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Ultimately, Philip created a service business as a part of his larger product development business. This side project was designed to bring in enough revenue to fund the long-term product development goals the business was ultimately focused on. While burrowing money from family added to this, creating a service business was what allowed him to fund his company in the early days.</p>
<p>#<span class="hashtag">#Sharing</span> Living Costs</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“What you need to keep in mind is that we aren’t on a stable salary, if we’re going to give someone an allowance, it wouldn’t be favorable, they might spend all their money on rent. It was a no brainer, living in one place would let our allowance have more value.”<br>
-Samuel Njuguna, Co-founder of Chura</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Funding yourself isn’t just about finding ways to bring in revenue during the early stage of a business. It’s also about cutting costs. Chura did this by deciding to have the entire team live together. Like with Edward’s strategy, this carried some risks if the team would argue or fight. But those risks were worth it to allow the entire team to save money by sharing rent and spend more time together developing their product.</p>
<p>#<span class="hashtag">#Finding</span> the Right Mixture for Your Business</p>
<p>The good news is that all of these tactics can be combined. These three examples show how many ways there are to fund yourself and your business. The first step is to consider how they apply to your situation.</p>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 1</p>
            <p>Participants: 1</p>
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/t/ways-to-fund-yourself/1601">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://community.source.institute/t/ways-to-fund-yourself/1601</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2017 10:28:25 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">community.source.institute-topic-1601</guid>
          <source url="https://community.source.institute/t/ways-to-fund-yourself/1601.rss">Ways to Fund Yourself</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>The Importance of Soft Skills</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@ehalsey1 Eric Halsey]]></dc:creator>
          <category>The Sources</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/u/ehalsey1">@ehalsey1</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <blockquote>
<p>”Soft skills, what? I didn’t know people actually could be coached on soft skills.”<br>
-Femi Akinde, CEO of Slimtrader</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Soft skills may be difficult to define, but Femi Akinde still realized how essential they are for his business. He came to understand that this set of skills related to emotional intelligence can and must be learned for him to succeed.</p>
<p>#<span class="hashtag">#How</span> developing soft skills led Femi to success</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“First thing is it’s hard to define soft skills. The best way to say it is how to get along. I think that’s my definition of soft skills. How to get along. I think it’s lost on most people. First of all, most people don’t know you actually can be coached, or it’s actually a discipline, or you can learn what soft skills are.”<br>
-Femi Akinde, CEO of Slimtrader</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Femi learned about soft skills as people asked him questions. Questions that made him understand the limitations of his background as an engineer. Over time, Femi came to define soft skills broadly as the ability to get along with people.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“The best way to win an argument is to get someone to make your argument for you. I didn’t know that before business school. That was a revelation to me. How do you get someone to make your argument for you? You ask questions leading up to it. You see now? There’s a lot of depth to this soft skills thing, right? It literally can be the difference between getting a deal done, or not getting a deal done.”<br>
-Femi Akinde, CEO of Slimtrader</p>
</blockquote>
<p>As an engineer, this new set of skills benefitted him a lot. According to Femi, you have to identify your weakness and find the solution to the weakness. He concludes that you do not have to acquire such knowledge from a business school and explains that he preferred acquiring knowledge in a classroom.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>”For engineer, this was good for me. You don’t necessarily have to go to business school to learn what I learned, I believe you can. You have to identify your weakness, and seek a solution to your weakness. What I did, my going to business school was I identified what I didn’t know, and I found a way to get that knowledge. I felt more comfortable getting it within the four walls of a prestigious institution. You can go into training at a major corporation and get the same knowledge, or you could read it off the web, but that was what I felt comfortable doing.”<br>
-Femi Akinde, CEO of Slimtrader</p>
</blockquote>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 1</p>
            <p>Participants: 1</p>
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/t/the-importance-of-soft-skills/1599">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://community.source.institute/t/the-importance-of-soft-skills/1599</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2017 09:51:19 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">community.source.institute-topic-1599</guid>
          <source url="https://community.source.institute/t/the-importance-of-soft-skills/1599.rss">The Importance of Soft Skills</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>The Limitations of Word of Mouth</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@ehalsey1 Eric Halsey]]></dc:creator>
          <category>The Sources</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/u/ehalsey1">@ehalsey1</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <blockquote>
<p>“The farmer was very excited, he was telling everyone and calling all the other farmers over. I was trying to keep coolm but I knew it was a breakthrough.”<br>
-Werner Swart, Founder of Drylo Bag, Africa Prize shortlist</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Talking with African entrepreneurs, you hear some stories that might make you believe that word of mouth is an amazing tool to solve almost any problem. However, others will tell you that you have to be careful and not rely on it too much. These three stories show both the potential and limitation of word of mouth advertising.</p>
<p>#<span class="hashtag">#The</span> Potential</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“We started with the international fair. We get small scale farmers coming and that’s where the numbers really picked up, 2K passed through our stand and word of mouth has really picked up. People meet us on the street and want to know where to get one.”<br>
-Musenga Siliwawa, Founder of Spot Agro</p>
</blockquote>
<p>For Musenga, and Werner, word of mouth was critical in their success. Both of them were able to begin by working with farmers and rely on the power of close knit communities of farmers to then spread the word about their products.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“The thing is with farmers, they’re copycats if I can say that. If one is succeeding with something, the others will follow. Once they’ve seen it work and they’ve seen the results, I’ve had people contact me from other provinces back in South Africa and it just started growing.”<br>
-Werner Swart, Founder of Drylo Bag, Africa Prize shortlist</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This was possible because the farmers in question understand that they all have similar challenges. So if they see another farmer finding success with a product, they’re ready to give it a try. This, however, is not always how other types of consumers work, as Felix Kimaru learned.</p>
<p>#<span class="hashtag">#The</span> Limitations</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Word of mouth is not enough. If you’re able to show how much this is going to improve the lives of their people, it’s a difficult sell but you have to start”<br>
-Felix Kimaru, Co-founder of Totohealth, Africa Prize shortlist</p>
</blockquote>
<p>When developing his health services product Totohealth, Felix initially thought word of mouth would be a more powerful tool. After all, his company was going to be making it far easier for rural East Africans to gain access to healthcare services and information. But those villages didn’t have strong connections with other villages dozens or hundreds of kilometers away.</p>
<p>The community connections between those rural people weren’t as strong as between the farmers that Werner and Musenga were selling to. That made the critical difference between finding success using word of mouth and not.</p>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 1</p>
            <p>Participants: 1</p>
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/t/the-limitations-of-word-of-mouth/1587">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://community.source.institute/t/the-limitations-of-word-of-mouth/1587</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 10:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">community.source.institute-topic-1587</guid>
          <source url="https://community.source.institute/t/the-limitations-of-word-of-mouth/1587.rss">The Limitations of Word of Mouth</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Mastering Technology Adoption</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@ehalsey1 Eric Halsey]]></dc:creator>
          <category>The Sources</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/u/ehalsey1">@ehalsey1</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p>#<span class="hashtag">#Market</span> considerations</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“The small farmers will wait, but the higher income ones will invest in new technology”<br>
-Musenga Siliwawa, Founder of Spot Agro</p>
</blockquote>
<p>In his effort to make Zambian farmers adopt his new technology, Musenga was quick to note that each class of farmers had a different buying pattern and required a different approach. The large, high income farmers were fast to adopt his fertilizer applicator citing their urge for time efficient and labor cutting cost innovations, whereas smaller, low income farmers were initially reluctant to experiment with his product.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Those above 10 have more issues with time, labor; they’re looking for the latest tech”<br>
-Musenga Siliwawa, Founder of Spot Agro</p>
</blockquote>
<p>He therefore came with a plan that accommodated the small scale farmers, who were a far larger market. He targeted to sell them his product after a season or two, to allow them ample time to budget for it and evaluate the efficiency of the applicator so as to gain confidence on it. This way, he was able to sell his applicator to many small scale farmers. It just took time and patience.</p>
<p>#<span class="hashtag">#Challenges</span> of a new technology</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“You’re initially driven by enthusiasm, but then market realities sink in. You’re creating something great but your market is maybe 100K smart phones”</p>
</blockquote>
<ul>
<li>Teddy Ruge, Founder of Raintree Farms, Co-founder of <a href="http://Remit.ug">Remit.ug</a> and Hive Colab</li>
</ul>
<p>Just like Musenga, Ruge also first found it difficult to convince the mass to adopt his new remittance service. First, he had to make sure the market was there. He understood that having a great product doesn’t mean very much if most of your consumers don’t have the technology you need to use it. This thinking kept his product development realistic and tailored to his customers.</p>
<p>So in both cases, the answer wasn’t to go out and force consumers to adopt the technologies Ruge and Siliwawa needed for their companies to thrive. Both took things slow, both waiting for the customers to be ready and slowly priming them when possible. This showed that building a company in Africa based on new technologies is possible with the right strategy.</p>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 1</p>
            <p>Participants: 1</p>
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/t/mastering-technology-adoption/1586">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://community.source.institute/t/mastering-technology-adoption/1586</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 10:05:19 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">community.source.institute-topic-1586</guid>
          <source url="https://community.source.institute/t/mastering-technology-adoption/1586.rss">Mastering Technology Adoption</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Living as and Learning about Your Customer</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@ehalsey1 Eric Halsey]]></dc:creator>
          <category>The Sources</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/u/ehalsey1">@ehalsey1</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <blockquote>
<p>“The first tip was being the users ourselves. we still have our farms.”<br>
-Brian Bett, Co-founder of Illuminum Greenhouses</p>
</blockquote>
<p><a href="//community.source.institute/t/understanding-b2b-customer-needs-request/1534">Our last lesson</a> touched on how to understand B2C (business to consumer) relationships. Here, two entrepreneurs expand on those experiences and how they address the challenges of understanding their customers.</p>
<p>#<span class="hashtag">#Living</span> As Your Customer</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“One major problem was that after sale services were really poor, a company was offering one agronomist officer for 200 farmers. They see that agronomist once every 3 months and their crops were failing. We sought to build our numbers as we built our staff. We constantly have a ratio we want to maintain, 20 farmers per agronomist, this enables great service, improved interaction, and more importantly, the farmer saves on transport costs.”<br>
-Brian Bett, Co-founder of Illuminum Greenhouses</p>
</blockquote>
<p>As mentioned above, one advantage of Bett and his co-founders was that they were their own customers. They used greenhouses on their farms. This allowed them to identify the areas where other greenhouses suppliers were failing to meet customer needs.</p>
<p>Bett and his co-founders built their company on this knowledge. This level of customer understanding helped him craft his company’s Unique Value Proposition (UVP), that thing he and his company were best at. But it also helped him in marketing and selling his product.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“You tell him what he produces will be better and where the risk is. Since you’ve done it yourself he is comfortable.”<br>
-Brian Bett, Co-founder of Illuminum Greenhouses</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Similarly to Felix Kimaru, Bett spoke the language of his customers, allowing him to quickly build trust and sell more efficiently. Of course, it’s not always possible to do this by being an example of your own customer, so how do outsiders do it?</p>
<p>#<span class="hashtag">#Learning</span> About Your Customer</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“By asking them how much they spend in money, we found out they’re very very aware of it, which is quite different to someone from the Western world. I can’t even tell you what my utility bill was last month, but they know, because it’s one of their 3 major expenses.”<br>
-Matt Wainwright, Co-founder of Standard Microgrid, Africa Prize shortlist</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The simply answer is that you ask. That’s what Matt Wainwright and his co-founders did. They spent lots of time in rural villages to really understand their customers’ needs, financial constraints, and desires.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“People in rural Africa have money, but it’s often quite erratic They have no access to credit, so if you want them to spend more than their monthly budget for energy, you start having a very un-viable product. The way you’ve got to price your product, whatever it is, has got to be within the monthly energy budget. That’s one of your key constraints.”<br>
-Matt Wainwright, Co-founder of Standard Microgrid, Africa Prize shortlist</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This knowledge allowed them to craft their product to their customers. As a result, they avoided the mistake of building something that was too expensive and didn’t address the unique needs of rural people. Instead, Standard Microgrid’s solar grids are finding tremendous success making electricity more available than ever before.</p>
<p>Similarly, Illuminum Greenhouses is expanding quickly in Kenya and helping more farmers than ever develop efficient greenhouse-based agriculture. Living as and learning about their customers was key to this success.</p>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 1</p>
            <p>Participants: 1</p>
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/t/living-as-and-learning-about-your-customer/1585">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://community.source.institute/t/living-as-and-learning-about-your-customer/1585</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 09:17:39 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">community.source.institute-topic-1585</guid>
          <source url="https://community.source.institute/t/living-as-and-learning-about-your-customer/1585.rss">Living as and Learning about Your Customer</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Understanding B2C Customers</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@ehalsey1 Eric Halsey]]></dc:creator>
          <category>The Sources</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/u/ehalsey1">@ehalsey1</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p>Everything from marketing to building great products and customer loyalty come down to understanding your customers. That’s what Werner Swart, Felix Kimaru, and Philip Walton all learned when selling their products to consumers. Their B2C (business to consumer) businesses succeeded by following several key principles:</p>
<p>#<span class="hashtag">#Understanding</span> Who Your Client Is</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“The imortant thing is to really see who your client is. Is it the farmer, coop, or government who’s gonna buy it? Once you know that you think how to reach him”<br>
-Werner Swart, Founder of Drylo Bag, Africa Prize shortlist</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Werner founded his business on this question: who is my client? That may sound obvious, but he had to decide whether his client was going to be farmers, cooperatives, or governments. Once he answered this question he had to decide how to reach that particular type of client and sell them on his product.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Once you know that you must ask how you reach him, how does he know about my product, what is the advantage my product brings to him?”<br>
-Werner Swart, Founder of Drylo Bag, Africa Prize shortlist</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Ultimately, Werner determined that he actually had two different clients for his business: farmers and governments. The reason was that some areas had wealthy farmers who could buy his product directly while other farmers were poorer and could only buy it through local government run programs.</p>
<p>So Werner developed two different marketing and customer acquisition strategies based on these two different types of customers. Understanding who these customers were allowed him to successfully target and sell to each of them.</p>
<p>#<span class="hashtag">#Speaking</span> Their Language</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“the only way we’ve managed to work with the counties is speaking their language, understanding their needs.”<br>
-Felix Kimaru, Co-founder of Totohealth, Africa Prize shortlist</p>
</blockquote>
<p>But selling to customers is about more than just knowing who they are. Felix Kimaru found that he really needed to speak their language. Not literally, but in the sense that his pitch to potential customers needed to focus on their unique needs.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“This is a very innovative product, it raises eyebrows, counties don’t want ot hear about innovations, they want to know it has been tested and works, so we don’t speak to them about innovation… We speak to them about their problems and how we will solve them. For example, Kenya did not achieve their Millennium Development Goals (MGDs), we went to them about how they can achieve them”<br>
-Felix Kimaru, Co-founder of Totohealth, Africa Prize shortlist</p>
</blockquote>
<p>When trying to sell his product to counties in Kenya, Felix realized that talking about innovation didn’t work. Instead, he focused on explaining how his product could help counties achieve their MDGs. Speaking in the language of development goals instead of the language of innovation helped Felix connect with his customers and sell his product.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Think about the end user, what problems are they facing, speak about that.”<br>
-Felix Kimaru, Co-founder of Totohealth, Africa Prize shortlist</p>
</blockquote>
<p>#<span class="hashtag">#Getting</span> Out of The Office</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“A lot of the learning has been a continual process of getting surprised like oh I wouldn’t have thought of it from that perspective and putting ourselves in the shoes of our users.”<br>
-Philip Walton, Co-founder of BRCK</p>
</blockquote>
<p>But how do you connect with your customers? One way to do this is to spend time with them in their own environments. This is what Philip and his company BRCK did. They lived in Nairobi but were selling mostly to rural villages. So the lessons they learned testing their product in Nairobi didn’t apply.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“The more we moved out the more we learned about how users would interact wituh the system.”<br>
-Philip Walton, Co-founder of BRCK</p>
</blockquote>
<p>By spending time with their customers in their own villages, Philip and his team learned about how users interacted with their product and what caused it to fail. This allowed them to improve the product and turn it into a success.</p>
<p>Ultimately, all three of these examples come down to a process: understand who your customer is and then learn everything you can about them. For these three African entrepreneurs, that was the path to success.</p>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 1</p>
            <p>Participants: 1</p>
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/t/understanding-b2c-customers/1580">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://community.source.institute/t/understanding-b2c-customers/1580</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 15:28:38 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">community.source.institute-topic-1580</guid>
          <source url="https://community.source.institute/t/understanding-b2c-customers/1580.rss">Understanding B2C Customers</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Using Tradeshows to Market a Product</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@ehalsey1 Eric Halsey]]></dc:creator>
          <category>The Sources</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/u/ehalsey1">@ehalsey1</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p><span class="hashtag">#Using</span> Tradeshows to Market a product</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“He just tooked it and said ‘how much?’ If you need more money come and see me” -Musenga Siliwawa, Founder of Spot Agro</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Musenga’s attempts to market his advanced fertilizer applicator weren’t met with initial success. Marketing to Zambian farmers with most traditional methods wasn’t effective. Using a tradeshow to exhibit his new product and at the same time allow potential customers to experiment with it was the prudent decision that vastly improved his marketing. Farmers were happy to see the practicality of the apparatus and weighed on its advantages compared to the existing methods used.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“We took advantage of farmer exports; we have the farmers’ export which is an international trade center for farm tech in central Zambia”- Musenga Siliwawa - Founder of Spot Agro<br>
#<span class="hashtag">#Personal</span> Interaction<br>
Because tradeshows attract many members from the public with a core aim of learning about new products, Musenga decided this would be an excellent place to educate farmers about his device. Farmers could interact with and ask him questions, creating confidence in his company and product.<br>
“We were at the farmers export store, he tried it out, thought it was unbelievable, each time they apply the fertilizer there’s some question, some problems, they do it themselves.”<br>
-Musenga Siliwawa, Founder of Spot Agro<br>
#<span class="hashtag">#Getting</span> Attention<br>
Other than demonstrating the use and performance of his new product, tradeshows also enabled Musenga to catch the attention of the media. He was able to reach out to the public throughout Zambia, attracting even more interest from potential buyers. Musenga’s fertilizer applicator took off after exposure and demonstration in the tradeshow. He not only found many new customers, but developed government interest to use it in improving production amongst farmers.<br>
“The government and ministry of agriculture they have a subsidy program for fertilizer, so they came and wanted to improve efficiency. They took maybe 5K units”<br>
-Musenga Siliwawa, Founder of Spot Agro<br>
#<span class="hashtag">#The</span> Benefits of Practical Demonstrations<br>
But a tradeshow could not have been effective without demonstrating to the audience how the new product worked. It is the knowhow of the operational procedures and the ease of use that probably impacted new customers to adopt the new technology. Musenga found that farmers were very practical and wanted to see the product demonstrated to overcome their skepticism.<br>
“Let farmers try the implements out - they like tangible things. If you just explain it they will be skeptical”<br>
-Musenga Siliwawa, Founder of Spot Agro</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Once the product became popular through Musenga’s tradeshow demonstrations, it became easier to organize more groups of farmers and reach them out at their areas where similar tradeshows were done. As a result of this strategy, Musenga’s fertilizer applicator has found tremendous success in Zambia.</p>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 1</p>
            <p>Participants: 1</p>
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/t/using-tradeshows-to-market-a-product/1577">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://community.source.institute/t/using-tradeshows-to-market-a-product/1577</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 13:10:28 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">community.source.institute-topic-1577</guid>
          <source url="https://community.source.institute/t/using-tradeshows-to-market-a-product/1577.rss">Using Tradeshows to Market a Product</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Delivering Great Customer Service</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@ehalsey1 Eric Halsey]]></dc:creator>
          <category>The Sources</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/u/ehalsey1">@ehalsey1</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p><span class="hashtag">#Good</span> customer service is managed by the numbers<br>
The co-founders of Chura and Teddy Ruge all learned that great customer service is much more than a buzzword. It comes down to very specific techniques. Getting these techniques right was critical for each of them to build a loyal customer base and grow their businesses. Here’s what they did to accomplish that.<br>
#<span class="hashtag">#Customer</span> response time<br>
The first thing they focused on was response time. This refers to the time it takes to respond to customer inquiries or comments. Response rate determines whether your customers will use your services or may quickly lose confidence in you and use other services where they are being responded according to the questions they ask in the shortest time possible. For this reason, Ruge and the Chura team both focused on making sure all customer communications were responded to very quickly, especially if a customer had a bad experience. This often helped transform skeptical or upset customers into powerful brand ambassadors.<br>
#<span class="hashtag">#Service</span> quality<br>
But those responses can’t just be quick, they also have to be quality responses. For instance, in Chura, the focus is on making sure every customer is ultimately satisfied.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“I would say the surest way to retain a customer is offering satisfactory services, that means offering a very efficient service, being there when the customer wants to reach out to you.”<br>
-Samuel Njuguna, Founder Chura</p>
</blockquote>
<p>With these practices, customer satisfaction and confidence increases because through their transactions, they witness efficiency without any delays. The customer is made to feel that the Chura is made of human being who care about their experience. This has helped them build customer loyalty.<br>
#<span class="hashtag">#Customer</span> representation ratio<br>
Another issue that is very important when handling customers is the customer representation ratio. Not having enough employees to handle your customers makes maintaining quality and response time impossible. So Chura ensures that it always has enough customer representatives to handle the workload and maintain good response times and quality.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Another key indicator for trust are social media targets, if people aren’t sure if you’re trustworthy they check you out on Twitter to see if you’re trustworthy, also on Facebook, so we update our social media channels often.”<br>
-Samuel Njuguna, Founder Chura<br>
#<span class="hashtag">#Conclusion</span><br>
“The first instance is to think of you as a crook, you have to deliver the product non-stop. You have 0 room for failure. The first few years it’s all about delivery delivery delivery. If you fail in customer service, overcompensate to make sure you sell that customer. You have to sell that customer on your service. Nothing will sell your customer better than that customer selling your product for you.”<br>
Teddy - Teddy Ruge, Founder of Raintree Farms, Co-founder of <a href="http://Remit.ug">Remit.ug</a> and Hive  Colab</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Teddy always found that potential customers were very skeptical of him, a problem we hear about a lot from African entrepreneurs. The only way he found to combat that is to relentlessly deliver on quality and customer care. It’s a similar story with Chura. By making sure their customers are treated well and satisfied, all of these entrepreneurs have grown loyal customer bases and successful businesses.</p>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 1</p>
            <p>Participants: 1</p>
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/t/delivering-great-customer-service/1574">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://community.source.institute/t/delivering-great-customer-service/1574</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 16:18:58 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">community.source.institute-topic-1574</guid>
          <source url="https://community.source.institute/t/delivering-great-customer-service/1574.rss">Delivering Great Customer Service</source>
        </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
