<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Why For-Profit Education Fails</title>
    <link>https://community.source.institute/t/why-for-profit-education-fails/1000</link>
    <description>We&#39;re all passionate about P2P education as well as how to build revenue streams into it. I stumbled on this article the other day and thought there were some real lessons to learn within it.

The main lesson is that large scale enterprises promising to &quot;change education&quot; fail. They fail pretty much every time and they fail hard. But the real lesson there is what succeeds. Smaller niche products which seek incremental advancements within the existing education sphere fare far better. They know their audience, they know what their KPIs are, they identify their revenue streams earlier and more clearly.

In my mind these lessons reinforce the principle behind The Sources. We&#39;re not out to change P2P or entrepreneurship education, we&#39;re out to build a great product serving a specific audience in a better way. If we can succeed there, we can ask ourselves what we can do next with that information.

So in summary, this confirms a lot of our strategy, but is still absolutely worth a read for @salim 

http://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2016/11/why-for-profit-education-fails/501140/</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2016 05:59:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Community</category>
    <atom:link href="https://community.source.institute/t/why-for-profit-education-fails/1000.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Why For-Profit Education Fails</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@ehalsey1 Eric Halsey]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/u/ehalsey1">@ehalsey1</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>We’re all passionate about P2P education as well as how to build revenue streams into it. I stumbled on this article the other day and thought there were some real lessons to learn within it.</p>
<p>The main lesson is that large scale enterprises promising to “change education” fail. They fail pretty much every time and they fail hard. But the real lesson there is what succeeds. Smaller niche products which seek incremental advancements within the existing education sphere fare far better. They know their audience, they know what their KPIs are, they identify their revenue streams earlier and more clearly.</p>
<p>In my mind these lessons reinforce the principle behind The Sources. We’re not out to change P2P or entrepreneurship education, we’re out to build a great product serving a specific audience in a better way. If we can succeed there, we can ask ourselves what we can do next with that information.</p>
<p>So in summary, this confirms a lot of our strategy, but is still absolutely worth a read for <a class="mention" href="/u/salim">@salim</a></p>
<aside class="onebox whitelistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <img src="https://cdn.theatlantic.com/assets/static/b/theatlantic/common/img/favicon.ico" class="site-icon" width="16" height="16">
      <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2016/11/why-for-profit-education-fails/501140/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">The Atlantic</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <div class="aspect-image" style="--aspect-ratio:690/359;"><img src="https://cdn.theatlantic.com/assets/media/img/2016/09/DIS_Knee_BizEducation-2/facebook.jpg?1474988228" class="thumbnail"></div>

<h3><a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2016/11/why-for-profit-education-fails/501140/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Why For-Profit Education Fails</a></h3>

<p>Moguls’ good intentions too often betray them.</p>


  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/t/why-for-profit-education-fails/1000/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://community.source.institute/t/why-for-profit-education-fails/1000/1</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2016 12:23:55 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.source.institute-post-1000-1</guid>
        <source url="https://community.source.institute/t/why-for-profit-education-fails/1000.rss">Why For-Profit Education Fails</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
