<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Communities mature in waves</title>
    <link>https://community.source.institute/t/communities-mature-in-waves/2951</link>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;The movement around the Lean Startup methodology began with startup founders only.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://peerlearning.is/tag/leancamp&quot;&gt;Leancamp&lt;/a&gt; talks in London were always about practical lessons learned, shared to help other founders.  Andy Young (then founder of a startup called GroupSpaces, now Growth Marketing at Facebook) explained how he learned SQL, a database query language, so that he could build his own analytics dashboard to manage his business. Andreas Klinger (then founder of a fashion startup, now CTO of Product Hunt) gathered everything he could find on &quot;Startup Metrics&quot; and invested a few days to turn it into a slide presentation he shared for free - for the benefit of all founders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;small&gt;This is a companion discussion topic for the original entry at &lt;a href=&quot;https://peerlearning.is/waves/&quot;&gt;https://peerlearning.is/waves/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 13:14:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Community</category>
    <atom:link href="https://community.source.institute/t/communities-mature-in-waves/2951.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Communities mature in waves</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@forum]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/u/forum">@forum</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>The movement around the Lean Startup methodology began with startup founders only.</p>
<p><a href="http://peerlearning.is/tag/leancamp">Leancamp</a> talks in London were always about practical lessons learned, shared to help other founders.  Andy Young (then founder of a startup called GroupSpaces, now Growth Marketing at Facebook) explained how he learned SQL, a database query language, so that he could build his own analytics dashboard to manage his business. Andreas Klinger (then founder of a fashion startup, now CTO of Product Hunt) gathered everything he could find on "Startup Metrics" and invested a few days to turn it into a slide presentation he shared for free - for the benefit of all founders.</p>
<hr>
<small>This is a companion discussion topic for the original entry at <a href="https://peerlearning.is/waves/">https://peerlearning.is/waves/</a></small>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/t/communities-mature-in-waves/2951/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://community.source.institute/t/communities-mature-in-waves/2951/1</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 13:14:47 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.source.institute-post-2951-1</guid>
        <source url="https://community.source.institute/t/communities-mature-in-waves/2951.rss">Communities mature in waves</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
