<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Hip-hop communities as a model for startup ecosystems</title>
    <link>https://community.source.institute/t/hip-hop-communities-as-a-model-for-startup-ecosystems/100</link>
    <description>What is education? We mostly associate it with systematic instruction. Showing and telling people how it’s done. But is that all there is to education? No. There’s also [a deeper part, that part of knowing why](http://community.source.institute/t/if-you-can-get-kids-interested-in-math/84), discovering what your reason is to appropriate these systematic handlings. 

That understanding leads to those ground-breaking trials to put existing things together in odd, new combinations, driven by that burning fire to achieve your ambition. Solid education helps you discover both. Specifically, when we’re talking about entrepreneurship education, you can sense how this would apply.

A good analogy to entrepreneurship is hip hop. What would hip hop culture have been if its protagonists were scratching using the same sequences of techniques, the same tracks, the same lyrics by the same kind of MC, and the same type of dance moves ? It would turn more into ballet or an opera.

Hip hop is different, right? It’s people trying out new sounds, and new technology, riffing on each other’s work, finding new ways to express the culture. Each has the motivation to make their mark on the culture, adding to the body of sound and motion. 

There are certain rules in this culture, but nobody owns the process on how it’s done. Everybody is learning from each other, picking things up through observations on leaders during performance events, on youtube, or just sitting with each other and mashing together structures. And thus you discover at a point that your listeners are subconsciously bobbing their heads to the same beat as you are, with this MPC you’ve used to create a new flow.

https://youtu.be/z73CcodfT_w

There’s no instructor, telling how this should work. It’s driven by a unity of interest amongst people, who seek each other out to take their own skills to the next level. That is the most granular, and most timely way to get the insights you need to build what you gotta build. 

This dynamic is the exponent of peer learning, and it is missing structure in our processes, brands, and curricula of entrepreneurship education. [We&#39;re waiting on our instructors to come up with the next thing.](http://community.source.institute/t/the-source-thesis/47)

Now, there do exist ways, but they require a lot of effort from the individual to make that work, eventually. 

So let&#39;s make it easier. Let&#39;s start with constructing[ the culture of peer learning for entrepreneurship education](http://community.source.institute/t/the-source-thesis/47). At Source we have a body of knowledge, skills and experience to share, but we’re not complete, not ever. We need to you to connect with your drive and motivation to teach us where we can do it differently or better. Come rif with us!</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 18:29:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Community</category>
    <atom:link href="https://community.source.institute/t/hip-hop-communities-as-a-model-for-startup-ecosystems/100.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Hip-hop communities as a model for startup ecosystems</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@salim Salim Virani]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/u/salim">@salim</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Oh, and if you’re into this, check out Scratch, a documentary on the emergence of Hip Hop DJs (before and after rappers got involved).</p>
<div class="lazyYT" data-youtube-id="YEKRAn-ZleM" data-youtube-title="Scratch (HipHop DJ Documentary)" data-width="480" data-height="270" data-parameters="feature=oembed&amp;wmode=opaque"></div>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/t/hip-hop-communities-as-a-model-for-startup-ecosystems/100/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://community.source.institute/t/hip-hop-communities-as-a-model-for-startup-ecosystems/100/2</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 18:29:08 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.source.institute-post-100-2</guid>
        <source url="https://community.source.institute/t/hip-hop-communities-as-a-model-for-startup-ecosystems/100.rss">Hip-hop communities as a model for startup ecosystems</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hip-hop communities as a model for startup ecosystems</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@bart Bart Doorneweert]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/u/bart">@bart</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>What is education? We mostly associate it with systematic instruction. Showing and telling people how it’s done. But is that all there is to education? No. There’s also <a href="//community.source.institute/t/if-you-can-get-kids-interested-in-math/84">a deeper part, that part of knowing why</a>, discovering what your reason is to appropriate these systematic handlings.</p>
<p>That understanding leads to those ground-breaking trials to put existing things together in odd, new combinations, driven by that burning fire to achieve your ambition. Solid education helps you discover both. Specifically, when we’re talking about entrepreneurship education, you can sense how this would apply.</p>
<p>A good analogy to entrepreneurship is hip hop. What would hip hop culture have been if its protagonists were scratching using the same sequences of techniques, the same tracks, the same lyrics by the same kind of MC, and the same type of dance moves ? It would turn more into ballet or an opera.</p>
<p>Hip hop is different, right? It’s people trying out new sounds, and new technology, riffing on each other’s work, finding new ways to express the culture. Each has the motivation to make their mark on the culture, adding to the body of sound and motion.</p>
<p>There are certain rules in this culture, but nobody owns the process on how it’s done. Everybody is learning from each other, picking things up through observations on leaders during performance events, on youtube, or just sitting with each other and mashing together structures. And thus you discover at a point that your listeners are subconsciously bobbing their heads to the same beat as you are, with this MPC you’ve used to create a new flow.</p>
<div class="lazyYT" data-youtube-id="z73CcodfT_w" data-youtube-title="Pete Rock On The MPC" data-width="480" data-height="270" data-parameters="feature=oembed&amp;wmode=opaque"></div>
<p>There’s no instructor, telling how this should work. It’s driven by a unity of interest amongst people, who seek each other out to take their own skills to the next level. That is the most granular, and most timely way to get the insights you need to build what you gotta build.</p>
<p>This dynamic is the exponent of peer learning, and it is missing structure in our processes, brands, and curricula of entrepreneurship education. <a href="//community.source.institute/t/the-source-thesis/47">We’re waiting on our instructors to come up with the next thing.</a></p>
<p>Now, there do exist ways, but they require a lot of effort from the individual to make that work, eventually.</p>
<p>So let’s make it easier. Let’s start with constructing<a href="//community.source.institute/t/the-source-thesis/47"> the culture of peer learning for entrepreneurship education</a>. At Source we have a body of knowledge, skills and experience to share, but we’re not complete, not ever. We need to you to connect with your drive and motivation to teach us where we can do it differently or better. Come rif with us!</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/t/hip-hop-communities-as-a-model-for-startup-ecosystems/100/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://community.source.institute/t/hip-hop-communities-as-a-model-for-startup-ecosystems/100/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2016 09:46:17 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.source.institute-post-100-1</guid>
        <source url="https://community.source.institute/t/hip-hop-communities-as-a-model-for-startup-ecosystems/100.rss">Hip-hop communities as a model for startup ecosystems</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
