<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Why You Only Need 3 Shirts</title>
    <link>https://community.source.institute/t/why-you-only-need-3-shirts/1858</link>
    <description>Louis-Antoine Muhire, is a Rwandan who made a new life in Canada as a Police Intelligence Officer. However, in spite of his success there, he decided to return to Rwanda to build a better remittance system, inspired by his own frustration sending money back home.

After three years of work, his company, [Mergims](https://www.mergims.com), has now raised 4 rounds of funding and is valued at 5 million US dollars. Along the way he learned a major lesson about where to spend money which totally changed his perspective on his business. Here&#39;s that story:

&gt;I had only about $10k dollars when I arrived in Rwanda. But when I came, I lived a lifestyle of someone who was from the West. Big house, big cars, everything was big.

&gt;When I left Canada it was winter so I had all the clothes, so in Rwanda I start buying things for a hot country. So I realized I have spent a lot of money on things that really have no value for my company. I have bought nice shoes, nice clothes for the beach and stuff like that. And in three months I was out of money. So quickly I realized, I started looking to other successful people like Zuckerburg, Steve Jobs

&gt;I see that Steve Jobs has one jeans and one black t-shirt because it was, I don&#39;t know, busy too much. It was a waste of money. And as the fact I ran out of money totally, totally have zero money in my account for one month and went through a very stressful moment, it gave me a sense of value for the money I&#39;m getting.

&gt;And from that I commit myself to really buy 3 shirts, that&#39;s my 3 shirt story. Like three white shirts and three black or blue, dark ones, and three pair of shoes and I know those are international standards, wherever you go you don&#39;t look badly dressed or extremely well dressed.

&gt;To me that question of waking up, trying to see how much you can pay for clothes was over. It saves me money because now every money I get I invest in my company. And that&#39;s what I was saying, because if someone has family, relatives that are depending heavily from his income, he has to obtain their support before, otherwise it will be very difficult.

&gt;Today, whenever I&#39;m spending money I have to think three or four times, do we really need this actually, do we really need to, because I remember the first 9 months was extremely painful for me. But, yeah. That was the relationship, I was lucky to have him come a little bit late but helping me. Because he could have said, &quot;you know what, I lost that 20k, you&#39;re part of the 90% I&#39;m have to lose, next!&quot;</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 11:10:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>The Sources</category>
    <atom:link href="https://community.source.institute/t/why-you-only-need-3-shirts/1858.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Why You Only Need 3 Shirts</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@ehalsey1 Eric Halsey]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/u/ehalsey1">@ehalsey1</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>Louis-Antoine Muhire, is a Rwandan who made a new life in Canada as a Police Intelligence Officer. However, in spite of his success there, he decided to return to Rwanda to build a better remittance system, inspired by his own frustration sending money back home.</p>
<p>After three years of work, his company, <a href="https://www.mergims.com">Mergims</a>, has now raised 4 rounds of funding and is valued at 5 million US dollars. Along the way he learned a major lesson about where to spend money which totally changed his perspective on his business. Here’s that story:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>I had only about $10k dollars when I arrived in Rwanda. But when I came, I lived a lifestyle of someone who was from the West. Big house, big cars, everything was big.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>When I left Canada it was winter so I had all the clothes, so in Rwanda I start buying things for a hot country. So I realized I have spent a lot of money on things that really have no value for my company. I have bought nice shoes, nice clothes for the beach and stuff like that. And in three months I was out of money. So quickly I realized, I started looking to other successful people like Zuckerburg, Steve Jobs</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>I see that Steve Jobs has one jeans and one black t-shirt because it was, I don’t know, busy too much. It was a waste of money. And as the fact I ran out of money totally, totally have zero money in my account for one month and went through a very stressful moment, it gave me a sense of value for the money I’m getting.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>And from that I commit myself to really buy 3 shirts, that’s my 3 shirt story. Like three white shirts and three black or blue, dark ones, and three pair of shoes and I know those are international standards, wherever you go you don’t look badly dressed or extremely well dressed.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>To me that question of waking up, trying to see how much you can pay for clothes was over. It saves me money because now every money I get I invest in my company. And that’s what I was saying, because if someone has family, relatives that are depending heavily from his income, he has to obtain their support before, otherwise it will be very difficult.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Today, whenever I’m spending money I have to think three or four times, do we really need this actually, do we really need to, because I remember the first 9 months was extremely painful for me. But, yeah. That was the relationship, I was lucky to have him come a little bit late but helping me. Because he could have said, “you know what, I lost that 20k, you’re part of the 90% I’m have to lose, next!”</p>
</blockquote>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/t/why-you-only-need-3-shirts/1858/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://community.source.institute/t/why-you-only-need-3-shirts/1858/1</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 11:10:07 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.source.institute-post-1858-1</guid>
        <source url="https://community.source.institute/t/why-you-only-need-3-shirts/1858.rss">Why You Only Need 3 Shirts</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
