<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:discourse="http://www.discourse.org/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Concepts - Source Institute</title>
    <link>https://community.source.institute/c/archive/concepts</link>
    <description>Topics in the &#39;Concepts&#39; category We lead with value.  We proactively do things we believe the world needs, and work with collaborators towards common goals.  </description>
    
      <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2016 09:53:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      <atom:link href="https://community.source.institute/c/archive/concepts.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
          <title>Deep Dive Sofia</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@salim Salim Virani]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Concepts</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/u/salim">@salim</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p>I’d like to get a regular <a href="http://startupdeepdive.com">Startup Deep Dive</a> going in Sofia, maybe every month or two.  I feel like the new blood in the Sofia community needs a way in, and a day-long launch event will upskill them and empower them.</p>
<p>I’d be happy to run it if we can schedule it while I’m in town, I just need support to promote it for now.</p>
<p>Benefits for SIS and AIESEC are that I can teach the teams how to facilitate Deep Dive themselves, and build capacity within those organisations.  It is designed as a <a href="//community.source.institute/t/self-propagating-workshops/204">self-propagating workshop</a> so it’s relatively easy for someone motivated to take the workshop, work on their skills for a few weeks, and then be able to deliver it themself.</p>
<p>I feel this is a solid need in the Sofia startup community - that people who think starting a tech business could be right for them need a way in to try without making a big personal commitment. This is long-term pipeline building for the Preaccelerator, Founders Institute, Eleven and LauncHub.  Personally, I feel this is a place where I can make a strong, unique contribution to Sofia.  (I’ve already invested months in the workshop design.)</p>
<p>A big opportunity I see for Bulgaria is to get this going so we can make this inclusive to a few Roma people I know, and next quarter help them run Deep Dive in their neighbourhood. Then, they can start running it in chitalishtes and it can spread to help create opportunities. But to do that I need Bulgarian-speaking facilitators to be able to run it so they can join.</p>
<h2>What’s needed?</h2>
<p>I need partners to help get the word out, host the event, and rally people who would like to learn to deliver a hands-on startup skills workshop like this.</p>
<hr>
<p>Would love to move on this quickly as my travel dates for November/December are filling up.  I can deliver this in Sofia on November 5th, or the week of December 17th after that.  I’d prefer to even get a small start on the 5th, but that’s 2-weeks away.</p>
<p><a class="mention" href="/u/nikyanev">@nikyanev</a> would love your support.  <a class="mention" href="/u/boyana">@boyana</a> can you please share this with the relevant people at AIESEC Bulgaria/Sofia, and re-introduce me over email if necessary?</p>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 2</p>
            <p>Participants: 2</p>
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/t/deep-dive-sofia/1018">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://community.source.institute/t/deep-dive-sofia/1018</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2016 09:53:49 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">community.source.institute-topic-1018</guid>
          <source url="https://community.source.institute/t/deep-dive-sofia/1018.rss">Deep Dive Sofia</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Source Summit Aviation</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@rvangeldrop Robbert van Geldrop]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Concepts</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/u/rvangeldrop">@rvangeldrop</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p>Continuing the discussion from <a href="//community.source.institute/t/source-summit-aviation/410/26">Source Summit: Aviation</a>:</p>
<p><strong>The opportunity</strong></p>
<p>A Source Summit in which we bring together different parts of the (Dutch) aviation sector together, lead by those who already are working with or bought into Lean Startup in the Netherlands. This was sparked on Leancamp, where Marieke Schoenmaker participated.</p>
<p><strong>Goal</strong></p>
<p>To test p2p structures in a risk-averse and unbundled industry. Also, it creates a safe environment for executives to experience the formats and learn from companies who they typically treat as suppliers and customers.</p>
<p>Transavia is already invested into Lean Startup.</p>
<p>NLR has put their toe in the water. They need to reinvent themselves as 25% of their income is from government grants, which will be capped to 0 in a few years.</p>
<p>Lean Startup Leadership Platform is actively advertising itself as the equivalent of the Dutch Lean Startup Circle for the enterprise and is looking for formats to run with their community.</p>
<p>I reminded myself of a bunch of hackers in Delft on the University campus who go by RoboValley. We should try to bring them in as well. I have a connection there who I invited for the last Leancamp. He liked the concept but couldn’t make that one due to holidays. I can make him an ambassador for that community.</p>
<p>Source Institute will design the Summit</p>
<p><strong>Strategic Relevance</strong></p>
<p>Source can demonstrate the power of p2p to an entire sector. There are many more of these setups, such as Holland ConTech and Holland FinTech. It’s also a way to spot potential Source Fellows, because people who’ll lead will be qualifying for the Belt System.</p>
<p><strong>Resources</strong></p>
<p>Budget: 10k - 20k</p>
<p>Timeline:<br>
Preparation - Aug-Sep<br>
Summit Date - beginning of Oct</p>
<p><strong>People:</strong><br>
Marieke Schoenmaker (lead, community outreach, committing sponsors and venue)<br>
Vincent Thamm - Transavia (lead, perhaps venue)<br>
<a class="mention" href="/u/bart">@bart</a> or <a class="mention" href="/u/salim">@salim</a> for design<br>
<span class="mention">@robbert</span> (for community outreach)</p>
<p>For delivery: trained facilitators</p>
<p><strong>Outcomes:</strong></p>
<p>Participants leave with confidence that they can use p2p formats as a way of working in their business</p>
<p>Showcase Source Summit to other community platforms, who can be a channel for this</p>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 10</p>
            <p>Participants: 4</p>
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/t/source-summit-aviation/496">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://community.source.institute/t/source-summit-aviation/496</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 19:39:14 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">community.source.institute-topic-496</guid>
          <source url="https://community.source.institute/t/source-summit-aviation/496.rss">Source Summit Aviation</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Mentor-funded startups</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@salim Salim Virani]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Concepts</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/u/salim">@salim</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p>From <a href="//community.source.institute/t/peer-education-hub-for-south-east-europe/46/11">Peer-Education Hub</a>:</p>
<aside class="quote" data-post="9" data-topic="46">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="//community.source.institute/user_avatar/community.source.institute/rvangeldrop/40/160_1.png" class="avatar"><a href="//community.source.institute/t/peer-education-hub-for-south-east-europe/46/9">Peer-Education Hub for South-East Europe</a>
</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Leon suggested for mentors to fund it and make them fund it in small increments, month-over-month or quarter-over-quarter. I like that idea.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<aside class="quote" data-post="10" data-topic="46">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt width="20" height="20" src="//community.source.institute/user_avatar/community.source.institute/lino/40/24_1.png" class="avatar"><a href="//community.source.institute/t/peer-education-hub-for-south-east-europe/46/10">Peer-Education Hub for South-East Europe</a>
</div>
<blockquote>
<p><a class="mention" href="/u/salim">@salim</a>’s also been suggesting that this would be a more impactful way to invest in Africa than traditional VC and there are already a few conversations around that under the Source Ventures topic which I don’t think we’ve covered on discourse much so far, but I’m very much in support of us working in that direction.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>The central theme here is to focus on smart money, with angels who bring skills and real time commitment at an executional level.</p>
<p>For a lot of African tech companies, the forex means smaller amounts of capital go way farther, but the real gaps aren’t around funding, but know-how.  So the Source Ventures discussion has followed roughly the same model, but the capital invement by the angels isn’t direct to the startup, and is more to create a bar for commitment on the angel <a href="http://side.It">side.It</a> sounds like Leon’s idea is more to tranch investments and have the mentors be the arbiter of the tranching targets?</p>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 7</p>
            <p>Participants: 3</p>
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/t/mentor-funded-startups/418">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://community.source.institute/t/mentor-funded-startups/418</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2016 09:08:58 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">community.source.institute-topic-418</guid>
          <source url="https://community.source.institute/t/mentor-funded-startups/418.rss">Mentor-funded startups</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>FarmHack.nl: filling in the gap in technology development for agriculture</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@bart Bart Doorneweert]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Concepts</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/u/bart">@bart</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p><span class="hashtag">#The</span> opportunity<br>
There are so many agriculture technology projects out there. Momentum is building to propel the farmer forward into the 21st century of technology use. Yet, while ambitions are big, and the budgets are accordingly high, farmers are not yet buying into the digital age of farming.</p>
<p>One of the recurring problems is that agriculture technology tends to get designed for the possibilities that technology can offer, but it generally doesn’t meet farmers at the level of use and understanding where they currently are. This disconnect with the learning curve that the farmer still has to traverse, is causing a barrier for adoption of technology solutions.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.farmhack.nl">Farmhack.nl</a> was founded by Anne Bruinsma, to take on this specific problem. <a href="http://Farmhack.nl">Farmhack.nl</a> aims to create a much needed human-centered force in technology design for farmers, by organizing small and dedicated on-farm hackathons, addressing topics that the hosting farmer is concerned with specifically. <a href="http://FarmHack.nl">FarmHack.nl</a> challenges design and technology related talent to come up with practical solutions for acute on-farm problems.</p>
<p><span class="hashtag">#Common</span> goal – how will it make a difference?<br>
Through these challenges, <a href="http://Farmhack.nl">Farmhack.nl</a> aims to reveal the relevant design patterns for technology solution design. This is pulling in interest from development firms, and from organizations that support technology development in agriculture, like the <a href="http://www.godan.info">Global Open Data for Agriculture and Nutrition (GODAN)</a></p>
<p><a href="http://Farmhack.nl">Farmhack.nl</a> is starting off in Holland with the intent of developing a self-propagating hackathon framework, that will spread on-farm hackathons throughout the world.</p>
<p><span class="hashtag">#Organisation</span> goals<br>
Farmhack wants to increase the likelihood that the hackathon challenges will turn into viable solutions, that are able to spread. It aims to support projects to develop further, through pulling in support from development houses, other agribusiness stakeholders as sponsors, and entrepreneurship education for the teams that have worked on the hack initially.</p>
<p>Source Institute is dedicated to developing, timely, relevant, and accessible education to even the most challenging environments. Source’s designs for self-propagating education can be integrated into the FarmHack concept.</p>
<p><span class="hashtag">#Strategic</span> relevance<br>
Data, and technology in agriculture are currently mostly underutilized. <a href="http://Farmhack.nl">Farmhack.nl</a>’s mission is to lay the groundwork for designing technology for agriculture, making the case for en open, ecosystem-based innovation approach (much like <a href="https://www.codeforamerica.org">Code for America</a> does for the US government). Stakeholders involved in developing technology solutions for farmers can learn first hand how technology can be designed to fit the needs and requirements of farmers.</p>
<p>At Source Institute, we see this as a very relevant early-stage development feeding ground for (notably hardware) technology advancement and entrepreneurship in the agriculture sector. Source can help establish FarmHack’s model, and help it spread, for instance by introducing it to our work on hardware startup acceleration, and network on the African continent.</p>
<p><span class="hashtag">#Resources</span><br>
<a href="http://FarmHack.nl">FarmHack.nl</a> is a non-profit initiative, running at-cost in its first iteration.</p>
<p><strong>Budget</strong><br>
FarmHack has received a subsidy, and sponsorships to cover the costs for organizing a series of 4 hackathons. As such, Source is also an in-kind sponsor to this initiative</p>
<p><strong>Timeline</strong><br>
The Hackathons will be organized in June 2016. And the winners of each hackathon will be supported until October, where they will pitch their progress during the Agri meets Design at the Dutch Design Week in Eindhoven. In July, Source will provide a bootcamp, and some remote check-ins after to mentor on progress.</p>
<p><strong>People needed</strong><br>
Bart is going to host the bootcamp. A position for a volunteer from Source fellows is still open.<br>
Both the volunteer and Bart will provide the remote follow-up, through check-in calls, and the Source community forum.</p>
<p><strong>Outcomes</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>4 hacks, which have developed a strong business viability</li>
<li>A design for self-propagating education material, that can be distributed with the <a href="http://FarmHack.nl">FarmHack.nl</a> hackathon package</li>
<li>New linkages for FarmHack to Source’s global entrepreneurship communities</li>
</ul>
<p><span class="hashtag">#Description</span><br>
Farmhack have found 4 challenging farmers, which will result in 4 decentralised hackathons, with 3 dedicated teams working on each one. A mobile unit will contructed to bring the required techinfrastructure to the farm locations.</p>
<p>Winning 4 teams will be offered a 1-day bootcamp and some mentoring after. The contestant will have a pitching final during Agri Meets Design at the Dutch Design Week in Eindhoven.</p>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 11</p>
            <p>Participants: 4</p>
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/t/farmhack-nl-filling-in-the-gap-in-technology-development-for-agriculture/228">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://community.source.institute/t/farmhack-nl-filling-in-the-gap-in-technology-development-for-agriculture/228</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2016 09:22:56 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">community.source.institute-topic-228</guid>
          <source url="https://community.source.institute/t/farmhack-nl-filling-in-the-gap-in-technology-development-for-agriculture/228.rss">FarmHack.nl: filling in the gap in technology development for agriculture</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Octopizzo Hackathon</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@salim Salim Virani]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Concepts</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/u/salim">@salim</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p><span class="hashtag">#The</span> Opportunity<br>
A hackathon focusing on enabling non-technical producers, such as women in Kibera, to sell their goods online.  We can create a suite of apps with viable business models, enabling local producers and manufacturs. With the input and apps developed by the iHub community, delivered economically to those who need them using Firefox OS, connected directly to the best producers by the Octopizzo Foundation, and promoted by Octopizzo, the initial network effects can be put in place.</p>
<p><span class="hashtag">#Common</span> Goal - How will it make a difference?<br>
A major difficulty in establish manufacturing in Africa is onward distribution.  Established supply chains export raw material, not manufactured goods, leaving small-scale producers unable to sell what they produce.   Online channels are beginning to change that, but they’re disconnected from suppliers simply because online marketplaces require their suppliers to be online as well.</p>
<p><span class="hashtag">#Organisational</span> Goals:<br>
<strong>Octopizzo Foundation</strong> creates economic opportunities in Kibera, and is looking to create impact in other slums in Africa.<br>
<strong>Mozilla</strong> has developed Firefox OS to bring connectivity to poorer communities.<br>
<strong>Source Institute</strong> develops educational techniques appropriate for unique and isolated contexts, and we focus on humanitech.<br>
<strong>iHub</strong> is the centre of the Kenyan tech community, and is positioning itself to grow its consulting businesses, targeting corporates.</p>
<h1>Strategic Relevance</h1>
<p>Successful marketing by mobile networks is a key factor in the successful adoption of Firefox OS.  Octopizzo is a saught-after brand among the networks in Kenya.  These two dynamics have been isolated from each other until now, but the work of the Octopizzo Foundation reveals a common goal - that Firefox OS brings the potential for an app ecosystem that economically benefits low-income markets.</p>
<h1>Resources</h1>
<p><strong>Budget:</strong>  hackathons can be run $1,000 - 2,000 USD, depending on in-kind sponsorship.</p>
<p><strong>Timeline:</strong>  A single hackathon can be organised with 3 months lead time.</p>
<p><strong>People needed:</strong><br>
Event manager<br>
Community leaders (for promotion)<br>
Mozilla Dev rep (for training and support)<br>
App developers and UX Designers (as participants)<br>
Octopizzo<br>
Goods-producers from Kibera<br>
Founders of marketplaces and e-commerce sites that either sell craft-goods anywhere, or sell manufactured goods in Kenya</p>
<p><strong>Resources needed:</strong><br>
iHub space<br>
Buses or transport from iHub to Kibera<br>
Prizes<br>
Phones (for development and testing)</p>
<h1>Outcomes:</h1>
<ul>
<li>New supply lines for e-commerce sites</li>
<li>New product lines for e-commerce sites</li>
<li>Possibly new viable business models for startups</li>
<li>Increased traction for Firefox OS</li>
<li>Increased sales volume and sale prices for Kibera producers</li>
</ul>
<h1>Description</h1>
<p>This is a simple hackathon where the focus is on improving the lives of Kibera producers, such as the women who produce clothing and traditional goods in the Octopizzo Foundation.</p>
<p>We’ll invite them to bring their goods to the hackathon, where they will meet the developers and e-commerce companies. For the duration, they’ll be available to test the usability of the apps developed. (Most have not used a smartphone.)</p>
<p>A simple concept app is to allow them to simply take pictures of their goods and post them for sale. Given that e-commerce companies, producers and designer will be contributing, a much wider variety of apps is expected.</p>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 9</p>
            <p>Participants: 3</p>
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/t/octopizzo-hackathon/86">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://community.source.institute/t/octopizzo-hackathon/86</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2016 13:26:21 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">community.source.institute-topic-86</guid>
          <source url="https://community.source.institute/t/octopizzo-hackathon/86.rss">Octopizzo Hackathon</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Village Accelerator</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@salim Salim Virani]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Concepts</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/u/salim">@salim</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p><span class="hashtag">#The</span> Opportunity<br>
The world’s growth markets often face socio-economic divides.  As internet access and mobile phones arrive there, technical skills provide money-making opportunities, whether that’s as outsource work or developing their own software to address local needs.</p>
<p>Village Accelerator is programme designed to develop these technology business skills, and to be syndicated to different communities around the world.</p>
<p><span class="hashtag">#Common</span> Goal - How will it make a difference?</p>
<p>Village Accelerator creates economic wealth.  It creates marketable skills that can be applied without leaving home, and enables people to address needs of growth markets.</p>
<p><span class="hashtag">#Organisational</span> Goals:<br>
<strong>Source Institute</strong> does this because the world needs it.  It’s an example of a self-propagating programme - one designed so the students can quickly become the teacher.  Our aim is to maximise reach and have an early insight into untapped investment opportunities around the world.</p>
<h1>Strategic Relevance</h1>
<p>Village Accelerator is for communities that most innovation and support programmes don’t consider worth targeting.  These communities are often considered worthy of social support programmes, but overlooked for economic opportunity.  However, they are often growth markets and the opportunities within them are findable by the many intelligent people in these communities.  Village Accelerator enables them on their own terms.</p>
<h1>Resources</h1>
<p><strong>Budget:</strong>  We are not currently seeking funding, however, this project could benefit from a part-time project manager.</p>
<p><strong>Timeline:</strong>  Ongoing</p>
<p><strong>People needed:</strong><br>
Software developers<br>
Technology entrepreneurs<br>
Translators</p>
<p><strong>Resources needed:</strong><br>
Computers</p>
<h1>Outcomes:</h1>
<ul>
<li>People employable with high-paying skills</li>
<li>Internet and mobile tech startups</li>
</ul>
<h1>Description</h1>
<p>Village Accelerator runs as two-week training programmes, taught by volunteers.</p>
<p>We target young adults by offering to teach them how to make their own video game.  We teach web site building, followed by simple web app development using the Facebook API, and build a simple game like Flappy Birds.   We then explore various web-based business models they can copy and customise to address local needs.</p>
<p>Each topic in the programme is self-propagating, meaning the students who complete the course can teach it next time.</p>
<p>The course material is syndicated following open source methodologies.  It is offered for free to others, who apply it, improve it, and share back their improvements.</p>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 1</p>
            <p>Participants: 1</p>
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/t/village-accelerator/80">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://community.source.institute/t/village-accelerator/80</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 19:55:52 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">community.source.institute-topic-80</guid>
          <source url="https://community.source.institute/t/village-accelerator/80.rss">Village Accelerator</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Peer-Education Hub for South-East Europe</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@salim Salim Virani]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Concepts</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/u/salim">@salim</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p><span class="hashtag">#The</span> Opportunity<br>
A Peer-To-Peer (P2P) education hub creates a bigger, higher-quality startup pipeline and supports non-high-growth startups based on <a href="//community.source.institute/t/true-ecosystems/48">local tech strengths</a>. It uses both tried-and-tested, and some of the most innovative education formats to create and enable technology companies from idea to growth stages.</p>
<p>We are considering hosting this in the UK, Netherlands or in SE Europe.  This overview focuses on SE Europe.</p>
<p><span class="hashtag">#Common</span> Goal - How will it make a difference?</p>
<p>This will give support on a meritocratic basis, to as many tech startups that warrant support, not just the ones who are selected for specific programmes.  It will do this by leading with local strengths, like B2B products and tech service firms, creating the host city (Sofia, Belgrade or Bucharest?) as the known capital in these areas.</p>
<p><span class="hashtag">#Organisational</span> Goals:<br>
<strong>Start It Smart</strong> wants to cement its position as a foundational startup support organisation, and establish ongoing programmes and a sustainable business model.</p>
<p><strong>LAUNCHub</strong> and <strong>Eleven</strong> are moving into later-stage investment and support, and need an early-stage pipeline.</p>
<p><strong>Accelerators</strong> are opening in Romania and Serbia.  This will provide a leg-up towards higher-tier and more responsive, relevant support.  It’ll also give the accelerators access to an instant mentoring network that’s run with state-of-the-art techniques.</p>
<p><strong>Montenegro and Macedonian</strong> startup communities will have an quivalent level of startup support and education as accelerators. Their geographically diverse (and isolated) startups will be actively included through the online aspects of the community.</p>
<p><strong>EIF</strong> is investing to see sustainable startup support as their legacy.</p>
<p><strong>MoveBG</strong> is interested in gathering data and insight on what are some innovative SMEs and what are their problems in order to drive strategic support in the industry. Similar to how the Erasmus consortium would benefit from using P2P summits for rapidly evolving it’s curriculum.</p>
<p><strong>Source Institute</strong> wants to progress startup support to be broader and farther reaching than through the standard accelerator model.  We want to progress with lessons learned from the first phase of the accelerator industry.</p>
<p><a href="//community.source.institute/t/the-source-thesis/47">Peer -to-peer (P2P) education</a> is the focus of Source Institute.  We’re invested in developing P2P from a small set of tested methods to a broad toollkit creating impact worldwide.</p>
<p>To do this, we invest in R&amp;D and demonstrate value with proofs-of-concept.  We’d like to support, or lead, an physical space that facilitates this.  This space will become the global leader in P2P.  In the same way that Lean Startup took hold in San Francisco and London first, we expect <a href="//community.source.institute/t/building-communities-of-master-entrepreneurs/53">similar benefits to accrue to the host city of the P2P Hub</a>.</p>
<h1>Strategic Relevance</h1>
<p>As Sofia’s startup community matures and specialises, early-stage support needs to scale and diversify to keep up.  Early-stage pipeline needs to widen.  Accelerators have provided investment, education and community support so far. By tackling early-stage support and education (at a scale not limited by selecting startups for investment), the P2P Hub offers the flexibility, responsiveness and scalability that’s required for the regions’s startup community to grow to the next level.   It allows us to education and support more early-stage tech businesses, regardless of if they’re seeking investment at the moment.  This develops a larger and more diverse pipeline.</p>
<h1>Resources</h1>
<p><strong>Budget:</strong>  50,000 - 450,000 EUR over 3 years, depending on partners’ in-kind contributions</p>
<p><strong>Timeline:</strong>  3 years</p>
<p><strong>People needed:</strong><br>
Managing Director<br>
3 X Programme Designer (p/t)<br>
UX Lab Director (p/t)<br>
Product Innovation Lab Director (p/t)<br>
Experiment Lab Director (p/t)<br>
Events Manager<br>
Marketing Manager<br>
Office Manager<br>
Writer<br>
Video Editor (p/t)<br>
Visual Designer (pt)</p>
<p><strong>Resources needed:</strong><br>
Multi-classroom space.<br>
Larger event space.<br>
Computer Lab<br>
UX Lab</p>
<p><div class="lightbox-wrapper"><a class="lightbox" href="//community.source.institute/uploads/default/original/1X/3afc778b93274a74890e806a8cdf8e47da42501e.png" data-download-href="//community.source.institute/uploads/default/3afc778b93274a74890e806a8cdf8e47da42501e" title="layout.png"><img src="//community.source.institute/uploads/default/optimized/1X/3afc778b93274a74890e806a8cdf8e47da42501e_2_690x436.png" width="690" height="436" srcset="//community.source.institute/uploads/default/optimized/1X/3afc778b93274a74890e806a8cdf8e47da42501e_2_690x436.png, //community.source.institute/uploads/default/original/1X/3afc778b93274a74890e806a8cdf8e47da42501e.png 1.5x, //community.source.institute/uploads/default/original/1X/3afc778b93274a74890e806a8cdf8e47da42501e.png 2x" data-small-upload="//community.source.institute/uploads/default/optimized/1X/3afc778b93274a74890e806a8cdf8e47da42501e_2_10x10.png"><div class="meta">
<svg class="fa d-icon d-icon-far-image svg-icon" aria-hidden="true"><use xlink:href="#far-image"></use></svg><span class="filename">layout.png</span><span class="informations">935×591 31.5 KB</span><svg class="fa d-icon d-icon-discourse-expand svg-icon" aria-hidden="true"><use xlink:href="#discourse-expand"></use></svg>
</div></a></div></p>
<h1>Outcomes:</h1>
<ul>
<li>+10 Super-Seed or Post-Seed investments per year</li>
<li>+200 knowledge worker positions created per year</li>
<li>10 startup seed  investments per year</li>
<li>+1 agency into international expansion per year</li>
<li>3 e-books per year</li>
<li>100 online lessons per year</li>
</ul>
<h1>Description</h1>
<p>The P2P Hub will provide many functions of accelerators, but at a larger scale:</p>
<ul>
<li>Startup education</li>
<li>Mentoring</li>
<li>Creating focal points for the international startup community in Sofia</li>
<li>Creating gathering points for the local technology community in Sofia</li>
<li>Providing a forum to express and address issues in the startup and technology industry</li>
</ul>
<p>It will do so through ongoing peer-to-peer events, both large and small scale:</p>
<ol>
<li>Unconferences address the most relevant, practical challenges faced by various local disciplines and industries. Each enables these communities to teach each other and bubble up unspotted leaders in the topics that truly matter.  These summits will  run quarterly, attracting the most active and viable startups in the region.</li>
<li>Online Education built from interviews of successful local founders and role models. Entreprenurs get the most relevant advice as they need it, delivered via a platform the reinforces Sofia’s strengths.</li>
<li>Content, such as e-books, written from local experiences and role models.</li>
<li>Experiential Workshops convey with <em>why</em> through simulations, spreading attitude shift from Sofia and Europe’s leading personalities, then layer on the <em>how</em>, the most relevant practical skills.  These workshops will be designed by Source and delivered by Source and Start IT Smart.</li>
<li>Peer-support programmes, like mentoring, peer-advisory, office hours, meetups.</li>
</ol>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 11</p>
            <p>Participants: 6</p>
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/t/peer-education-hub-for-south-east-europe/46">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://community.source.institute/t/peer-education-hub-for-south-east-europe/46</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2016 08:19:31 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">community.source.institute-topic-46</guid>
          <source url="https://community.source.institute/t/peer-education-hub-for-south-east-europe/46.rss">Peer-Education Hub for South-East Europe</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Why we share our concepts</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@salim Salim Virani]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Concepts</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/u/salim">@salim</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p>We lead with value.  We proactively do things we believe the world needs, and work with collaborators towards common goals.</p>
<p>This section outlines a number of projects we’d like to start - ideally with partners and collaborators.</p>
<p>If you’d like to work with Source, this is the place to get involved.</p>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 1</p>
            <p>Participants: 1</p>
            <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/t/why-we-share-our-concepts/42">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://community.source.institute/t/why-we-share-our-concepts/42</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2016 10:32:32 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>Yes</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">community.source.institute-topic-42</guid>
          <source url="https://community.source.institute/t/why-we-share-our-concepts/42.rss">Why we share our concepts</source>
        </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
