<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Robbert&#39;s Rules Of Order</title>
    <link>https://community.source.institute/t/robberts-rules-of-order/2470</link>
    <description>I&#39;m only loosely familiar with Robert&#39;s Rules.   Like when someone interjects to make a &quot;point of order.&quot;   Or the idea that someone can make a motion, and it will only continue if there is a &#39;seconder&#39; in the room. 

I looked them up for the first time last week, after someone suggested them to improve the chaotic meetings of forming industry organization.  They&#39;re named after a US Army officer who wrote up the practices of US Congress for broader community use in 1876. 

Here&#39;s [a cheatsheet for the Robert&#39;s Rules](https://robertsrules.org/) based on the 1915 version. I noticed a few that I already use when facilitating, but without the Robert&#39;s Rules shorthand or jargon:
&gt; The member moving the &quot;immediately pending question&quot; is entitled to preference to the floor! 
&gt; No member can speak twice to the same issue until everyone else wishing to speak has spoken to it once!

Even more formal Robert&#39;s Rules procedures, like starting with a review of the last meeting, then moving onto reports followed by clarification questions before moving onto proposals.  I realised these are echoed in our own formats, like the hands-on [Fixer format](http://community.source.institute/t/format-fixer-sessions/1810) where someone with a challenge delegates it to an interdisciplinary group to solve.

There are versions of Robert&#39;s Rules for [different specializations](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robert%27s_Rules_of_Order#Application_to_specific_organizations), like law-making or trade unions, and the rules can get [somewhat complex](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robert%27s_Rules_of_Order#The_Basics) depending on the size and purpose of the assembly, and what degree of consent or actionability are desired.

I&#39;m not a fan of boring meetings, especially the kind where people can drone on and on on a pedestal, so tend to rely on simpler rules like [Roman Voting](https://www.conferencesthatwork.com/index.php/event-design/2012/06/testing-consensus-using-roman-voting/), but those tend to work better in smaller groups.  

I think Robert&#39;s Rules can be unpacked into various facilitation and democratic principles, and used in more modern, even casual, forms.  I offered to facilitate the next meetings for this industry association.  I&#39;m interested to see if I can facilitate meetings with the principles and order of Robert&#39;s Rules without requiring the people in the meeting to have studied them in advance.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 16:14:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Community</category>
    <atom:link href="https://community.source.institute/t/robberts-rules-of-order/2470.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Robbert&#39;s Rules Of Order</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@salim Salim Virani]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
          <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/u/salim">@salim</a> wrote:</p>
          <blockquote>
              <p>I’m only loosely familiar with Robert’s Rules.   Like when someone interjects to make a “point of order.”   Or the idea that someone can make a motion, and it will only continue if there is a ‘seconder’ in the room.</p>
<p>I looked them up for the first time last week, after someone suggested them to improve the chaotic meetings of forming industry organization.  They’re named after a US Army officer who wrote up the practices of US Congress for broader community use in 1876.</p>
<p>Here’s <a href="https://robertsrules.org/">a cheatsheet for the Robert’s Rules</a> based on the 1915 version. I noticed a few that I already use when facilitating, but without the Robert’s Rules shorthand or jargon:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The member moving the “immediately pending question” is entitled to preference to the floor!<br>
No member can speak twice to the same issue until everyone else wishing to speak has spoken to it once!</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Even more formal Robert’s Rules procedures, like starting with a review of the last meeting, then moving onto reports followed by clarification questions before moving onto proposals.  I realised these are echoed in our own formats, like the hands-on <a href="//community.source.institute/t/format-fixer-sessions/1810">Fixer format</a> where someone with a challenge delegates it to an interdisciplinary group to solve.</p>
<p>There are versions of Robert’s Rules for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robert%27s_Rules_of_Order#Application_to_specific_organizations">different specializations</a>, like law-making or trade unions, and the rules can get <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robert%27s_Rules_of_Order#The_Basics">somewhat complex</a> depending on the size and purpose of the assembly, and what degree of consent or actionability are desired.</p>
<p>I’m not a fan of boring meetings, especially the kind where people can drone on and on on a pedestal, so tend to rely on simpler rules like <a href="https://www.conferencesthatwork.com/index.php/event-design/2012/06/testing-consensus-using-roman-voting/">Roman Voting</a>, but those tend to work better in smaller groups.</p>
<p>I think Robert’s Rules can be unpacked into various facilitation and democratic principles, and used in more modern, even casual, forms.  I offered to facilitate the next meetings for this industry association.  I’m interested to see if I can facilitate meetings with the principles and order of Robert’s Rules without requiring the people in the meeting to have studied them in advance.</p>
          </blockquote>
          <p><a href="https://community.source.institute/t/robberts-rules-of-order/2470/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://community.source.institute/t/robberts-rules-of-order/2470/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2018 08:55:13 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">community.source.institute-post-2470-1</guid>
        <source url="https://community.source.institute/t/robberts-rules-of-order/2470.rss">Robbert&#39;s Rules Of Order</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
